OK so we have our application it's in the cloud.
It's running.
And your manager calls you at 2:00 a.m. and say it's not running anymore.
What happened?
Well we've deployed her application but we forgot to turn on monitoring.
Monitoring is so important and it will make sure that your applications are running the right way.
Such as you can see what's happening with the logs with the metrics with tracing and audits who made what's
in your AWS infrastructure.
This section is so important because as a developer.
I never deployed an application in AWS without enabling some kind of monitoring.
I know you're excited to learn about monitoring!
Let's go.