Now let's talk about how we can use something
called the CloudWatch Agents to take logs
from EC2 instances, as well as metrics
and have them onto CloudWatch.
So by default, no logs are going
from your EC2 instance from CloudWatch.
For this, you need to create and start an agent
which is a small program on your EC2 instances
that will push the log files that you want.
So the idea, is that your easy EC2 instances
will have the CloudWatch Log Agents,
for example running sending the logs into
CloudWatch Logs for it to work.
Your EC2 instance must have an IAM role
that allows it to send the log
to CloudWatch Logs, that make sense?
And good to notice that this CloudWatch
log agents can also be setup
on-premises servers.
So it's possible for you to have your services,
virtual servers like VM-ware on premises
and you install the exact same agent,
which is a small Linux Program
and your logs will end up in CloudWatch Logs as well.
Now, there are two different agents
you can find in CloudWatch.
You have the CloudWatch Logs Agent,
which is the older one
and the CloudWatch Unified Agent,
which is the newer one.
So they're both for virtual servers
EC2 instances on premises servers, et cetera.
The CloudWatch Logs Agents is the old version
and can only send logs to CloudWatch Logs.
Whereas the Unified Agents,
will collect additional system level metrics
which has RAM, processes.
I'll show you this in the very next slide,
and also send the logs into CloudWatch Logs.
Now it's unified.
It's better because it can do both metrics and logs.
Hence, the name Unified Agent.
But also you can configure that agents very easily
using the SSM Parameter Store,
which is a feature that the previous agent did not have.
So you can do centralized configuration,
for all your Unified Agents.
So the CloudWatch Unified Agent can send,
logs to CloudWatch Logs.
But let's have a look at the metrics.
So if you install it,
on your Institute instances or your Linux servers
you can collect metrics, and what are they?
Well, we can collect the CPU metrics
but at a way more granular levels,
for example: active, guest, idle, system, user, steal.
You don't need to know them at all.
I'm just giving you the granularity of all these metrics.
Disc metrics of free use total.
Disc IO in terms of number of writes, reads, bytes, iops.
RAM so free, inactive, used, total, cached.
Netstats with number of TCP and UDP connections,
net packets, bytes to get some information
around the processes.
So in total number of process,
I mean your dead, bloqued, idle,
running, sleep.
And Swap Space, which is a memory spilling on disc.
So how much is free use and use percentage?
So why don't you remember is just take a
a mental screenshot of these things.
The bottom line is the CloudWatch Unified Agent allows it.
You get a lot more metrics at a lot more granular details
than the normal monitoring for EC2 instances.
As a reminder out of the box for EC2,
you get some information on disk, CPU,
and network not memory
not swap, but all of this at a high level, okay?
If you want more granularity
think CloudWatch Unified Agents, okay?
So that's it for me.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.