Được rồi, bắt đầu thôi
với cuộc thảo luận kiến trúc giải pháp đầu tiên của chúng ta.
Tôi rất hào hứng
vì chúng ta sẽ xem rất nhiều chủ đề khác nhau cùng lúc,
và chúng ta sẽ thật sự hiểu cách chúng ghép lại với nhau,
và những thách thức mà chúng ta có
với tư cách một solutions architect.
Vậy website đầu tiên là WhatIsTheTime.com
và WhatIsTheTime.com cho phép mọi người biết bây giờ là mấy giờ.
Tôi biết nghe có vẻ ngớ ngẩn,
but at least it's so easy that everyone understands it,
and we'll be able to talk about it at length.
So we don't need a database because it's so simple.
Each instance, each server knows what time it is,
and we want to start small.
We're willing to accept downtime,
but overall maybe our app will get more and more popular.
People really wanna know the time around the world,
and so we'll need to scale vertically,
and horizontally maybe removed downtime.
And let's go through
the Solutions Architect journey for this app.
You'll see, we'll see a lot of things on how we can proceed.
So let's start really simple.
Okay, let's start from the very beginning.
You are a solutions architect and you say
you know what would be great?
You have a T2 micro instance and you have a user,
and the user says, "What time it is?",
and say, "Okay, it's 5:30 PM.", done, this is my app.
So we have a public EC2 instance,
and because we want to make the EC2 instance
have a static IP address in case something happens,
and which we restart it,
then I will attach a Elastic IP address to it.
So this is my first PoC, it's working really great.
Our users are able to access our application,
and we're getting great feedback.
So now what's happening is that our users are
really having a good time using our application.
So they said to their friends,
"Hey, you should also use this application."
So another friend comes in and says, "What time is it?"
And 7:30 PM and another friend comes in,
"What time is it?", 6:30 PM and so we realize here that
our application is getting more and more traffic,
and certainly the T2 Micro instance isn't enough.
And so as a solution architect we say, wait a minute,
maybe we should replace that T2 Micro instance
by something a little bit bigger to handle the load,
so that's called vertical scaling.
Maybe we'll make it an M5 large type of instance.
So what we do is that we stop the instance,
we change the instance type,
and then we start again the instance, and here we go.
This is an M5 type of instance.
So what happened here is that it has the same public IP
because it has an elastic IP address,
so people are still able to access our application,
but we have experienced downtime while upgrading to an M5.
And so our users were not really happy during that moment,
they were not able to access our application.
So this works, but this isn't great, right?
So next we're going really popular,
and it's time to scale horizontally.
So we get, remember this application M5 has
one public IP, elastic IP attached to it.
And now we're getting tons of users.
And so they're all asking what time is it?
And so now we wanna scale horizontally.
So we start adding EC2 instances, they're all M5 large,
and they all have an elastic IP attached to it.
So now on top of having three EC2 instance,
we have three elastic IP.
And so our users, they need to be aware
of the the exact values of these three elastic IP
to talk to our instances.
And so that's called horizontal scaling.
We're doing not bad,
but we see we starting to reach some limits.
Now the users need to be aware of more and more IPs,
and we have to manage more infrastructure,
and it's pretty tricky, right?
So okay, let's change the approach.
Now we have three EC2 instances,
M5, and let's remove Elastic IP
because it's something that we can't really manage.
There's only five elastic IP
per region per accounts by default, so it's not a lot.
And so instead our users, what they're going to do
is that they're going to leverage Route 53.
So we've set up Route 53,
and the website URL is api.whatisthetime.com.
And we've decided it's going to be an A record
with a TTL of one hour.
An A record means that from a DNS like this,
it's going to give me a list of IP.
So remember, Route 53 A record is IP.
So great, so the users query Route 53,
and then they get the IP addresses of our EC2 instances,
and they can change over time, it doesn't really matter
because Route 53 will get updated,
we'll update it and keep it in sync.
And so our users are now able to access our EC2 instances,
and we don't have any Elastic IP to manage anymore.
So using Route 53, we've done some good improvements.
But what happens is that
now we want to be able to scale, you know,
and be able to add and remove instances on the flight.
And so when we do remove an instance, what happens?
Well it seems like these users on the top,
they were talking to this M5 large instance,
but now it's gone, and it turns out that
if they do a Route 53 query,
because the TTL was one hour,
they're using the same response for one hour.
So for one hour they'll try to connect
to the instance and that instance is gone.
And so here it's not really great
because even though these users are having a good time,
and maybe after one hour,
these user will be able to connect to these two instances,
they're not having a good time right now
'cause they think that our application is down,
and that's really, really bad.
So, okay, so this is an architecture,
and we see the limit of it.
So how can we push this a little bit further?
So let's talk about adding a load balancer.
So instead now having,
we don't have a public instances anymore,
we have private EC2 instances,
and we're going to launch them
in the same availability zone
because we don't know any better.
So we've launched them manually,
we have three and five large instances,
and we are following this course,
and we said, okay, let's use a load balancer.
And you know what, on top of it,
it's going to have health checks such as
if one instance is down or not working,
at least we won't send traffic
from our users to the instance.
So okay, we're linking the two together.
So my ELB is going to be public facing,
whereas my private instance EC2 instances are in the back,
and so they restrict traffic between these two
using maybe a security group rule that we've seen before
using security group as a reference.
Okay, that sounds pretty good.
So now our users, they're going to query
for whatisthetime.com, but this time, it cannot be A record
because a load balancer has its IP changing all the time.
And so instead, because it's a load balancer,
we can use an alias record.
And this alias record is perfect
because it will point from Route 53 to the ELB,
and everything will work really great.
And so here we'll change the DNS.
But now the users connect to our load balancer,
and our load balancers redirects us
to our EC2 instances, and balances the traffic out.
And it's really great
'cause now, we can add and remove these instances,
and register them with a load balancer,
and we won't have any downtime for our users
thanks to the health checks feature.
So really, really good.
But now adding and removing instances manually
is pretty hard to do.
So what about we just leveraged something
we just learned in this class,
and we'll launch an auto-scaling group.
So now we have our API on the left hand side,
it's the same thing, Route 53, ELB.
But on the right hand side now,
we're gonna have an availability zone,
and we're going to launch private EC2 instances,
but this time they're going to be managed
by an auto-scaling group.
And so this allows our auto-scaling group
to basically scale on demand,
maybe in the morning, no one wants to know the time of it,
yet night when people want to leave work,
they want to know the time.
So we're able to scale based on the demand,
scale in and scale out.
And this is really, really great
because now we have an application,
no downtime, auto-scaling, load balanced.
It seems like a really stable architecture and it is,
but what happens is that there's an earthquake
that happens and availability one goes down.
So one goes down, and guess what?
Our application is entirely down, our users are not happy.
And so Amazon comes to us and says, "Yes, it's because,
you haven't implemented a multi-AZ application,
and we recommend you to implement multi-AZ
to be highly available."
So okay, we say, "All right,
let's change a little bit the things."
Now we're gonna have to ELB, and on top of health checks,
it's also going to be multi-AZ,
and it's going to be launched on AZ 1 to 3.
So three AZs for this ELB and our auto-scaling group as well
is going to span across multiple AZ,
and this allows us maybe to have two instances in AZ one,
two instances in AZ two, and one instance in AZ three.
And so the cool thing now is that,
oh great, like if AZ one goes down,
well, we'll still have AZ two and AZ three
to serve our traffic to our users,
and we've effectively made our app multi-AZ,
and highly available and resilient to failure.
Pretty awesome, right?
Okay, how far can we go with this, let's keep on going.
So we have two AZ and we know that
at least one instance we'll be running in each AZ,
so why don't we reserve capacity?
Why don't we start basically
diminishing the cost of our application
because we know that for sure two instances
must be running at all time during the year.
And so by reserving instance,
maybe for the minimum capacity of our auto-scaling group,
then we're going to save a lot of cost in the future.
Whereas the new instances that get launched,
maybe they're gonna be temporary, so on demand is fine.
Or if we are a bit crazy,
we can even use spot instances for less cost,
but we might have the instances being terminated.
And so it's really interesting, right?
Because we've seen an architecture going
from a very small application all the way to a, you know,
load balance, auto-scaling group, multi-AZ, health checks,
reserved instances type of application.
And so to me that's as a solutions architect, your journey;
it's up to understand what are the requirements,
and what should we architect
in returns to these requirements,
and this is what the exam will test you.
Now, this is the first architecture discussion, trust me,
there will be many others in the next lecture.
But for now, let's just review what we've discussed.
What we've discussed, for example, what it is to,
for an EC2 instance to have a public IP and a private IP,
you know, where does it fit in our architecture diagram?
We've also seen what is the benefit of having
an Elastic IP versus using Route 53
versus maybe using a Load Balancer for our application.
We've also seen that, because of the Route 53 TTL,
we couldn't really use A records.
So we had to use an Load-Balancer and Alias Record,
and so that would be able to see
how Route 53 can fit in this whole picture.
We've seen how to maintain EC2 instances manually,
and then we say, well, it's too much maintenance,
let's use auto-scaling groups, and you know what,
it's actually gonna provide us even better costing
because it'll just scale on demand,
and we'll just have the perfect amount
of EC2 instances at any time.
And then we said, okay, let's go into Multi AZ,
we can survive disasters this way.
And let's enable ELB Health Checks, so just only
the instances that are correctly responding do get traffic.
And we've seen how to set up security group rules
so that the EC2 instances would only receive traffics
coming from the ELB, and finally we said,
"You know what, let's look at capacity,
let's do some cost saving.
We always know that we want two EC2 instances
running at any time, so let's reserve these instances,
and then we'll bring lots of cost savings."