Được rồi, trong bài học trước chúng ta đang
trong một loại ứng dụng web stateless,
WhatIsTheTime.com.
Chỉ trả lời giờ hiện tại.
Và chúng ta không cần bất kỳ database nào
hoặc bất kỳ thông tin nào, thông tin bên ngoài
để trả lời câu hỏi đó.
Nhưng bây giờ chúng ta sẽ đi vào một ứng dụng web stateful,
gọi là MyClothes.com,
và MyClothes.com cho phép mọi người mua quần áo trực tuyến.
And there's a shopping cart when you navigate MyClothes.com
and we're having hundreds of users at the same time,
so all these users are navigating the website.
And we wanna be able to scale,
maintain horizontal scalability,
and keep our application web tier,
as stateless as possible.
So even though there's a state of shopping cart
we want to be able to scale our web application
as easily as possible.
So users, that means
that they should not lose their shopping cart
while navigating our website.
That would be really bad.
And maybe also have their details such as address
et cetera, in a database that we can store effectively
and make accessible from anywhere.
So let's see how we can proceed.
You'll see it's going to be yet another fun
but challenging discussion.
Okay, so this is our application, and I'm going to go fast.
Here's the kind
of architecture we've seen in the previous lecture.
So we have our user Route 53, Multi AZ,
ELB, Autoscaling Group three AZ, very basic.
So our application is accessing our ELB
and our ELB says, all right, you're gonna talk
to this instance and you create a shopping cart.
And then the next request is going to go
not to the same instance, but to another instance.
And now the shopping cart is lost.
And the user says, oh, there must just be a little bug.
I'm going to try again.
So it adds something into the shopping cart
and it gets redirected to the third instance
which doesn't have the shopping cart.
So basically the user is going crazy and say, wait
I'm losing my shopping cart every time I do something.
This is really weird.
MyClothes.com is a bad website.
I don't wanna shop on it.
And we lost money.
So how do we fix this?
Well, we can introduce stickiness or session affinity
and that's an ELB feature.
So we enable ELB stickiness, and now our user talks
to your first instance, adds something
into the shopping cart, and then the second request goes
to the same instance because of stickiness.
And the third request also goes to the same instance.
And actually every request will go to the same instance
because of stickiness, this works really well.
But if an EC2 instance gets terminated for some reason,
then we still lose our shopping cart.
But there is definitely some kind of improvement here
thanks to stickiness and session affinity.
So now let's look at the completely different approach
and introduce user cookies.
So basically, instead of having the EC2 instances
store the content of the shopping cart, let's say
that the user is the one storing the shopping cart content.
And so every time it connects to the load balancer
it basically is going to say, by the way
in my shopping cart, I have all these things.
And that's done through web cookies.
So now if it's talks to the first server
the second server or the third server,
each server will know what the shopping cart content is
because the user is the one sending the shopping
cart content directly into our EC2 instances.
So it's pretty cool, right?
We've achieved statelessness
because now each EC2 instance doesn't need to know
what happened before.
The user will tell us what happened before
but the HTP request, they're getting heavier.
So because we send a shopping cart content in web cookies
we're sending more and more data every time we add something
into our shopping cart.
Additionally, there is some level of security risk
because the cookies, they can be altered by attackers maybe.
And so maybe our user
may have a modified shopping cart all of a sudden.
So when we do have this kind of architecture,
make sure that your EC2 instances do validate the content
of the user cookies.
And then the cookies overall, they can only be so big
they can only be less than four kilobytes total.
So there's only a little information you can store
in the cookies.
You cannot store big data sets.
Okay, so this is the idea.
So this works really well.
This is actually a pattern that many web
application frameworks use
but what if we do something else?
Let's introduce this concept of server session.
So now, instead of sending a whole shopping cart
in web cookies,
we're just going to send a session ID.
That is, just this one for the user.
So we're gonna send this, and in the background
we're gonna have maybe an elastic cage cluster.
And what will happen is that when we send a session ID,
we're gonna talk to an EC2 instance,
and say we're going to add this thing to the cart.
And so the EC2 instance will add the cart content
into the ElastiCache.
And the ID to retrieve this cart content
is going to be the session ID.
So when our user basically does a second request
with a session ID, and it goes to another EC2 instance,
that other EC2 instance is able using that session ID
to look up the content
of the cart from ElastiCache and retrieve that session data.
And then for last request, the same pattern.
The really cool thing with ElastiCache,
remember it is sub millisecond performance.
So all these things happen really quickly
and that's really great.
An alternative, by the way, for storing session data,
we haven't seen it yet,
it's called DynamoDB, but I'm just putting it out here
just in case you know what DynamoDB is.
So it's a really cool pattern here.
It's more secure because now ElastiCache
is a source of truth and no attackers
can change what's in ElastiCache.
So we have a much secure
much more secure type of pattern, and it is very common.
So now, okay, we have ElastiCache.
We figured this out.
We wanna store user data in a database.
So we wanna store the user address.
So again, we're gonna talk to our EC2 instance,
and this time it's going to talk to an RDS instance.
And the RDS is going to be great
because it's for long term storage.
And so we can store and retrieve user data,
such as address, name, et cetera,
directly by talking to RDS.
And each of our instances can talk to RDS.
And we effectively get, again
some kind of Multi AZ stateless solution.
So our web up traffic is going great.
Our website is doing amazing,
and now we have more and more users.
And we realize that one of most of the thing they do
is they navigate the website.
They do reads, they get product information,
all that kind of stuff.
So how do we scale reads?
Well, we can use an RDS Master, which takes the writes
but we can also have RDS Read Replicas
with some replication happening.
And so anytime we read stuff, we can read
from the Read Replica,
and we can have up to 15 Read Replicas in RDS.
And they will allow us
to scale the reads of our RDS database.
There is another alternative called lazy loading
where we use the cache. And so the way it works is
that our user talks to an EC2 instance.
It looks in the cache and says,
do you have this information?
If it doesn't have it, then it's going to read
from RDS and put it back into ElastiCache.
So just the information is cached.
And so the other EC2 instances,
they're doing the same thing,
but this time when they talked to ElastiCache,
they will have the information and they get a cache hit.
And so they directly get the response right away
because it's been cached.
And so this pattern allows us to do less traffic on RDS,
basically decrease the CPU usage
on RDS and improve performance at the same time.
But we need to do cache maintenance now
and it's a bit more difficult.
And again, this has to be done application side.
So pretty awesome.
Now we have our application.
It's scalable, it has many, many reads
but we wanna survive disasters.
We don't want to be stricken by disasters.
So how do we do?
Our user talks to our Route 53,
but now we ha have a Multi AZ ELB.
And by the way, Route 53 is already highly available.
You don't need to do anything.
But so for our load balancer
we're going to make it Multi AZ.
Our order scaling group is Multi AZ.
And then RDS, there is a Multi AZ feature.
The other one is going to be a standby replica
that can just take over whenever there's a disaster.
And ElastiCache also has a Multi AZ feature
if you use Redis.
So really cool.
Now we basically have a Multi AZ application
all across the board,
and we know for sure
that we can survive an availability zone
in AWS going down.
Now for security groups, we want to be super secure.
So maybe we'll open HTTP/HTTPS traffic from anywhere
on the ALB side.
For the EC2 instance side,
we just want to restrict traffic
coming from the load balancer.
And maybe for ElastiCache, we just wanna restrict traffic
coming from the EC2 security group.
And from RDS, same thing.
We want to restrict traffic coming directly
from the EC2 security group.
So that's it.
So now let's just talk about this architecture
for web application.
So we have discussed ELB sticky sessions,
web clients for storing cookies
and making our web app stateless
or using maybe a session ID and a session cache,
physically using ElastiCache.
And as an alternative, we can use DynamoDB.
We can also use ElastiCache
to cache data from RDS in case of reads.
And we can use Multi AZ to be surviving disasters.
RDS, we can use it for storing user data.
So more durable type of data.
Read replicas can be used for scaling reads
or we can also use ElastiCache
And then we have Multi AZ for disaster recovery.
And on top of it, we added tight security
for security groups referencing each other.
So this is a more complicated application.
There's three tier
because there is the web tier,
the client tier, the web tier, and the database tier.
But this is a very common architecture overall.
And yes, it may start to increase in cost, but it is okay.
At least we know the trade-offs we're making.
If we want Multi AZ, yes, for sure, we have to pay more.
If we want to scale the reads, yes, for sure
we'll have to pay more as well.
But it gives us some good trade-offs
and architecture decisions that we have to make.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.