So now let's talk about Amazon Transcribe.
So as the name indicates,
it allows you to automatically convert speech into text.
So you pass in some audio
and automatically is going to be transcribed into text,
so you could say, hey, hello,
my name is Stephane and I hope you're enjoying the course.
Now, how does it do it?
Well, it uses a deep learning process called the ASR,
the Automatic Speech Recognition,
to convert speech to text very quickly and accurately
and there are a few features you need to know about.
The first one is that you can automatically remove any PII,
so personally identifiable information, using reduction.
So that means, for example,
if you have someone's age or name or Social Security Number,
this can be automatically removed
and also you can have access
to automatic language identification for multilingual audio.
So if you have some French and some English,
some Spanish, Transcribe is smart enough
to recognize all of those.
So the use cases for Amazon Transcribe
is to transcribe customer service calls,
to automate closed captioning and subtitling,
and also to generate metadata
for media assets to create a fully searchable archive.
So let's have a look at Amazon Transcribe.
So I can create a transcript and I can see
that the specific language right now is set to English US,
so now if I click on start streaming,
hello, I really like this course.
As you can see, the outcome of the audio
get directly transcribed into some text,
so that's pretty cool, right?
Also, you can have the setting to remove some content
and you can remove PII identification.
So I could say, hey,
you can identify and redact it to remove it
and these are the kind of things that can be removed.
So for example, let's have an example
and try it out, so I won't show this all again.
Hello, my name is Stephane, I am 31 years old
and my phone number is 910-747-280
and as you can see now, the things got hidden.
So my name is hidden and my phone is hidden.
Obviously this was not my real phone number.
You cannot try it.
Okay and last thing I want to show you
is that you can actually stream into multiple languages.
So you have automatic language identification.
So I would choose English and French
and then let's start again.
Hello, this is some recognition happening in English.
(speaking in French)
Pretty awesome, right?
Well, that's it for Amazon Transcribe.
If you wanted to play some more,
you can have a look at all the options in the bottom,
but that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.