Now let's talk about Amazon Translate.
So Translate, as the name indicate,
is a natural and accurate language translation.
Translate allows you to localize content,
for example, your websites and your application,
for your international users
and easily translates large volume of text efficiently.
So for example, say in English, I say,
"Hi, my name is Stephen,"
In French, it would be. (speaking in foreign language)
In Portuguese, it would be. (speaking in foreign language)
And in Hindi, it would be. (speaking in foreign language)
Okay, I just showed off.
So that was it, super easy service.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.