So now let's discuss Amazon Lex and Connect.
So Amazon Lex is the same technology that powers
the Alexa devices by Amazon.
And if you don't know Alexa, Alexa is like a little device
that you have in your home and you say,
"Alexa, what's the weather like tomorrow?"
And it will reply, "The weather is good,
it'll be 24 degrees and it'll be sunny."
So, the idea is that with Amazon Lex,
you get automatic speech recognition, so ASR,
that allows you to convert speech,
so spoken words, into text.
There's also a very good thing
because Lex understands the intent of text, callers
by doing natural language understanding,
so it understands sentences.
And Amazon Lex is a technology
that will help you build chatbots or call center bots.
And talking about call centers,
how do we build a call center?
We have Amazon Connect.
So Amazon Connect is a visual contact center
that allows you to receive calls, create contact flows,
and it's all cloud-based.
And it can integrate with other customer
relationship system, management systems, so CRMs
or AWS services.
And the cool thing about Amazon Connect versus traditional
offering is that there is no upfront payment.
It's about 80% cheaper
than traditional contact center solutions.
So the whole flow of building a smart contact center is
that you will have, for example,
a phone call to schedule an appointment that is made
into a number that is defined by Amazon Connect.
So they call Amazon Connect.
Lex is streaming all the information from this call
and understand the intent of the phone call,
and therefore, it will invoke the right lender function.
And that lender function, for example,
can be very smart and say, "Hey, someone has said
to schedule a meeting tomorrow with Tom at 3:00 PM."
Okay, I will go into my CRM and schedule that meeting
by writing some code.
So this is the whole idea behind Lex and Connect.
So remember Lex is for ASR
and Connect is for contact centers.
So that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.