Now, Amazon Comprehend
is a very simple service from an exam perspective.
All you need to know is that Comprehend is
to comprehend stuff,
so it is for Natural Language Processing, or NLP.
So anytime you will see NLP on the exam,
you would think Amazon Comprehend.
Now what it is, it is a fully managed and serverless service
and it will use machine learning to find insights
and relationships in your text.
For example, it can understand what is the language
of the text, it can extract key phrases,
places, people, brands, or events from that text.
It can understand, do a sentiment analysis to understand
how positive or negative the text you're analyzing is.
It can also analyze a text using tokenization
and parts of speech.
It also has audio.
And finally, it can organize a collection
of text files by topic, and find topics itself.
So, Comprehend is really about getting a lot of data in
and then Comprehend will do the rest
to try to understand the meaning of that data.
So it's about taking text or unstructured data
and structuring it around these features.
So some sample use cases of Natural Language Processing,
or NLP, are for example, to analyze customer interaction.
So say you have a bunch of customers sending you emails
and you want to understand overall based
on your support service what leads to a positive
or negative experience from your customers.
So we use Comprehend to extract these features
and then you will have the business insight
and then you can improve your business,
thanks to that analysis.
You can also, for example, create
and group articles by topics that Comprehend will uncover.
So imagine you have a lot of articles
and you want to group them together instead
of going to them one by one, you would feed them
into Comprehend and then it would output you
the topics you need to group them by.
So that's it.
So again, a bit more information than what you need,
but Comprehend from an exam perspective is
for Natural Language Processing.
So hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.