Another machine learning service on AWS
is called Amazon Kendra.
So this one is a fully-managed document search service
that is powered by machine learning
and it allows you to extract answers from within a document.
That document could be text, PDF, HTML
PowerPoints, Microsoft Word, FAQs, et cetera, et cetera.
So you have a lot of data sources
where these documents may be
and you see some of them right now in the screen
and they're going to be indexed by Amazon Kendra
which is going to build internally
a knowledge index powered by machine learning.
And how does it help from an end-user perspective?
Well, we get natural language search capabilities
just like you go on Google.
So for example, if a user says,
Hey, where is the IT support desk into Amazon Kendra?
Kendra can reply, 1st floor.
And this could be due to the fact that Kendra knows
from all the resources that it took
that the IT support desk was on the 1st floor,
which is quite awesome.
And also, you can just do a normal search
and it will learn from the user interaction and feedback
to promote preferred search results
which is called incremental learning.
Finally, you can fine tune the search results, for example,
based on the important data, importance of data,
the freshness, or whatever custom filters you have, okay?
So from an exam perspective,
whenever you see a document search service,
think Amazon Kendra.
That's it, I will see you in the next lecture.