So now let's talk about Amazon Textracts.
And Amazon Textract is used to extract texts,
so, hence the name.
So you extract text, handwriting,
or data from any scanned document
and behind the scenes, of course,
uses AI or machine learning.
So we have, for example, a driver license,
and then we upload it into Amazon Textract,
and then, automatically, will be analyzed,
and the results will be given to you as a data file,
and so you'll be able to, for example,
extract the date of birth, document ID, and so on.
So you can extract any data, even from forms and tables,
and you can read PDFs, images, and so on.
So the use cases for extracting texts are multiple,
but you could be for financial services
to process invoices or financial reports,
could be for healthcare,
for medical records, and insurance claims,
or for the public sector, for example, for tax forms,
ID documents, and passports.
So that's it for this lecture,
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.