Now let's talk
about the machine learning services on AWS,
and you have to remember them all going into the exam.
So Rekognition is a way for you to do face detections,
to do labeling, and celebrity recognition.
Transcribe is for you to get a way to get subtitles,
for example, to convert your audio into text,
whereas Polly is the opposite.
It allows you to get to use your text
and create audio out of it.
Translate is for you to get translations.
Lex is to build conversational bots or chatbots,
and if you bundle it with Connect,
then you can create a cloud contact center.
Comprehend is a way
for you to do natural language processing.
SageMaker is a fully featured machine learning service
that is accessible to developer and data scientist.
Kendra is going to be an ML-powered document search engine.
Personalize is used
for real-time personalized recommendations
for your customers,
and Textract is used to detect text
and data and extract them from various documents.
So hopefully, you can remember this whole list.
This will get you a few points at the exam.
I hope you liked this lecture,
and I will see you in the next lecture.