Now let's talk about
the machine learning services on AWS,
and you have to remember them all going into the exam.
So, recognition is a way for you to do face detections,
to do labeling, and celebrity recognition.
Transcribe is for you to get,
a way to get subtitles.
For example, to convert your audio into text.
Whereas Polly is the opposite.
It allows you to get,
to use your text and create audio out of it.
Translate is for you to get translations.
Lex is to build conversational robots or chatbots.
And if you bundle it with Connect,
then you can create a cloud contact center.
Comprehend is a way for you
to do natural language processing.
SageMaker is a fully featured machine learning service
that is accessible to developer and data scientist.
Forecast allows you to build highly accurate forecast.
Kendra is going to be an ML-powered document search engine.
Personalize is used for real-time
personalized recommendations for your customers.
And Textract is used to detect text and data,
and extract them from various documents.
So, hopefully you can remember this whole list.
This will get you a few points on the exam.
I hope you like this lecture,
and I will see you in the next lecture.