Okay, so let's discuss
serverless architectures now,
and we're going to create
a mobile application called MyTodoList.
So, what we want to do is have the following requirements.
We want to expose a REST API that has HTTPS endpoints.
We want to be serverless architecture,
and we want the users to be able to directly interact
with their own folder in S3
to manage their data if you want to.
And users should be able to also authenticate
through a managed serverless service.
And finally, users can write and read to-dos,
but they mostly read them.
So, maybe there's something to do around performance here.
The database layer should scale
and should have some really high read throughputs.
So, that's a pretty good requirements.
Now, let's see how we can do it.
Number one is to get started, we have mobile clients,
and we talked about doing a REST HTTPS thing.
So, let's use Amazon API Gateway for this.
This is a great way of doing it.
Now, in the classic serverless API fashion,
API Gateway will invoke a Lambda function,
which basically allows us to scale
and use serverless infrastructure.
Okay, Amazon Lambda needs to be able to store
and read to-do from a database.
A database that scales really well
that is serverless is DynamoDB.
So, here we have DynamoDB as our backend.
Now, we said there was going to be also some kind
of authentication layer going on.
So, for this, we can use a serverless technology such
as Amazon Cognito, so our mobile client can connect
and authenticate to Cognito,
and then API Gateway along the way will verify
the authentication with Cognito.
And so, that gives us a very classic serverless API
that we've just created here.
Nothing new for you here, but it's good to see it again.
Now, if you wanna give our users access
to Amazon S3 bucket, how do we do this?
Well, we have our mobile clients
that authenticates to Amazon Cognito
and Cognito that can generate temporary credentials for us
and return these credentials to our mobile clients.
And these credentials allow our mobile clients to store
and retrieve files in Amazon S3
and basically access their own little space in S3.
So, this is a very classic question as well, how to do this?
And the wrong answer is to store
AWS user credentials on your mobile clients.
You definitely do not want to do this.
What you want to do is really use Amazon Cognito,
and then Amazon is free with temporary credentials.
Okay, so it's a very common question.
So, next, our app is starting to scale.
We're starting to get more users,
and it turns out that we, by looking at the patterns,
figure out that we have a very high read throughput.
So, we have many RCUs,
and the to-dos don't really change much.
They don't get edited very often.
So, how can we change this architecture
to basically improve the read throughput
and decrease maybe the cost overall?
What we can do is use DAX as a caching layer.
So, just before DynamoDB, we'll use DynamoDB DAX,
and this will basically have a caching layer.
And because we're doing so many reads,
now the reads will be cached in DAX.
And so DynamoDB, we won't need as much read capacity units.
Maybe we'll scale better, maybe we'll have less cost overall
because so many reads are cached.
And this is a great way overall
to keep on improving our architecture
in a serverless fashion.
Now, there could be another way of doing caching.
Maybe we want to use DAX, but maybe also we want
to start caching the responses
at the Amazon API gateway level.
This is also something we can do,
and this is also a very good one if you think
that the answers never really change
and that you can start caching a few responses
for a few API routes.
So, overall, really interesting to see these kind
of architectures because they really show you
how serverless is done, where the caching appears.
And in this architecture, nothing is managed by us.
We really pay per usage,
and we really don't think about management of databases.
All these things is done by AWS for us.
So, in this lecture,
we've seen the classic serverless REST API architecture,
basically leveraging HTTPS, API Gateway,
Lambda, and DynamoDB.
And then, we've used Cognito
to generate temporary credential, which gives us access
to an S3 bucket with a restricted policy.
And we could use the exact same app pattern using Cognito.
So, our app can access maybe DynamoDB
or Lambda directly or whatever.
This is a very common pattern.
Now, caching the reads on DynamoDB can be done using DAX.
It's a very easy way to enable,
and you can bring not only performance improvement,
but also cost reduction and caching the REST request
can be done at the API Gateway level
if we have very static responses.
Security, finally, for the entire thing can be done
with Cognito and Cognito is directly integrated
with the API Gateway.
So, this was a very basic example,
but it gives us started basically
on serverless architectures
and shows us all the different components we've seen
in the past section.
So, I hope that helps,
and I will see you in the next lecture.