Okay, so let's talk
about a serverless hosted website,
maybe called MyBlog.com.
So our website should scale globally,
and we rarely write blogs,
we often read blogs.
So our blog is seen
by hundreds of thousands of people online,
and we really add blogs maybe one a day, one a week.
But, most of the time, these blogs are being read.
And so most of my websites is going
to be purely static files,
and maybe a little bit of my website is going
to be a dynamic REST API.
I want to implement caching, where possible,
to really save cost and save latency,
and have a great user experience.
And any new user that subscribes to my website,
to my blog, I really want them
to receive a warm welcome email.
And this should be serverless.
And any photo uploaded to the blog,
I also wanna have a thumbnail being generated,
also serverless, because I really like serverless.
So how do we implement all these requirements?
Number one, we wanna serve content,
it's static and it's global.
So if you remember, we have our clients,
and our static content maybe stored in Amazon S3.
So how do we expose that bucket?
Remember the Amazon S3 bucket is in specific region.
How do we expose this globally?
Well, we can use Amazon CloudFront.
And Amazon CloudFront is a global distribution CDN,
and so basically our client is going to interact
with edge locations of Amazon CloudFront,
and it's going to cache data coming straight from Amazon S3.
Okay. Super easy.
We've seen CloudFront,
we've seen S3 is a classic architecture.
Now how do we do this securely?
Now, that's a very common question as well.
So we have the clients, it's interacting with CloudFront
and it's a global distribution still.
But now we will add an Origin Access Control
which will ensure that our Amazon S3 bucket
can only be accessed by CloudFront.
For this, we will add a bucket policy
to only authorize the CloudFront distribution.
Therefore, a user trying
to access our Amazon S3 bucket directly
will not be authorized,
and we have secured our Amazon S3 buckets.
Okay, so now we have this, and this is really good.
How do we add a public serverless REST API?
Well, for this, we'll have a REST HTTPS,
talking to Amazon API Gateway,
invoking a Lambda function,
maybe querying and reading from DynamoDB.
And because we have so many reads,
maybe DAX is a great caching layer we could use.
Okay? So far very easy.
If we're going global,
maybe we could be leveraging DynamoDB Global Databases
to reduce the latencies in part of the world.
That also could be a really good way
of maybe speeding up our infrastructure
and our architecture.
Okay, so this is fine.
We have everything we need.
Now let's talk about the User Welcome email flow.
Well here, remember when a user subscribes,
I want them to be having an email saying,
hello, how are you?
So for this maybe in DynamoDB,
we want to enable streams of changes.
So we'll have a DynamoDB stream being created,
and that DynamoDB stream will invoke a Lambda function.
That Lambda function is going to be very special.
It's going to have an IAM role,
which allows us to use Amazon SES.
So we haven't seen what Amazon SES is,
but it's really simple.
It's called Amazon Simple Email Service.
So SES, and it basically allows us to send emails.
So here our Amazon Lambda function can use the AWS SDK
to send emails from Amazon SES.
And here we go.
We have a basically serverless User Welcome email flow,
and really simple, no infrastructure to manage,
it just works and scales really, really well.
Okay, so now we said,
okay, if users upload images,
we want thumbnails to be created.
So our clients is going to maybe upload
to our S3 bucket directly,
or maybe we again have an OAC and a CloudFront distribution,
in which case our clients will upload photos to CloudFront,
and CloudFront will forward them onto the Amazon S3 bucket.
And this is called S3 Transfer Acceleration.
So either directly to S3 or using Transfer Acceleration.
And then what we'll do is
that whenever a file is added to S3,
it's going to trigger a Lambda function,
so Lambda can be triggered by S3,
and Lambda will be creating a thumbnail,
and putting that thumbnail into an S3 bucket,
could be a different bucket, for example.
And just to show you that it's possible,
Amazon S3 also has triggers to SQS and SNS.
Now this is optional, and from SQS SNS you can do
whatever you want, but it's just to show you
that you're very free into how you want things to work.
And so Amazon S3 can invoke either Lambda, SQS or SNS,
and you're really free to think
about your solution architecture
and how to make things serverless
and easy for you on your end.
So this is quite a complete architecture we've just done,
but it's all serverless, it's all scaling globally,
and I think that's what matters most.
So we've seen static content being distributed
using CloudFront with S3.
We've seen the rest API that was serverless.
We didn't need Cognito this time,
because it was a public REST API.
And we leveraged a Global DynamoDB Table,
to serve the data globally.
We could have used also Aurora Global Database,
but in this case he wouldn't have been serverless,
it would've been provisioned Aurora.
Or we could also enable DynamoDB streams.
Basically, these streams will tell us about changes
to our user tables and then trigger a Lambda function.
And that Lambda function had an IAM role attached to it,
so it could use SES or Simple Email Service.
And this was just to send emails in a serverless way.
And S3, we've seen that it could trigger SQS, SNS, Lambda
to notify of events.
So quite a lot of learnings.
All these things we know,
but now it's I think, really nice
to see all these things working together,
and how we can create really cool applications
using all the concepts we know.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.