So you need to know a few Lambda Limits
before going into the exam,
because the exam likes to see if you know these limits
and these limits are per region.
So we have some execution limits
and then we'll have some deployment limits.
So execution is that the memory allocation
is between 128 megabytes to 10 gigabytes.
And this is in 64 megabytes increments.
And when we increase the memory,
then we have more vCPU, you understand this now.
The maximum execution time is 900 seconds
which is 15 minutes.
So anything above that is not a good use case for Lambda.
Environment variables,
we can only have up to four kilobytes
of environment variable,
so a little bit amount of space.
But there is a temp space
if you want to pull in some big files
while we create another function.
And so this is this capacity in the /tmp folder
and we have up to 10 gigabytes there.
We can have up to 1000 concurrent executions
over Lambda functions.
This can be increased as well if we do a request.
But it's good to use reserved concurrency early on.
Finally, for deployments,
the max size for your compressed zip is 50,
uncompressed, it is 250 megabytes.
So anything above that, for example, big files,
you should use a /tmp space instead.
So as I said,
in case you need to have a big file (mumbles),
please use that directory.
And finally,
again, the environment variables is four kilobytes.
So once you know all these limits,
when the exam will ask you a few questions
such as we need 30 gigabytes of RAM,
or we need 30 minutes of execution time,
or we need a big file of three gigabytes,
then you will know that Lambda is not the right way
to run this workload.
I hope that was helpful,
and I will see you in the next lecture.