So now, let's talk about Lambda SnapStart.
So this is a feature of Lambda
that helps you improve your Lambda function performance
up to 10x at no extra cost for your Lambda functions
that are running on Java 11 or above.
So let's understand how and why.
So your Lambda invocation have several lifecycle phases.
And if SnapStart is disabled
and you have, again, remember a Lambda function
that is running on Java,
then whenever your Lambda function is invoked,
your Java code is going to be initialized, then invoked,
and then there is going to be a shutdown.
But when you enable SnapStart,
then the function is going to be invoked
from a pre-initialized state.
That means, there is no function initialization
from scratch.
So when you enable SnapStart,
then your Lambda function running Java again is invoked,
but the function is pre-initialized.
And so this init phase,
which can last a very long time in Java is gone.
And you go straight into the invoke phase
and then the shutdown down phase.
So this is a feature
that is completely free and how does it work?
Well, whenever you publish a new Lambda version,
then Lambda is going to initialize your function.
So this init phase is going to be done ahead of time.
Then a snapshot of the memory
and the disc state
of your initialized function is going to be taken.
And finally, this snapshot is going to be caged
for low-latency access, which will allow your function
to have what's called a SnapStart, a rapid start.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.