So let's talk about
Customization At The Edge.
So what does it mean?
Well we know we deploy our functions
and our applications in a specific region,
but sometimes using, for example, CloudFront,
we have the Edge locations are distributing our content.
And sometimes the modern applications require
to execute some form of logic at the Edge
before reaching the application itself.
So these are called Edge Functions,
and this is a piece of code that you write
and that you will attach to your CloudFront distributions.
The idea is that you want to run these functions
close to users in order to minimize latency in some cases.
So CloudFront has two kinds of functions,
you have the CloudFront Functions and Lambda@Edge.
The idea will be to be able to understand
when they are required and their differences,
and will do this in this lecture.
But using the Edge Functions,
you don't have to manage any servers,
these Edge Functions are deployed globally.
And the use cases of them,
for example, would be to customize the CDN content
coming out of CloudFront.
Also, you only pay for what you use,
and it is fully serverless.
So now let's have a deeper look
into these things, the use cases.
The first one is around website security and privacy,
then we have dynamic web applications at the Edge,
we can do search engine optimization, SEO,
we can do intelligent routing across
Origins and data center,
Bot mitigation at the Edge,
real-time image transformation at the Edge,
A/B testing, user authentication and authorization,
user prioritization, user tracking and analytics, and so on.
So this is a lot of different customizations
we can have using CloudFront Functions and Lambda@Edge.
So now let's discuss what CloudFront Functions
are used for and how they work.
So this is what a typical request
into CloudFront looks like.
So the client will do a request into CloudFront,
and this is called a viewer request,
because the client views it.
Then CloudFront will do an origin request
into your origin server,
the server will reply to CloudFront,
so we have an origin response,
and finally CloudFront sends that response to the client,
so we have a viewer response.
Now CloudFront Functions are lightweight functions
written in JavaScript,
and they modified the viewer request and response.
They're used for high-scale,
latency-sensitive CDN customizations,
which gives you sub-millisecond startup times,
and a scale of millions of requests per second.
As I said, they're used to change viewer request
and responses only,
so the view request is after CloudFront
receives a request from a viewer, we can modify this,
or the viewer response is to
before CloudFront forwards the response back to the viewer.
It's a native feature of CloudFront,
and the entire code is managed
from within CloudFront directly.
Remember, CloudFront Functions high performance,
high scale only for the viewer request and response.
Now Lambda@Edge is a bit more,
so you can modify all of them.
So these are functions returned in NodeJS or Python,
and you scale to 1000s of requests per second,
and it's used to change CloudFront request
and response, multiple ones, so all of them actually,
the viewer request and the origin request,
which is before CloudFront forwards a request to the origin.
You also have the origin response,
which is after CloudFront receives the response
from the origin, and the viewer response,
which is before CloudFront forwards
the response back to the viewer.
You author your function in one region,
which is us-east-1, which is the same region
where you manage your CloudFront distributions,
and then CloudFront is going to replicate this function
to all of its locations.
So we have a table here to differentiate
between CloudFront Functions and Lambda@Edge.
So one notable difference is the runtime support,
of course JavaScript only for CloudFront Functions,
and then NodeJS and Python for Lambda@Edge.
The scale is really, really high scale
for CloudFront Functions, we're talking about
millions of requests per second,
versus thousands for Lambda@Edge.
Now where the trigger is happening is a big difference.
So Lambda@Edge has impact on both
the viewer request and the origin,
whereas the CloudFront Functions is only on the viewer.
And very important, the max execution time
is less than one millisecond for CloudFront Functions,
so they're very, very quick and simple functions.
Whereas for Lambda@Edge you can get
up to 5 to 10 seconds,
so you can perform a lot of logic in these functions.
The rest, you can have a look, okay?
Now in terms of use cases,
CloudFront Functions is going to be for
cache key normalization,
so to transform, for example the request attributes
to create an optimal cache key.
Header manipulation to insert, modify, or delete
HTTP headers in the request or response,
or to do URL rewrites or redirects,
or to request of an authorization
to create and validate JWT tokens to allow or deny request.
So all these things can be executed
in less than one millisecond,
whereas Lambda@Edge has a longer execution time,
it could be up to 10 seconds, for example.
You have adjustable CPU and memory,
so you can load a lot of libraries,
and your code can depend therefore,
on third party libraries, such as the SDK
if you wanted to access other AWS services.
You also have network access to external services
for processing the data,
so you can really perform some big integrations.
And Lambd@Edge gives you file system access,
or access to the body itself of the HTTP request,
so you can do some more customizations.
So hopefully that helps you.
I hope you liked this lecture,
and I will see you in the next lecture.