Is there a tight integration from RDS, Aurora, and Lambda?
Well, we can actually invoke Lambda functions
from within your database instance in some cases.
And this would allow you to actually process data events
happening from within your database.
So this is supported, for example,
by RDS for PostgreSQL, and Aurora MySQL.
And the idea is that, for example,
a user is going to insert an event data into your table,
your registration table.
And RDS will be set up
to directly invoke your Lambda function.
Your Lambda function may send a welcome email to your user,
and then the user will receive it.
This is something that you have to set up
from within the database by connecting to it.
This is not something that you set up from the AWS console.
And when you do do that
the RDS instance is the one invoking your Lambda function.
And so therefore you must sure to have allowed
the inbound traffic from the RDS database instance
to the Lambda function through whatever way,
either because your Lambda is on the public interest.
So we can use the Invoke,
or the NAT gateway, or the VPC endpoints and so on.
But network connectivity is important.
On top of it, of course,
because your RDS database instance is going to
invoke your Lambda function,
then you must have the required permissions
to invoke the Lambda function.
And so you make sure that your database instance
has a proper IAM policy.
This is completely different
from using the RDS event notifications.
So these notifications are happening within AWS
and there are notifications that tell you information
about the database instance itself.
For example, when it was created,
when it was started, and so on.
And you don't have any information
of the data happening within your database.
So don't fall for this trap.
You can subscribe, for example,
to events about your database instance,
your database snapshots, your parameter group,
your security group, your proxy,
or the custom engine version.
But you're not gonna get information
about the data within your database.
You get near real time events,
so up to five minutes of delivery.
And then you can send these to SNS,
or you can also intercept them in EventBridge.
So from SNS, we can, for example,
send them to an SQS Queue, or a Lambda function.
And from Event Bridge
you can have so many different destinations,
including, for example, a Lambda function.
But remember, you do not get information
about the data events themselves.
You have to use the previous methodology
as I've shown you from before.
Okay, that's it for this lecture,
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.