So let's talk about the advanced features
that can come up at the exam for DynamoDB.
And the first one is DynamoDB Accelerator or DAX.
So this is a fully-managed, highly available,
and seamless in-memory cache for DynamoDB.
The idea is that if you have a lot of reads
on your DynamoDB table,
then you can create a DAX cluster
to solve read congestion by caching the data.
And with DynamoDB DAX,
you get microseconds latency for cached data.
So this is something you have to look out for
in terms of keywords at the exam.
It doesn't require for you
to change any of your application logic
because the DAX cluster is compatible
with the existing DynamoDB APIs.
So you have your DynamoDB tables and your application,
and you will just create a DAX cluster
made of few cache nodes, connect to this DAX cluster.
And then behind the scenes,
the DAX cluster is connected to your Amazon DynamoDB table.
The cache has a default TTL of five minutes,
but you can change this.
So you may ask me,
why should I use DAX and not elastic cache?
Well, DAX is in front of DynamoDB
and it's going to be very helpful
for individual objects cache or queries,
and scanned queries' cache.
But if you want to store, say, aggregation results,
then Amazon ElastiCache is a great way to do it.
So if you want to store a very big computation
that you've done on top of Amazon DynamoDB.
So they're not drop-in replacements for one another,
they're actually complementary.
But most of the time,
for caching solution on top of Amazon DynamoDB,
it's just going to be using DynamoDB Accelerator DAX.
You can also do stream processing on top of DynamoDB.
The idea is that you want to have a stream
of all the modifications that happen on your table.
Would it be create, update, and delete.
And the use cases for that will be, for example,
to react to changes on your DynamoDB table in real time.
For example, to send a welcome email
whenever you have a new user in your user's table.
Or if so, you may wanna do real-time usage analytics,
or maybe you want to insert data into a derivative table,
or you want to implement cross region replication,
or you want to invoke Lambda on any changes made
on your DynamoDB table.
So two kind of stream processing on DynamoDB.
You have DynamoDB Streams, with 24 hours retention,
a limited number of consumers,
and is going to be greatly used with Lambda triggers.
Or if you wanted to read it yourself,
there is something
called the DynamoDB Stream Kinesis Adapter.
Or you can also choose to send all your changes
directly into a Kinesis Data Streams.
And here you can have up to one year of retention,
you can have a much higher number of consumers,
and you have a much higher number
of ways to process the data,
whether we blend the functions, Kinesis Data Analytics,
Kinesis Data Firehose, Glue Streaming ETLs, and so on.
So let's have a look at an architectural diagram
to understand DynamoDB Streams better.
So your application does create updates
and delete operations on top of your DynamoDB table,
which is going to be either a DynamoDB Streams
or a Kinesis Data Streams.
If you choose to use Kinesis Data Streams,
then you can use Kinesis Data Firehose.
And from this, you can send your data into Amazon Redshift
for analytics purposes,
or Amazon S3 if you want to archive some of the data,
or Amazon OpenSearch to do some indexing
and some searches on top of it.
Or if you are using DynamoDB Streams,
you can have a processing layer
and you can use either the DynamoDB KCL Adapter
to run your applications
on top of EC2 instances or Lambda functions.
And from there, do some notifications on top of SNS
or do some filtering and transformations
into another DynamoDB table.
Or use the processing layer to do whatever you want,
such as, again, send the data to Amazon OpenSearch.
So I didn't represent all the possibilities
or our architectures.
Of course, you can have EC22 instances
reading from Kinesis Data Streams.
You can have Kinesis Data Analytics and so on
on top of Kinesis Data Streams, many, many transformations.
But again, you know enough now
to figure out what is going to be the right architecture
at the right time.
DynamoDB also has a concept of global table.
So a global table is a table, of course,
that is going to be replicated across multiple regions.
So you can have a table in US-East-1
and a table in AP-Southeast-2.
And there is a two-way replication between the tables.
That means that you can write to a table
either in US-East-1 and AP-Southeast-2.
So here, the idea with global tables
is to make DynamoDB accessible
with low latency in multiple regions.
And it is an Active-Active replication.
That means that your applications can read and write
to the table in any specific region.
And to enable global tables,
you must first enable DynamoDB Streams
because this is the underlying infrastructure
to replicate the table across regions.
DynamoDB also has a feature named Time To Live, or TTL.
The idea is that you want to automatically delete items
after an expiry timestamp.
So you have your table, SessionData,
and then you will have one last attribute
called ExpTime, which is your TTL,
and it has a timestamp in it.
And the idea is that you're going to define a TTL.
And as soon as the current time in the Epoch timestamp
is going to be over your ExpTime column,
then automatically it's going to expire items
and then eventually delete them through a deletion process.
So the idea is that the items in your data table
are going to be deleted after a while.
So the use cases for this will be to only store data
by keeping only the most current items
or to adhere to regulatory obligations by,
for example, deleting data after two years.
Or another use case that is very common at the exam
is the web session handling.
So a user would log into your website,
and then would've a session.
And you would keep the session in a central place,
such as DynamoDB for two hours.
And you would set the session data there
and any kind of applications can access it.
And at some point, after two hours,
if it hasn't been renewed,
then it will expire and move away from this table.
You can also use DynamoDB for disaster recovery.
So what are your backups options?
Well, you can have continuous backups
with point-in-time recovery, PITR.
So it's optionally enabled,
but you can have it for the last 35 days.
And then if you enable it,
you can do a point-in-time recovery
to any time within the backup window.
And if you do happen to do a recovery,
then it will create a new table.
If you wanted to have longer term backups,
then you can use on-demand backups,
and they will be retained until you delete them explicitly.
And doing these kind of backups
do not affect the performance
or the latency of your DynamoDB table.
And if you wanted to have
a better management of your backups,
you can use the AWS Backup Service,
and this will enable you to have lifecycle policies
for your backups and so on.
And also copy your backups across regions
for disaster recovery purposes.
And again, if you were to do a recovery
of one of these backups, it will create a new table.
Now, let's talk about the integrations
between DynamoDB and Amazon S3.
So you can export a table into S3, just like this.
And to do so, you must enable point-in-time recovery
and you would export DynamoDB table into S3.
For example, if you wanted to do some queries,
for example, using the Amazon Athena engine.
So you can export at any point in time
during the last 35 days
because you've enabled continuous backups.
And when you do an export,
this does not affect the read capacity of your table
or your performance.
So with this, you can perform,
for example, data analysis on top of DynamoDB
through exporting through Amazon S3 first.
You can also use this to retain snapshots for auditing,
or to do any kind of big transformation,
maybe any ETL of the data before importing it back
into a new DynamoDB table, for example.
The format of the export can be in DynamoDB JSON
or the ION format.
And similarly, you can import to Amazon S3.
So you can export from S3 into the CSV, JSON, or ION format
back into a new DynamoDB table.
And this does not consume any write capacity
and it will create a new table.
If there are any import errors,
they will be logged in CloudWatch Logs.
So that's it for DynamoDB. I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.