So let's open API Gateway
and we are in the API Gateway console.
So as you can see in here,
I have option of choosing an API type.
So we have HTTP, APIs, we have WebSocket API,
REST API, which are public or private,
and so as such, we will only deal with a REST API for now.
So we can try out new console by clicking on this
and this is going to be the default very soon.
So please make sure to have that.
And then you choose REST API, and then you build it.
So when you build an API, a REST API
you have several options.
You can create a new API, you can import one
from an open API definition file.
So where it's says file and just import
and API's created for you.
You can clone an existing API
or you can start from the example API.
For us, we were going to start from a new API
and the name is going to be MyFirstAPI.
Now as you see for the API endpoint type,
we have three options.
We have Regional, Edge-optimized, or Private.
So Regional is going to be deployed in one region.
Edge-optimized is going to be deployed
in many different regions,
but it's at the edge that is going to be deployed.
And then one, the API will still live in one region.
Or private is just private not exposed to the web.
To keep things simple right now
I'm going to choose regional API type.
So let me create the API.
And here we are.
So now we are here,
we are going to create our first method in this API.
So for this, you click on create method here
and then we choose the method type.
So it could be any of these HTTP verbs
but we're going to do a GET just to get a page.
And then you have to choose the integration type.
So you can see we have five options.
We have Lambda function, HTTP, Mock, AWS service
and VPC link.
And the one we'll be testing is Lambda function.
But I want to show you that we can also integrate
with any service in any region.
So we choose a region and then we choose a service.
And what it does that you can expose
some of your AWS services
as an API through API Gateway.
So we're going to keep things simple
and use Lambda functions in this one.
And so we need to choose a Lambda function
but for this of course we need to create it.
So let's go in Lambda and create our function
that is going to react to this API gateway.
So create a function and I call this one
api-gateway-route-gets.
And this is perfect.
And then the framework I'll use at the runtime
is going to be Python 3.11
but whatever Python 3 or Python should work.
So this is perfect.
Let's go and create this function.
And while this is creating,
I wanna show you the code we're going to use.
So I am in my code, in my folder
and there's lambda-code.py.
And this is the entire code we're going to copy to Lambda.
And so the idea is that this is a very simple
in the function which responds to an event
with some context and says, "Hey,
the body's going to be hello from Lambda.
It's going to be returned as the body."
The status code is 200.
And then the headers is Content-Type application/json,
to let our web browser know
that we get back a JSON response.
So I'm going to copy this entire code.
Scroll down and paste it here.
So we're going to deploy this function.
So I'm going to click on Deploy to deploy this function,
and we can also test it.
So for example, I can create a test event called DemoTest.
And then we just send this event, we save it
and then we click on Test.
And as you can see, the result is hello from Lambda
with status code 200.
So everything is working fine right now and this is perfect.
And what I'm going to do now is to integrate,
this Lambda function to my API gateway.
So back in here, I'm going to copy the function ARN,
go to my API gateway, and then just click and paste the ARN.
Perfect.
So now we have the Lambda function integrated
and because we want to see the full requests being passed
to Lambda and being sent back from Lambda,
you're going to take Lambda proxy integration.
Now for timeout, as you can see,
even though a Lambda function can have a long timeout,
for example, five minutes or 15 minutes,
API Gateway has a limited timeout
and the default is 29 seconds.
You can customize it and have it less than 29 seconds
but the default timeout is 29 seconds regardless
of how long your Lambda function takes to execute.
So let's create this method
and this is going to automatically grant API gateway,
the right to invoke our Lambda function.
So if I go back here and refresh this page,
as you can see now our API gateway
can invoke our Lambda function
and we can verify this by going into the configuration
and then permissions.
And if we have a look at the resource-based
policy statement, this one, and we click on View policy,
it turns out that my API gateway
is allowed to invoke my Lambda function
if the source API is the one from my API gateway
being route GET.
So this is the stuff that happens behind the scenes on AWS
to allow the API gateway to invoke our Lambda function.
So we know that everything is done
from a security perspective.
So now we can have a look at our API gateway.
So the client for this one method sends a request
and we can have a look at the request itself here.
So all the settings are here, it's done integration
with Lambda, and so it's a Lambda type of integration
with proxy enabled.
Then the Lambda itself is this function.
We can click on it and get back to our function.
Then the response is proxy integration.
That means that it will, the API gateway will parse
what is being sent by the Lambda and interpret it.
And then the method response is what we have here.
We could modify it if you wanted to,
but we're looking for application/json.
So let's test out this API.
So for this on the bottom right there is a test
and you can specify some query strings or some headers
but we don't specify anything.
Just click on Test.
And the test is, hey,
the response body is hello from Lambda.
So you can see from the API gateway, the status is 200.
That comes right from our code right here
which says status is 200.
We also have the response body, hello from Lambda, again,
was defined in our code right here,
body equals json.dumps.
And then hello from Lambda.
And finally the content type is JSON,
and that is retrieved as part of the response headers
being content type JSON.
On top of it from the test,
we can have a look at the execution log
from the API gateway, which is really nice,
which is also when you wanna debug and see what's happening.
A very nice way of doing so.
So we have done our first execution
of an API gateway on top of a Lambda function.
So now let's actually debug this
and see what is being sent to our Lambda function.
So I'm going to do print event,
and then I'm going to deploy this,
and we are going to invoke now our Lambda function again
from our API gateway.
So we're going to run a new test,
which still says hello from Lambda, but this time
we are printing the events.
So if we go to the CloudWatch logs
we should be able to find it.
So let's go into monitoring
and then look at CloudWatch logs.
We're going to find the latest log stream, this one.
And here we have our log.
And we can see here that this was the printed event
that was received from API Gateway.
So some information you have in here, for example,
the resource which is slash, the path slash,
the method which is GET, and then you get headers
and then you get query string parameters and so on.
So a lot of information is passed on
by the API gateway to our Lambda function.
And our Lambda function can use this information
to forge a response and send it back to the API gateway.
So now we can go ahead and actually create a new resource.
So this time we're going to have the resource by doing this
and the resource name is going to be houses.
So let's create this resource.
And now we have the /houses path that I just opened.
And in /houses, I'm going to create a method.
It's going to be a GET again for Lambda function
of proxy integration.
And I need to create my Lambda function.
So let's do this quickly, I'm going to copy this
and then create a function.
And it's not root yet, it's houses yet now.
The runtime is still going to be Python.
And let's create this function.
Yet again, I'm going to just copy this code.
And so instead of hello from Lambda,
we're going to change the message to be hello from,
and then something with houses.
So my function is now created.
We're going to copy this
and it's going to be hello from my pretty house.
Okay, we're going to deploy this.
So now we have deployed the function.
I'm going to copy the function ARN
and paste it in here.
And create this method.
And so now we have /houses that has the GET method.
I can test this.
So let's test it and click on Test.
And as you can see, I get a 200 hello from my pretty house.
And so far it's pretty cool.
We have the root, GET and we have the houses, GET,
which invoke two different Lambda functions.
But we want to be able to access this from a web browser,
not just testing it from the API Gateway UI.
So let's click on Deploy API, and we need to select a stage.
So it's going to be a new stage, and the name is dev,
we'll have a look at it later.
Let's deploy this.
And now that we've deployed this API, there's an invoke URL.
So I'm going to copy this URL
and then I'm going to paste it in my web browser.
And as you can see when I go to /dev,
it says hello from Lambda.
So this is just Firefox doing a pretty print
but you get hello from Lambda.
And if I go to /houses
then I get hello from my pretty house.
So this API has two Lambda functions replying to me.
And if I do something wrong, if I do /wrong
then I'm getting error message
such as message missing authentication token.
So here we go.
We have deployed our API to API Gateway
and this is pretty cool
because, well, we have two Lambda functions
behind the scenes actually replying to it.
And that's it for our basics role on API Gateway.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.