Now let's learn
about the AWS Step Functions.
So, Step Functions is a way for you
to build a serverless visual workflow
to perform orchestration,
and it's usually of your Lambda functions.
So you would design a graph,
and you would say at each step of the graph,
in case of success or failure, what goes on next?
And this is really cool,
because you can start really having some complex workflows
within AWS.
So Step Functions have some internal features,
such as sequencing, parallel functions, conditions,
timeouts, error handling, and so much.
And it doesn't just do Lambda functions.
It is actually integrate with EC2 instances, ECS tasks,
On-premises servers, the API Gateway,
the SQS queues, [00:00:47 NMADB],
and actually a lot of AWS services.
Also, it is possible for you
within the Step Function workflow
to implement a human approval feature.
For example, a workflow goes up to some points,
and you say, okay, a human will have a look at the results.
And if the human says "Yes," then please go on.
If "No," then fail.
This is something that's possible
thanks to the Step Functions.
So the use cases of Step Functions are manifold,
but, like, we can have, for example, the order fulfillment.
We can have data processing, web applications,
or any kind of workflow that is complex
to describe and that would require some sort
of graph for you to visualize it, okay?
So that's it for this little intro.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.