So now let's have a look
at IAM policies in depth.
So first of all, let's go into users.
And as you can see, the user Stephane
is part of the admin group,
and therefore, has administrator access permissions to AWS.
That means that if I use my user Stephane
to go into the IAM console, so now I'm using my user,
and then I go to the left-hand side and click on users,
as you can see, I can see my user Stephane,
which is right here.
So my user Stephane has permission to do anything
because it's an administrator.
But what I'm going to do is that I'm going to the groups
of admins and then I'm going to remove my user Stephane
from that group.
So by removing the user, which I've done right now,
then Stephane loses its permissions on the right-hand side.
How do we make sure of this?
Well, let's refresh this page.
And as you can see, now I see zero users
and I get an access denied and it said
that I don't have the permission to do iamListUsers.
And so therefore, because I removed my Stephane user
from the admin group, then I've lost permissions to look
at users on the right-hand side.
So let's try to fix this.
So let's go into IAM
and we're gonna go under users, find Stephane in here.
And right now, as you can see,
Stephane has zero permission policies
but let's add permissions.
So we can add permissions directly
or create an inline policy.
So let's add permissions, and this is going to be easier.
And so again, we could add the user back to a group.
That's not what we want.
Or we could attach policies directly to my user.
And so the policy I'm going to attach is going
to be IAMReadOnlyAccess.
So this will allow my user Stephane
to read anything on IAM, which is what we want.
So let's add this permission
and now this policy has been added.
So back in here, let's refresh this page.
And as you can see now, I can finally do my API call again
and look at the Stephane user in my users category.
So I can view users, I can view user groups, such as admin
but can I create a group?
Let's try to create the developer group
and then create this group.
And as you can see, I cannot create it
because I'm not allowed to actually create a group.
I'm only given the read-only access on IAM.
And so therefore, because I have read-only access,
I cannot create groups.
So this shows you that you can only permission users
for what they're supposed to do.
And of course, if I wanted to give access to create groups
on the right-hand side,
I will need to attach a bigger permission sets,
such as the IAM full access.
So next, let's do something.
So next, I'm going to go into the left-hand side
under user groups, and I'm going to create a group.
So this group is going to be called developers.
And then I'm going to add the user Stephane in this group
and I'm going to attach whatever policy I can find,
for example, AlexaForBusiness
but it doesn't really matter.
Just attach the first policy you can
and let's create this group.
Okay, so this has been added.
And finally, let's go into the admin group.
And again, we're going to add users
and re-add Stephane into this group.
So now if we go back to the Stephane user, so let's go
into IAM and look at the users and look at Stephane,
I'm going to shut down this message on right-hand side.
So if we look at Stephane as the user, as we can see,
we have three permission policies attached to my user.
We have the administrator access that has been inherited
from the group admin.
We have this AlexaForBusiness managed policy
that has been attached via the group developers.
And finally, IAMReadOnlyAccess
that has been attached directly.
And so as you can see,
I inherited different permissions based
on how it's been attached.
So now let's look at policies in detail.
So on the left-hand side, let's look at policies.
And first, let's have a look
at this AdministratorAccess policy.
So if we look at it, it's the permission
that gave us administrator access to everything.
And if you look at the permissions defined
in this policy as a summary, as you can see,
this allows all the services in AWS.
And this number can change over time.
It doesn't matter.
The course will be up to date.
So all these services, for example, App Mesh
or Alexa for Business or Amplify, they all have full access.
So how is this permission defined?
Well, if you click on JSON,
this is the JSON form of this policy, and we can see
that here we have allow Action, star and resource, star.
So star in AWS means anything.
So it means we allow any action on any resource.
And of course, allowing any action
on any resource is exactly the same thing
as giving administrator access to someone.
So this is how it's been defined.
If we have a look at another policy, for example,
the IAMReadOnlyAccess that we saw from before.
So if we look at it, we see
that IAM is authorized with Full: List and Limited: Read.
And if I click on it, you can actually have a look
at all the API calls that has been allowed
as part of this policy, which is very handy.
But if we look at how this has been actually defined,
let's click on JSON.
And here we have the JSON document that shows
how this has been defined.
So the effect is allow, and then we list out the API calls
that are being allowed.
So we have this one, this one, and then we have Get*.
So when you have Get*, it says that anything that starts
with Get and then has something after is authorized.
For example, get users or get groups.
Same for list.
So we have a List*.
So list users or list groups.
So by using a star,
we encompass and group many API calls together.
So all this is allowed on Resource*.
And so therefore, that summarizes
what the read-only IAM access policy is made of.
So this is very handy.
You can also create your own policy.
So let's create a policy
and we have a visual editor or a JSON editor.
So if you have JSON, you can just very simply edit this
and create your JSON document with this builder,
which is very handy.
Or you can use the visual editor.
And for example, let's say IAM,
we wanna create stuff for IAM.
And what action do we wanna authorize?
Well, we want to authorize ListUsers.
So we're going to take this and GetUser.
So just two API calls.
And as we can see, we have selected one out of 38 in list
and one out of 32 in read.
And then what do we want to authorize this on?
So on all resources or only specific resources?
So this is a very simple one
but as you can see, this builder is very handy.
And when you click on next,
you can have a look and say MyIAMPermissions.
And then we create this policy.
And if we have a look at the policy we created,
we can have a look at the corresponding JSON
and see that indeed through the visual editor,
we allowed iam:ListUsers and iam:getUser on Resource*.
And then this policy, we can attach to groups
or to users and so on.
So this is how you manage permissions in AWS.
So now to just wrap up this hands-on,
let's go to user groups
and we're going to delete the developers group
because we don't need it.
And then I'm going to go into my Stephane user
and I'm going to just remove this IAMReadOnlyAccess
that had attached directly.
So now Stephane only belongs to the group admin
and it has administrator access.
So of course, if I go back
to my IAM console in here and I just look at users,
as you can see, yes, everything is showing fine.
So it is working correctly.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.