Okay.
So I would like to talk to you about an alternative
to using the terminal to issue commands against AWS.
And this is using cloud shell.
So cloud shell is this icon right here on the top
right corner of your screen.
And if you don't see it, just make sure you check
out the clutch shell availability regions
because it's not available everywhere.
And so if you go to the clash of FAC, you can see
that there are some regions that's not available.
So let's have a look right now with the regions.
Here we go. Question three.
Right now that's, I'm recording.
It's only available in one of these regions.
So by the way, I would recommend if you want to follow
along to just use one of these regions, then
so we can use cloud shell, but if you don't use cloud shell
in this hands-on, that is completely fine.
If the terminal was working for you, do not worry.
You're good to go.
Okay. So we have cloud shell in here and within cloud shell
you could take a minute maybe to launch your environment.
You can issue commands.
For example, you can issue the AWS commands.
So as you can see is installed, if I do
either of us management is version, as we can see
I'm on version two.one right now using cloud shell.
So cloud shell is basically a terminal in the cloud of AWS.
That's free to use.
Okay. So the cool thing about cloud shell is
that whenever you are using the CLI, so for example
it was am list users.
This is going to return for you an API call
as if the credentials being used, where the credentials
of the accounts of you using the cloud right now
which is why the API calls are working.
And by default, you can specify any kind
of region you want to do.
The API call using the management is region arguments, but
in cloud shell, the default region is going to
be the region you're currently in
logged in right now in cloud shell.
So this is another thing that's good to know.
Okay. Other things that you should know
about cloud shell is that you have a full repository.
So for example, right now, as we can see
we have zero files within cloud shell.
But if you just do
echo
tests
into demo dot TXT, this is going to create a text
file that contains the word texts tests.
And so it turns out that
if you happen to restart your cloud shell
then this file will stick.
So all the files you are creating
within your cultural environment, for example
this demo that's TXT are going to stay.
And the other cool thing you can do
about cloud shell is that you can configure it.
So you can say what font size you want, smallest
medium and large.
And so on the tech, the theme you want, so light or dark
if he wants safe based or nuts.
So resist like a bigger cloud shell for me right now.
And also you have the possibility to download
and upload files.
So for example, if I want you to get the full path
to my file, so did this demo let's six.
I can just copy it right now.
Action and download foul, and then do demo dot TXT.
And this will go ahead and download the file for me.
And alternatively, you could upload your own files
into your cultural environments.
So I want to show you these handy options
because for me, they are lifesavers.
Okay.
And finally, if you wanted more tabs into this environment
you could have a new tab.
You can split into column example, and there you go.
You have two terminals
into cloud shell connected at the same time.
So really that once show you the power
of cloud shell in this hands-on again, you're doing it.
You know, all the commands that data just wants to show you.
If you're a power user, then you can do these commands
and how they would work with cloud shell.
So the bottom line for this lecture again, is number one
cloud shell is only available in some regions.
So maybe try to choose one
of the regions where cloud shell is available.
If you want to use it, if you don't want to use cloud shell
or cloud shell is not working for you.
This is completely fine.
As long as you use the terminal, the way we configured it
from before, this will work just fine.
And you'll be fine in the course to either use cloud shell
or your terminal to perform the commands
with the CLA against AWS.
Okay. And also remember that I really like the upload
and download feature of cloud shell
choose to upload files and download files from it.
Okay. So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.