So here are some general guidelines
on IAM and best practices, 'cause I don't want you
if you go to use AWS to make some mistakes.
So do not use a root account
except when you set up your AWS account.
So by now you should have two accounts, a root account
and your own personal accounts.
And remember, one AWS user is equal to one physical user.
So if a friend of yours wants to use AWS,
do not give them your credentials,
instead, create another user for them.
You can assign user to groups
and assign permission to groups to make sure
that security is managed at the group level
and should create a strong password policy.
Also, if you can use and enforce the use
of multi-factor authentication or MFA to really guarantee
that your account is going to be safe or safer from hackers.
Then you should create and use roles whenever
you're giving permissions to AWS services,
and that includes easy two instances
which are virtual servers.
If you were to use AWS programmatically or using the CLI,
so the CLI or some SDK, you must generate access keys,
and these access keys are just like passwords,
they're very secret.
So just keep them for yourself.
To edit the permissions of your account,
you can use the IAM credentials reports
or the IAM Access advisor feature.
Finally, never, ever, ever share your IAM users
and access keys, I am very serious about it.
So that's it,
we are nearing the end of this section.
You know everything about IAM.
I will see you in the next lecture.