So here is a summary for IAM.
We've seen IAM users and they should be mapped
to an actual physical user within your company.
And this user will have a password for the AWS console.
Now we can group these users into groups
and therefore users only.
We can attach policies
or share JSON documents that outline the permission
for users or groups.
And we can also create roles
and these roles will be identities, but this time
for maybe EC2 instances or other AWS services.
We assume that for security
we can enable multi-factor authentication so MFA
and also set a password policy for our users.
We can use the CLI to manage your services
using the command line
or the SDK to manage your AWS services,
using a programming language.
Finally, we can create access keys to access AWS
using the CLI or the SDK.
And finally, we can audit our IAM usage
by creating an IAM credentials report
and also using the IAM access advisor service.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.