Okay, so let's see how far we've learned
in this course,
and we're going to check the exam certification page
to have a look at the exam guide.
So here I am
on the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate page.
And if you scroll down,
you can have a look at the exam guide
as well as the sample question.
So let's go over the exam guide.
So this is a long document at 17 pages
and it represents what you should be knowing
going into the exam.
So we're going to skim through this document
and verify that we know a lot,
and then I will do a few precisions,
especially when we go into this right here,
which is the services covered
which are at the very bottom, the appendix.
And this is concept that might be covered on the exam, okay?
So all these services here
will not necessarily be at the exam
and I've created the course in a way that's what I teach
I know is at the exam, okay?
So if you see something here
but I don't teach it in the course,
do not freak out.
If I hear from students that it is indeed at the exam,
then I will include lecture on it, okay?
This is just technology that might be covered at the exam.
Okay, so let's go back up.
So you're going to have one year of hands-on experience
to do the exam,
but after doing this course
you will have enough experience.
So the exam will be of two types of question.
You have the multi-choice
where one correct responses and three incorrect responses,
and multi response
when you have two or more correct responses out of five.
And you must answer a question.
So there's no penalty for guessing.
You must answer every question,
because if you answer incorrect or if you don't answer,
you will not get points removed from your score, okay?
So answer all the questions.
There are 15 unscored questions that you do not know about
and they do not affect your score.
This is so that AWS can test new questions over time
and make sure they're good
and make sure people answer them correctly or not,
but you don't know about them, okay?
So you're actually scored on 50 questions out of 65,
but 15 of them you don't know about.
Okay.
So your exam score is between 100 and 1000,
and the minimum passing score is 720.
Next you should have the content outlines.
So this is the domains at the exam.
So you have four domains you're being tested on.
And when you receive the final results,
it will tell you on each domain
if you were passing or not passing.
And it doesn't tell you your score per domain.
It will never tell you
if you're right or wrong on the question,
it will just tell you your total score,
as well as your domain level pass or not pass.
So 30% of the exam is on designing secure architecture.
So security is a big thing.
26% is resilient architecture.
So making sure we know about high availability and so on.
24% is high performance.
So how do we leverage the best service for the best use case
with the best features and the best options?
And finally cost-optimized architecture is at 20%.
How do we save on cost in the cloud?
Okay.
So here you can really have a look at each domain
and each knowledge of.
So I'm not going to read everything out to you,
that would be extremely boring, okay?
But I've designed this course in reading all the domains
and all the tasks and all the skills.
So really you should be good to go.
If there is something that you don't know
or don't feel confident about,
try to go back to the course,
or even better,
now you should know enough
to start looking into the AWS documentation
and really get the right information you need
to understand some services, okay?
So you have the four domains.
I invite you to read them in your own time,
otherwise that would be a very horrible video.
And then the appendix of services
that you can consider can appear at the exam
or might appear at the exam,
but you can hopefully rely on me
and say that, "I know what goes at the exam.
I've passed it."
People have passed it
and I receive feedback all the time.
And so what I cover in the course should be enough.
And if I don't,
if you have something that is not covered in the course,
just please let me know and I will edit the course
as soon as possible.
But it's usually one question out of 65.
So it doesn't impact your ability to pass the exam.
I want you to have a very high score.
Okay.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.