All right, so just a few exam tips,
just to make sure that you have the maximum chances
to pass your exam.
Number one, practice makes perfect.
So if you're new to AWS, maybe you're overwhelmed
by this course, so take a bit of AWS practice
thanks to this course.
And don't rush to go to the exam.
Take your time, okay?
This is not a race, this is a challenge to you
to know that you know AWS, okay?
This exam recommends that you have one or more years
of hands-on experience on the AWS.
You can't fake that.
Now, you should be able to answer all the exam questions,
but hands-on experience is really how I learned AWS,
and this is how you should learn AWS, too.
Practice makes perfect, so give it a go.
Now, if you feel overwhelmed by this course
because you learned a lot of knowledge right now,
go through it one more time.
It is fine to take your time, okay?
There is so much new knowledge, even me,
I need to go back to it sometimes, so take your time.
Now when you do have questions, proceed by elimination.
So most questions are going to be scenario based,
they're going to be a bit long,
giving you hints and stuff.
And so for all the questions, first rule out answers
that you know for sure are going to be wrong.
This is really good way for you to maybe come back to
one or two answers, and then just know which
one is right, right away, okay?
So understand which one makes the most sense, okay?
Sometimes they are not that complicated,
so there is very few trick questions.
Maybe in the scenario they will try to lead you
into thinking something else because there will be
EBS, ASG, SSM, all these kind of technologies.
But there are very few trick questions,
and don't overthink your answers, okay?
If an answer seems feasible, but it's too complicated,
it's probably wrong.
So think about it, think about it real hard.
And if you don't know the answer of a question right away,
answer it, and then you can flag it for review later
using your little flag feature in the exam.
And so you can come back to it later,
and maybe you'll have the response then
because you have time to think about it.
I also recommend that you skim through
some AWS white papers.
And so you can read them, there's three of them
that I recommend.
Architecting for the Cloud: AWS Best Practices,
AWS Well-Architected Framework, and then finally,
AWS Disaster Recovery, and here's the link
because this one may be tough to find.
So overall I think we've explored the most important
concept in this course, but if you are interested
into these white papers, then it's never bad to look at them
or read them.
Maybe it will help you reinforce your learnings on AWS
and make you understand the course a little bit better.
Also, if you don't know a service very well,
or you have doubts, look at the service FAQ.
This is where most of the questions on the exam will be.
FAQ stands for frequently asked questions.
For example, if you look at VPC, this will be the URL,
amazon.com/vpc/faqs.
FAQs, as I said, cover a lot of questions that are going
to be asked on the exam, and it's really helpful
to look at it just to make sure that you understand
a service really, really well.
And finally, I think if you are really serious about AWS,
you need to get into the AWS community.
So do participate in this course,
answer other peoples' Q and A, help other.
Review questions that are asked by other people
just to make that you may be having the same questions,
and maybe you have the same doubts.
Maybe the answers will help you clear out your doubts.
And then do the practice test in this section.
You have to do it just to make sure you're ready.
Finally, there's some forums online, there's online blogs,
and there's even local meetups in pretty much every city
in the world to discuss with other AWS engineers.
And then if you're really into AWS,
you can also watch the re-invent videos.
This is Amazon's conference on YouTube,
and they're really, really great to get started.
So that's it for my tips.
I hope you're excited to pass the exam,
and I will see you in the next lecture.