So a common question I get
is how will the exam work?
So first you register online, as I showed you.
Then you pay $150 to sign up for the exam.
Then you provide one identity document on the day.
So it could be your ID, your passport,
and all the details are in the email
that will be sent to you after you register for the exam.
You cannot take any notes.
You cannot use a pen.
You cannot speak.
And if you're at home, you will have to scan your room
to make sure it's fully empty.
Then we have 65 questions that will be asked in 130 minutes.
And in case you're not sure about a specific question,
you can use the flag feature
to optionally mark the question with the flag.
And at the end
when you can review all the questions and answer,
you can directly go back to the ones where you put a flag
to maybe answer it in a better way or verify your answer.
Once you submit the exam,
you cannot change any of your responses.
And to pass,
you will need a score of at least 720 out of 1000
and you will know within five days
if you passed or failed your exam.
Most of the time, it's going to be less than five days
but it's not immediate.
You will know the overall score as well, a few days later.
So you'll receive an email notification
telling you your score
to be downloaded on the certification website.
You will never know which answers were right or wrong.
This is so that people don't cheat.
And if you fail, you can take the exam again 14 days later.
So that's it, I wish you good luck for your exam
but I know you've prepared very hard.
Make sure to practice, practice, practice,
and revisit the lectures in this course
where you have some doubts.
That's it, I will see you in the next lecture.