Next, we have S3 Storage Lens, which is a service
to help you understand, analyze, and optimize
storage across your entire AWS Organization.
With this, you're going to discover anomalies,
identify cost efficiencies,
and you're going to apply protection
best practices across your entire AWS Organization.
You're going to get 30-day usage and activity metrics.
You can aggregate the data at the organization
level or for specific accounts, regions,
buckets, or even prefixes.
You can create your own dashboard or use
a default dashboard provided by the Storage Lens service.
And finally, all these metrics,
all these reports can be exported into an
S3 bucket in the CSV or Parquet format.
So to summarize, Storage Lens will take all
these things into account, organization,
accounts, region, buckets.
Then you aggregate all this data into a report,
which is going to help you with your analysis.
And then finally, this can be sent for summary insights,
data protection, cost efficiency, which allows you
to optimize your usage of Amazon S3.
So when you use the S3 Storage Lens service,
you have a default dashboard
and the dashboard gives you summarized insights
and trends for both the free and the advanced metrics.
This default dashboard will show data across multiple
regions and across multiple accounts.
So you don't have to do anything special just
to set up the filters.
It is pre-configured by Amazon S3.
You cannot delete the default dashboard,
but you can disable it, if you wanted to.
So in this UI right here, you would select
the region you want, the accounts you want,
the buckets you want, storage classes, and so on.
And this is a centralized configuration.
And then once you have that,
the dashboard right here gives you information
such as, for example, the total storage,
the objects count, the average object size,
the number of buckets you have, accounts,
and you can get detailed per accounts,
or per region.
So let's have a look at what kind
of metrics are available into Storage Lens,
because this will help you understand if Storage Lens
is a service you should be choosing for the exam.
So you have summary metrics which give you general
insights about your S3 storage.
For example, storage bytes to know the size
of your storage and object counts to know
how many objects you have in your storage.
So use cases for this is to identify, for example,
the fastest-growing or not used bucket and prefixes,
because if the storage bytes remains the same,
that means that no new objects have been added
or same for object counts.
Then you have cost optimization metrics
and they provide you insights to manage
and optimize your storage cost.
So they give you an information about the non-current
version storage bytes, meaning how many version objects
that are not current,
how much space they're actually taking,
or incomplete multi-part upload storage bytes.
You know, if for example,
you've had some incomplete uploads,
how much space they take
in your bucket and you can clean it.
So the use cases will be, for example,
to see which buckets have failed multi-part uploads,
or which objects could be transitioned
to lower-cost storage classes.
You have data protection metrics to provide insights
for data protection features.
So here we have versioning enabled bucket counts
to make sure that all your buckets have been
enabled with versioning and so on.
MFA, delete enabled bucket counts.
SSCKMS enable bucket counts, cross replication
region rules, counts, and so on.
So the use cases are, for example, to identify
the buckets which are not following your data
protection best practices.
You have access management metrics to provide
insights for S3 bucket ownership.
So here's the name of the metric
and the use cases will be to identify which object
ownership settings your buckets currently use.
You have event metrics to get insights
for S3 event notifications
and to know how many buckets have the S3 event
notifications configured.
You have performance metrics
to get insights into S3 transfer acceleration
and see how many buckets have
S3 transfer acceleration enabled.
And you have activity metrics such
as information about all requests, get requests,
put requests, the number of bytes downloaded and so on.
And finally, metrics around the HTTP status code
such as 200OK, 403 Forbidden, et cetera, et cetera,
to understand the type of usage
your buckets are getting.
Now, you have different kinds of metrics
in two Storage Lens, you have the free
and the paid metrics.
So the metrics selection can be done in the UI as well.
But just as a summary,
while the three metrics are automatically available
to all customers, and it contains around 28 usage metrics,
and the data is available for queries for 14 days,
whereas for advanced metrics and recommendations,
you get additional paid metrics and features
such as the activity, the advanced cost optimization,
the advanced data protection and status codes.
And then you get also these metrics being
published to CloudWatch.
So you can access them without any additional charges.
And then you can collect metrics at the prefix
level within your S3 buckets.
And finally, the data when you pay,
is available for 15 months.
So that's it for S3 Storage Lens.
It's a very helpful service.
You have to remember the difference
between free and paid.
You have to remember that the default dashboard
has data across multiple accounts and multiple regions.
And of course, the fact that Storage Lens
covers your object storage, the fact that you can
count how many objects are encrypted and so on.
So let's say for this lecture, I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.