Okay, so let's talk about
a little bit of networking
because I want you to understand how it works
to block an IP address if you want it to in AWS.
So say for example, we have the architecture
of an EC2 instance in a public subnet
and a client wants to access it.
So the first line of defense in your public subnet
is going to be your Network ACL, or NACL.
And with it you can very cheaply and very simply
explicitly write, deny, or allow rules
which will allow or block the client if you need to.
But say you have a default Network ACL, for example,
and everything is allowed through,
your second line of defense
is going to be your Security Group.
And here you have no deny rules,
but you can only have allow rules,
so if you know in advance the IP of your clients,
you can specifically only allow
your clients to get to your EC2 instance.
If the traffic gets all the way through
to your EC2 instance,
it is possible for you to optionally run a firewall software
on your EC2 instance,
which is going to inspect all the packets getting to it.
And here you have a lot more control
over everything, of course,
because this is customized solutions, not AWS dependent,
but because you have firewall software running
on your EC2 instance,
there will be a CPU cost on your instance.
It can slow it down, for example.
So hopefully that makes sense
for this first line of defense.
Okay, so now let's consider this situation
in which we have a Network ACL, a Application Load Balancer,
and an EC2 instance.
So here what's happening is that we have the ability
to have the client connect directly
into an Application Load Balancer
that will be sitting in the public subnet.
And that Application Load Balancer
will be diverting traffic to the EC2 instance.
That means your EC2 instance can live in a private subnet
and it's going to be better for your security
of your application, of course.
And so your EC2 instance has a private IP,
and so you need to have a security group
around the EC2 instance that will allow only connections
from your Application Load Balancer.
We've seen this before.
So what's happening is that the Application Load Balancer
that sits in the public subnet
is doing a connection termination.
That means that the client connects to the ALB
and the ALB will connect to the EC2 instance.
That also means that you now have the ability
to manage security at the Application Load Balancer level
with the security group, or with some extra features
within the Application Load Balancer.
And if you need to, you can always, as well,
leverage the Network ACL to do allow or deny rules
at the public subnet level.
So all of this shouldn't be new
and should be mastered by now.
And the situation is very similar
if you are to use a Network Load Balancer
that will have a security group
that's connected to EC2 instances, okay?
So same for ALB and NLB in terms of security.
Now we can explore security features
around the application balancer.
So you can pair it with WAF,
the Web Application Firewall from AWS.
And this allows you, for example,
to set IP address filtering from within WAF.
So obviously, now this has a cost
because you have a firewall set up
at the Application Load Balancer level,
but WAF has more than just the IP address filtering feature.
It has a lot more and you will get a lot of control
and defenses for your infrastructure
if you expose directly your Application Load Balancer.
Another place where you can apply AWS WAF
is around CloudFronts.
So CloudFronts can be set up, for example,
on a public infrastructure, for example,
using an Application Load Balancer in public mode.
And so what's happening is that CloudFront
will send traffic directly from all the edge locations
with the public IPs of them
directly into your Application Load Balancer.
Here your Network ACL is not helpful
to filter traffic from the clients
because, well, the client
does not reach the traffic of AWS, okay?
CloudFront does.
And so therefore you must set up security at the ALB level
with your Security Group
so that you allow all the CloudFront public IPs
into your infrastructure only.
Also, you have the ability, for example,
if a client was coming from a specific country
and was attacking your infrastructure,
you could use the Geo Restriction feature
to block that specific country
and that's one line of defense.
Another line of defense, is again to use WAF
and all its features
to have a firewall at the CloudFront level
and, for example, implement IP address filtering.
So now hopefully that makes sense into
how network security is working.
This kind of diagrams hopefully show you the path
that the network traffic is taking
and so why it makes sense to apply some rules at some level.
And if you have any issue
understanding what are the specific rules,
it's always very helpful to draw what the network is doing.
And then it will make a lot of sense into
how to define the rules along the way.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.