Okay, so now let's view an advanced use case
that comes up a lot in the exam, which is around Hybrid DNS.
So we have our region and there is the Route 53 resolver.
And by default, this resolver is going
to automatically answer DNS queries
for local domain names for EC2 instances.
So for example, here's our VPC.
We have an EC2 instance.
There is this DNS name,
the Route 53 resolver knows how to reply to these queries.
So this is fine.
Any records in your private hosted zone as well
is going to be easy to answer to,
and records in public name servers,
for example, for a public hosted zone,
or any name server out there that is public on the internet.
Now, if you want to resolve DNS queries
between your VPC and other private networks,
your own networks that has other DNS resolvers,
then you're going to need a hybrid DNS.
So these networks can be PeeredVPC for example,
or it could be an on-premises network that is going
to be connected to our VPC
through Direct Connect or AWS VPN.
So for this, let me introduce you two concepts
that we're going to see with diagrams in the next slides.
So these are about resolver endpoints.
So there is two things.
There's an inbound endpoint and an outbound endpoint.
So inbound endpoints are allowing DNS resolvers
on your external networks to forward DNS queries
to your Route 53 resolver and answer these queries.
So these resolvers will help to resolve domain names
for the resources of AWS.
For example, your EC2 instances or records
that you create in your Route 53 private hosted zone.
So you get both answers for your internal systems,
and also for AWS private host zones,
and I will show you a diagram,
it will make a lot more sense very, very soon.
Now, your outbound endpoint is
to conditionally forward DNS queries
to your on-premises DNS resolvers.
And for this, we're going to create resolver rules
to forward them.
Now we associate these endpoints with one or more VPCs
within the same region,
and we create in two availability zones
for high availability.
Now each endpoint supports
about 10,000 queries per second, per IP address.
And if you need more, well, you create more IP addresses.
And these resolvers remove the need from before
where people have to run their own DNS resolvers
on AWS and link them to their resolvers on premises.
Now, these are managed resolver endpoints by AWS.
So let's have a look at a diagram,
it will make a lot more sense.
So let's take an example where we have an EC2 instance,
and lives in a VPC,
and we have a private hosted zone that we create,
for example, aws.private,
and we have also an on-premises data center
that has a server.
Now, if you look at the EC2 instance,
I gave it a CNAME of app.aws.private, okay?
This is a CNAME, which is linked maybe to its EC2 DNS,
or it could be an A record linked to its private IP.
It doesn't matter right?
Now what's happening is that the server
at web.onpremises.private wants to access this EC2 instance.
And so first, the on-premises data center and the AWS cloud
are going to be linked using a VPN connection,
or Direct Connect.
Okay?
Now we're going to have on-premises as well
as some DNS resolvers,
for obviously the zone of our on-premises data center.
So they're going to be for the zone onpremise.private.
Now, when the server will issue a DNS query
for app.aws.private
the DNS resolvers are going to say, hey, you know what?
I don't know these,
but what we're going to happen is that we're going
to create a resolver inbound endpoint,
and behind the scenes this resolver inbound endpoint
has two ENIs, again for high availability.
Now these ENIs are associated with private IP addresses.
So what's going to happen is that
within our DNS resolvers on premises,
we're going to say that for the domain name, aws.private,
we're going to forward to these two IPs.
Okay?
And what's going to happen is that now the DNS query
for app.aws.private matches this domain name
that was configured on-premises,
and therefore the DNS resolver is going to say,
hey, I know I should forward these queries
to a DNS server that has this information.
So it's going to forward them to these IPs.
Now the resolver inbound endpoint is linked
to the Route 53 resolver,
and then from the private hosted zone,
we're going to get our final lookup
and give us the final information for this query.
So this is what's called inbound endpoints
because requests coming from the exterior
and go inbound on AWS, so on-premises to AWS.
As you may expect, the outbound endpoints are quite similar,
but they go the other way.
So we have again, the same setup, okay?
But this time we want to be able to resolve the DNS names
of the on-premises data center.
So our EC2 instance is going to ask our Route 53 resolver,
Do you know about web.onprem.private?
And for this,
we're going to create a resolver outbound endpoint,
which has two different ENIs.
And we're going to create a forwarding rule,
which is saying, hey, for on-prem.private
here is the target IP, and this target IP corresponds
to the IP of my DNS resolver on-premises.
So the Route 53 resolver is going to send this
to this endpoint,
and the endpoint is going to forward the DNS query
into the on-premises DNS resolver.
And then we will have automatically the response
from the records stored in the DNS
of our on-premises data center.
Now to manage this outbound endpoint,
we need resolver rules.
So the outbound endpoint is going to set,
to have a set of rules, okay?
And it's going to explain how to forward DNS queries
on your network.
So there's conditional forwarding,
which are the forwarding rules.
So the idea is that we're going to say
for specific DNS queries in this domain,
please match all of it to a target IP address.
So you can say, for example.com or acme.example.com,
here is the target IP, or here are the target IPs
for these domains.
You can also override them with a system rule.
And this is to define overriding behavior,
which is saying, hey, for a whole subdomain,
do not use these forwarding rules.
This could be something you can create.
And then finally we have auto-defined system rules,
which is for domains that we know are resolved internally.
For example, domain names that are internal
to AWS or private hosted zones, for example
compute.amazonaws.com or EC2.internal.
Now in case of multiple rules matched,
the Route 53 resolver is going to choose
the most specific match,
in terms of how to choose which rule to apply.
Okay?
Finally, these resolver rules can be shared across accounts.
If you're using AWS resource access manager or RAM.
That means that you can share them across multiple accounts.
That means that you can manage them centrally
in one dedicated account for these resolver rules.
And then you can send DNS queries
from multiple VPC to the target IP defined in the rules.
So there are a way to have a central management
of your resolver rules in the central accounts.
Okay?
So this is it.
This is how you have a hybrid DNS on AWS.
Remember inbound endpoints and outbound endpoints
usually are used together to have in and out traffic
from your both DNS systems from AWS and on-premises,
and the exam will ask you about them for sure.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.