Okay, so this section
is about studying the white papers
and a few architecture documents that we can have,
and these are actually not strongly required for the exam,
but you absolutely need to know a little bit
about the Well-Architected Framework
and Disaster Recovery and a few other things.
So this section is going to cover just that.
So we'll see the Well-Architecture Framework whitepaper,
and I'll be honest, I'll try to make this
as less boring as I can,
but it's not very fascinating for some,
the Well-Architected Tool, which I think is awesome,
AWS Trusted Advisor,
some reference architecture resources,
and these are super-cool so don't miss that.
It's for the real world,
so these are to be links that we will need to use
as a real solutions architect,
and then finally, Disaster Recovery on AWS Whitepaper.
This one is a bit boring,
but it is super important going into the exam,
so we'll have to look at it,
and actually, you'll find this pretty interesting, I'm sure,
by the end of it.
All right, so let's get started.