So there is a framework
called the AWS Well-Architected Framework.
And I'm going to describe it to you.
This is a tool as well as a framework
that allows you to do good applications on AWS.
So it's quite a long read
and so I try to summarize it for you in a few slides.
So the idea is that with the well-architected framework
once you implement the best practices,
then you go to outcomes,
and I'll give you the main guidelines of it.
The first one is that to stop guessing your capacity need
instead use auto scaling groups and so on.
Test systems at production scale.
So with AWS, you can very quickly perform big test
big infrastructure, and then shut them down an hour later.
So there's no reason for you not to test
at production scale.
Also automate that allows you to make
architectural experimentation easier.
If you have a Cloud formation template
you can easily deploy it
in multiple environments to experiments.
You can also allow for evolutionary architectures.
So your architecture can show over time it can start with
for example, EC2 instances and a load bouncer
and evolve towards a more serverless architecture such as
API Gateway and Lambda.
So design based on these changing requirements and so on.
Also drive architecture using data.
So data is very important.
You have to move it around storage and so on.
And finally, improve through game days.
The idea is that you must try out your architecture
good production, give it a go and see how you can improve.
So you need to submit your application, for example
for flash sale days that put a lot of pressure
on your architecture.
So the architecture framework is six pillars.
The first one is operational excellence.
The second one is security.
The third one is reliability.
Fourth one, performance efficiency.
Fifth one, cost optimization.
And six one, sustainability.
So you have to know them all,
I mean, just the names, okay?
Not what they represent,
but the names are pretty explicit
and you can go on the website to learn more about them
but this is not the focus of this course.
And so these pillars are not something to balance
or trade off, they're actually a synergy.
For example, if you improve your operational excellence
you most likely will improve as well your cost optimization.
And if you are or more sustainable,
most likely you'll also be having
a higher performance efficiency and so on.
So to help you guide you through this framework
there is something called the AWS Well-Architected tool.
And it's a framework tool to review your architectures
against the six pillars I just defined.
And then you adapt architectural best practices.
So this is whether your looks like
and we'll see this in a second.
So how does it work?
Well, you select your workload
and then you answer questions.
You review your answers
against the six pillars that I just defined.
And then you obtain advice.
You get videos, documentation reports
and you see results in a dashboard.
So let's have a look to see how this tool works.
So here I am in the well-architected tool UI
and I'm going to define a workload.
So you can, for example, define a demo workload
and say this is your production application.
You can say, this is my prod application.
Okay, the review owner will be John@example.com.
We are in production and we are functioning
in two either of this regions that I will choose.
So this one and then US-West-2, perfect.
We can specify non-AWS regions, account IDs and so on.
And you can just specify a lot of information
around your infrastructure and architecture.
So next I'm going to apply lenses.
And these lenses are the kind of questions you apply
to your architecture.
So we'll apply the well-architected framework lens.
But you have the FTR lens, the serverless lens,
the SaaS lens and you can even create your custom lenses
if you wanted to.
But for now, we'll keep it simple
and just answer questions regarding
the well-architected framework.
So let's define the workload.
And once you have that, you need to start reviewing.
So we'll start reviewing and then we'll review
for the lens of the AWS Well-Architected Framework.
So in here I get some resources on the right hand side
that I can close.
And the idea is that
you're going to have a lot of questions on the six pillars,
for example, 11 questions on operational excellence
and then 10 questions on security, six on sustainability
and things can change over time, of course
but the idea is that you answer questions
and then you're gonna get recommendations.
So for example, how do you determine that
what your priorities are?
And we'll say, okay, we evaluate governance requirements
external customer needs and trade offs.
And then next, so answer one question.
And then how do you structure your organization?
Maybe I just have this answer and then next.
And so you can answer questions in the various pillars
and you should answer them all for all pillars,
but let's answer one as well
in performance efficiency, randomly and next.
So once you answer maybe three questions of course
they're a lot more, then you save and continue.
And then here, as you can see, we have three high risks.
So you can click on this lens right here
and then you're going to get the overview of this lens
as well as the risks.
So you can click on the risk itself
by going to improvement plan.
We see we have three high risk and zero medium risk
and so this one was a high risk
and here are the recommendations regarding this risk.
So I need to evaluate internal customer needs
evaluate threat landscape and so on.
And then if I click on it, I get the section
in the framework itself that tells me exactly
what I need to do.
So it's very important.
And then I will go back to answering more questions
and making sure that this is addressed.
And so this tool just gives you feedback.
And over time you can define milestones.
You can look at your improvement plans and so on.
And the idea is that once you are very confident
that this framework works for you
then your application is production ready
and your workload is compliant and well architected, okay?
So that's it for this tool.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.