So in this course, I really try
to make it a huge differentiator for you
to actually see very important architectural patterns.
To me, you can't do a solutions architect course
without seeing solution architecture.
So we've explored architectures around classic, you know,
for example, EC2, ELB, RDS, ElastiCache, et cetera.
And also, we've explored in-depth serverless,
more cloud native serverless architectures using S3, Lambda,
DynamoDB, CloudFront, API Gateway, et cetera, et cetera.
But you may be hungry for more architectures.
And so if you wanna see more architectures,
there's two links on the AWS website,
which I think are really awesome
and not many people know about it.
So hopefully, I raise awareness on these links
through this course.
The first one is this link, and the second one is this link.
So you know what?
We're going to visualize these links together
just to show you what they're about.
So here I am on the AWS Architecture Center,
and this is where you're going
to find reference architecture examples and diagrams.
So if you scroll down, you get access
to different links, such as, for example, a link
to the Well-Architected Framework.
But let's scroll down even more.
In here, we can browse the contents
with all the architecture diagrams.
So as you can see, we have over 2,000 of those.
So this is huge.
And therefore, on the left-hand side, you have some filters
to select whatever you want.
So for example, here, if I automate your DR solution
for relational databases, I click on it
and I get access to this in PDF form or HTML form.
So let's access it in PDF form,
and you get access to a lot of information.
And within that information,
you will find some architecture diagrams
and everything is explained,
which I think is tremendously good resources
as a solution architect.
So it's very detailed.
As you can see, we have CloudFormation templates
that functions, I mean, everything is there.
You also have, for example, WordPress architecture.
So if you type WordPress, you have best practices
of WordPress on AWS.
Again, let's open the PDF version and scroll down.
And here we go again.
We have some architecture diagrams
and we have an even bigger architecture diagram.
So everything is quite thorough
and there's a lot of text that really helps you to step up
as a solution architect.
The other one I really liked is the AWS Solutions Library.
So this is vetted solutions and guidance for businesses
and technical use cases.
And I really like it
because it provides you not only architecture diagrams,
but also CloudFormation templates
to actually implement things.
So here, let's look at this AWS solution
called Live Streaming on AWS.
And here, this is how to build
a highly available architecture
that delivers reliable, real-time viewing experience.
Okay, perfect, let's scroll down,
and we get some information
around the type of solution we have.
So we have one on S3 and one on AWS,
which use different kind of services,
where they support, what they don't support and so on.
And then the technical details.
So we have the first architecture, the second architecture,
so they're both here.
And we can actually get implementation guides
and we can actually launch it in the console.
So there is a CloudFormation template,
the source being here,
and the source code is also on GitHub, as you can see.
And these CloudFormation template allow you
to actually develop and deploy these kind of architectures.
So this is awesome
because you really do a huge steps forward
as a solution architect into deploying some
of these solutions.
So if you scroll down on the solutions library,
you will find that you can browse by industry based
on what industry it is or cross industry solutions
or by technology or by organization type.
And finally, again, you have a lot
of filters on the on the left-hand side.
So if I type, for example, serverless in here,
I can find the Serverless Image Handler, which shows me
how to handle some images, such as smart cropping,
constant moderation, na, na, na, and so on.
And this is the architecture.
Again, there's a CloudFormation template.
You have an implementation guide and so on.
So everything is super well described,
and I really like these two resources
because they really propel you into the real world
of solution architecture.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.