So now let's discuss
advanced concepts of Aurora
that you need to know going into the exam.
So let's talk about Replica Auto Scaling.
So let's say we have a client
and we have three Auroras instances right now.
So one will be writing through the Writer Endpoint
and the other two would be reading
through the Reader Endpoint, okay?
Now let's say that we are having many, many requests,
read requests on the Reader Endpoint,
and so therefore the Amazon Aurora databases
have an increased CPU usage.
In that case, we can set up replica auto-scaling
and what this will do is that it will add, obviously,
Amazon Aurora Replicas,
and then what will happen is that automatically
the Reader Endpoint is going to be extended
to cover these new replicas,
and therefore these new replicas
will start receiving some traffic
and the reads will be happening
in a more distributed fashion,
hopefully bringing down the overall CPU usage.
So this is replica auto scaling.
The second thing is Custom Endpoints.
So let's say we have the same setup,
but this time we have two different kinds of replicas.
As you can see, we have some db.r3.large
and some db.r5.2xlarge.
So some Read Replicas are bigger than others.
And the reason you would do this
is that you want to define
a subset of your Aurora instances as a Custom Endpoint.
So let's say we define a Custom Endpoint
on these two bigger Aurora instances.
The reason we would do so is for example,
that we know that these instances are more powerful
and therefore they're going to be better
to run analytical queries on these specific replicas.
So when you do so,
you have a Custom Endpoint that's defined.
And when you have a Custom Endpoint,
generally the Reader Endpoint itself
is not used after defining Custom Endpoints.
So it would not disappear, but you would not use it anymore.
And what you would do, like practically speaking,
is set up many Custom Endpoints
for many different kind of workloads,
therefore allowing you to query only a subset
of your Aurora Replicas.
Next we have Serverless.
So this is going to give you
automated database instantiation
and auto-scaling based on actual usage,
which is great when you have infrequent, intermittent,
or unpredictable workloads.
And therefore you don't need to do any capacity planning.
You're going to pay per the second of each Aurora instance
that is being spun up
and this can be a lot more cost effective.
So how does that work?
Well, the client is going to talk to a proxy fleet
that is managed by Aurora
and in the backend, many Aurora instances will be created
based on your workload in a serverless fashion,
so you don't have to provision capacity at all in advance.
Finally, we have Global Aurora.
So in case we have a Aurora Cross Region Read Replica
it's going to be very helpful for disaster recovery.
Very simple to put in place,
but you can also set up the Aurora Global Database,
which is the recommended way of doing things today.
In this case, you have one primary region
where all the reads and writes happen,
but you can set up up to five secondary read-only regions
where the replication lag should be less than one second
and up to 16 Read Replicas per secondary region.
And this will help you decrease latency
for the read workloads all over the world,
but also in case you have a database outage in one region.
Promoting another region for disaster recovery purposes
has an RTO, so recovery time objective,
of less than one minute.
So it takes us in one minute to recover into another region.
And here's a sentence you should look out for
from an exam perspective,
it takes on average less than one second
to replicate data across region
for your Aurora Global Database.
So this is something that if you see an exam,
it's a hint to use a Global Aurora.
So let's have a look.
We have us-east-1 as our PRIMARY region,
which is where the applications do the read and writes,
and then we'll set up a SECONDARY region in eu-west-1
where some replication happening
with a global database of Aurora,
and the applications that it can do read-only
from that setup.
But in case us-east-1 fails,
then we can fail over to eu-west-1
by promoting it as a read/write Aurora cluster.
Aurora also has an integration
with machine learning services within AWS.
So the idea with Aurora Machine Learning
is that you can have ML based predictions
to your applications via the SQL interface.
It's a simple, optimized and secure integration
between Aurora and different AWS machine learning services.
So two supported services are SageMaker,
which allows you to use
any kind of machine learning model in the backend
or Amazon Comprehend if you want to do sentiment analysis.
Now, you don't need to be an expert in SageMaker
or Comprehend, you just need to know that
Aurora has an integration with those.
So in order to use Aurora Machine Learning,
you don't need to have a machine learning experience.
And the use cases for this would be to have fraud detection,
ads targeting, sentiment analysis,
or product recommendation all within Aurora.
So to give you the architecture idea,
Aurora is going to be connected
to the machine learning services in AWS.
And your application can just run a very simple SQL query.
For example, what are the recommended products?
Aurora will send some data
into the machine learning services
such as, for example, the user's profile,
the shopping history, et cetera, et cetera.
And then the machine learning service
will return a prediction directly to Aurora.
For example, the user should buy a red shirt and blue pants,
and then Aurora can just return the query results
to the application all through
as a result of the SQL query, which is very handy.
So let's talk about Babelfish for Aurora PostgreSQL.
So this is a feature that allows
Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL to understand commands
that are targeted for Microsoft SQL Server
using the language T-SQL.
So let me explain so it's clearer.
If you have an application in your company today
that's using Microsoft SQL Server as a database,
then your applications are going to be written
and they're going to use a driver called
the SQL Server Client Driver,
which is going to send the commands
to your Microsoft SQL server using T-SQL.
But tomorrow you want to migrate to the cloud.
And so you migrate to Aurora PostgreSQL,
which is a scalable database in the cloud that you like,
but the engine is PostgreSQL.
So that means that your applications must be converted
to using the PostgreSQL driver
and the SQL language is a little bit different.
It's using the PL/pgSQL language.
So it's just a different language
you're going to remember the name of it.
So the idea is that how do we make sure
that our SQL Server application does not have to be
migrated to be rewritten?
For this we use Babelfish
and Babelfish is going to be enabled on Aurora PostgreSQL,
and this allows your application
to just communicate to Aurora PostgreSQL
using the T-SQL language through Babelfish.
And so there is almost nothing to change.
So that means that your SQL Server applications
can now work on Aurora PostgreSQL
with little to no code changes using the same driver.
And so this is very handy
because well, migrations are super easy.
Now to do the migration to use something called,
and we'll see this later on this course,
something called AWS SCT and DMS to migrate from,
for example, SQL Server to Aurora PostgreSQL.
But Babelfish is here to do the translation
of T-SQL queries into Aurora PostgreSQL.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.