So now let's talk about RDS Backup.
So first of all, you have automated backups
and what it means that this service, RDS service,
will automatically do a daily full backup of the database
during your database backup window.
But on top of it, every five minutes
there's going to be the transactions log being backed-up.
That means that the earliest backup you have
is five minutes before now.
That means that from these automated backups
you can restore to any point of time
up until five minutes ago.
And for the automated backup retention,
you can say between one to 35 days of retention.
And if you wanted to disable this feature
you would set zero to disable automated backups.
The second option is to do manual DB Snapshots,
manual database snapshots.
And these, as the name indicates,
are manually triggered by the user.
But the benefit of it
is that this backup, that you do manually,
you can retain it for as long as you want.
So automated backups expire,
whereas DB Snapshots that are manual
can be retained for as long as you want.
So here is a trick.
When would you use backups, obviously, to back up your data,
but also if you want to save some costs.
So say for example, you have an RDS database
and you know that you're going to use it only
two hours per month.
Instead of stopping the database in which, for example,
you will still have to pay for the storage
even though your database is stopped.
What you can do is that after using it for two hours
you do a snapshot and then you delete the original database.
The snapshot is costing you way less
than the actual storage of the RDS database.
And when you're ready to use again the database
you would restore the snapshot and use that.
So it's a little trick and it can come up in the exam.
Now for Aurora backups, it is actually quite similar.
You have automated backups from one to 35 days
but they cannot be disabled.
So on RDS, they could be disabled, but not on Aurora.
And you have a point-in-time recovery
at any point of time in that timeframe,
so you can recover to whatever you want.
Now for manual DB Snapshots,
they can also be manually triggered by the user
and you retain them for as long as you want.
So you can see Aurora and RDS Backups are quite similar.
Now what about the restore options?
The first thing is that you can restore an RDS or
Aurora backup or snapshots, they're the same thing,
into a new database.
So anytime you restore an automated backup
or a manual snapshot, then it will create a new database.
The other option is that you can restore
a MySQL RDS database from S3.
And S3, we haven't seen it yet,
it's a way to store objects in the cloud on AWS,
it's a very popular service,
And the idea is that you will create a backup
of your on-premises database,
and then you will place it onto Amazon S3,
which is some object storage.
And finally, there is the option in RDS
to restore the backup file from Amazon S3
onto a new RDS instance running MySQL.
And if you wanted to, instead,
restore to MySQL Aurora cluster,
what you can do is that you take a backup again
of your on-premises database, so externally,
and then you used to use a software
called Percona XtraBackup.
It only works with this for now.
Then the backup file of Percona XtraBackup
goes onto Amazon S3.
And from this you can restore the backup file
onto a new Aurora cluster running MySQL.
So the difference here is that for restoring into RDS MySQL
you just need a backup of your database
for restoring into Aurora MySQL.
What you need to do is to do a backup using
Percona Xtrabackup, and then from S3
into your Aurora DB cluster.
Okay, so those are restore options
for either the snapshots or the database dumps
onto Amazon S3.
And finally, there's a last feature you need to know about
called Aurora Database Cloning.
So this allows you to create a new Aurora database cluster
from an existing one.
So say you have a production database in Aurora
and you want to actually run test on it
but you want to copy the data
because your test application must be
in a staging environment.
Well, for this
you're just going to clone your production Aurora database.
It's going to give you a new database,
and you can call it, for example,
the Staging Aurora database.
And it's going to be very quick.
It's faster than doing a snapshot and restore.
So why, while cloning uses the copy-on-write protocol,
how does that work?
Well, initially, when you create a database clone
it's going to be using the same data volume
as the original database cluster,
which is going to be fast and efficient
because you don't have any copying of data.
And then as the updates are being made
to the production Aurora database,
or to the Staging Aurora database,
then new additional storage is going to be allocated
and data is going to be copied and separated.
So that means you have the best of both worlds.
So doing a database cloning is very fast and cost effective,
and it's extremely useful to have a staging database
from a production database
without impacting the production database
and without going through snapshot and restore features.
Okay, that's it.
We've seen all the options for backup and restore
as well as cloning.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.