So now, let's talk Amazon RDS Proxy.
So we know we can deploy our RDS database within our VPC,
but now we can also deploy
a fully managed database proxy for RDS.
So you may say,
"Okay, we can access our RDS database directly.
Why do we need a proxy to access our database?"
Well, if you use an As an RDS Proxy,
this will allow you, your application,
to pool and share the database connections
established with the database.
So instead of having every single application
connect to your RDS database instance,
they will be instead connecting to the proxy,
and the proxy will pool these connections together
into less connections to the RDS database instance.
So why may you do this?
Well, this makes a lot of sense
if you have a lot of connections
into your RDS database instance,
and it's going to improve your database efficiency
by reducing the stress on database resources,
for example, CPU and RAM,
and also minimize the open connections
and the timeouts into your database.
So that's one thing you need to look out for
from the exam perspective.
Now, as I said, the RDS Proxy is fully serverless.
It's auto scaling, so you don't need to manage its capacity.
And it's highly available.
It's across multiple AZ.
And therefore, in case, for example,
there is a failover that happens
on your RDS database instance.
For example, it goes from the primary instance
to the standby instance,
then it will, thanks to the RDS Proxy,
reduce the failover time by up to 66%.
So this is true for RDS and Aurora.
So again, instead of having all your applications
connect to the main RDS database instance
and then handle the feller themselves,
they will just connect to the RDS Proxy,
which does not know any failover.
And the RDS Proxy will, itself,
handle the failover of the RDS database instance,
therefore improving your failover time.
So something else you need to look for
from an exam perspective.
So the RDS Proxy supports MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB,
Microsoft SQL Server,
as well as Aurora for MySQL and PostgreSQL.
It doesn't require you
to do any code change in your application.
Just instead of connecting to your RDS database instance
or your Aurora database,
you'd now just connect to your RDS Proxy and you are done.
On top of it,
there's a third advantage to using an RDS Proxy.
It is to enforce IAM authentication for your database.
So to make sure that people
can only connect to your RDS database instance using IAM.
And then these credentials
can be securely stored in another service
called the AWS Secrets Manager.
So again, if you need to see a way
to enforce IAM authentication for your database,
think RDS Proxy.
And finally, the RDS Proxy is never publicly accessible.
So it's only accessible from within your VPC.
So you cannot connect over the internet to your RDS Proxy,
which is enhanced security.
And so one service we haven't seen
that is going for sure to be very helped by the RDS Proxy
is called the Lambda functions.
And the Lambda functions, they will execute pieces of code.
We'll see them later on in this course.
Okay, you don't need to know them right now,
but we have to tackle them right now
because of the RDS Proxy feature.
And so the Lambda functions, they can multiply,
multiply many, many times.
And they will appear and disappear very, very fast.
And therefore, imagine you have 100
or 1,000 Lambda functions appearing and disappearing
just like that, and opening up connections
into your RDS database instance, they will be a big problem
because it will leave open connections and timeouts,
and it will be a mess.
And therefore what you do is that you use the RDS Proxy
to pool connections for your Lambda functions,
and then the Lambda functions will overload the RDS Proxy,
but it's meant to be overload.
And the RDS Proxy will pool these connections
into less connections to the RDS database instance,
thus, solving your problems, okay?
So that's it for this lecture. I hope you liked it.
And don't worry, we'll review the proxy once again
once we go into the Lambda lectures.
But again, RDS Proxy is used to minimize
and pool connections on your RDS database instance.
It's also used to minimize failover time
and reduce it by up to 66%.
And also, it's used to enforce IAM authentication
for your database and to securely store its credentials
in the Secrets Manager service.
All right, that's it. I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.