Now, let's talk about ElastiCache Security.
So ElastiCache supports IAM authentication for Redis only
and for the rest you just use a username and password.
If you define IAM policies on ElastiCache,
they're only used for AWS API-level security.
Then you have security within Redis called Redis AUTH,
where you can set a password and a token
when you create a Redis cluster,
which gives you an extra level of security
for your cache on top of your security groups.
It also supports SSL in flight encryption.
Next we have Memcached.
So Memcached supports SASL-based authentication
which is quite an advanced mechanism.
Just remember, just a name.
So to summarize, when we have an EC2 instance in a client,
for example, we could use Redis AUTH to connect
to Redis Cluster that's protected by Redis Security Group
and we can have in-flight encryption.
Or alternatively, we could, for example,
leverage IAM authentication for Redis.
Now, there are three kinds of patterns
for loading data into ElastiCache.
The number one is Lazy Loading,
where all the read data is cached
and data can become stale in the cache,
Write Through, which is to add or update data in the cache
whenever it is written to a database
where there's no stale data,
and using ElastiCache as a session store that we saw before
and then we can expire a session
using the time to live features.
Now, caching is very hard and there's this very famous quote
in computer science that "There are only two hard things
in computer science: caching invalidation
and naming things."
So caching is a very complicated topic
and give you a very high-level overview,
but let's illustrate the lazy loading strategy here.
So your application, if it has a cache hit
in ElastiCache data from the cache,
otherwise there's a cache miss, therefore,
you read from the database and you write to the cache.
This is something we've seen from before
and it is called lazy loading
because only when you don't have a cache hit,
then you load the data into Amazon ElastiCache.
So now let's talk about the use cases for Redis
and there's one you need to know going to the exam.
It is around creating a gaming leaderboard.
So it is very complex.
The idea is that you wanna say
who is number one, who is number two,
who's number three at any moment in time for your game.
And so there is a feature in Redis called Sorted Sets
which guarantees both uniqueness and element ordering.
And each time an element is added it's going to be ranked
in real time and then added in the correct order.
The idea is that if you have a Redis cluster,
you can create a realtime leaderboard with a number one,
number two, and number three player in realtime
and all the Redis cache will have
at the same leaderboard available.
That means that your clients,
when talking to your Amazon ElastiCache using Redis,
they can have access to this realtime leaderboard
and we don't need to program that feature application side.
We can just leverage Redis
with the sorted sets to get access
to your realtime leaderboard.
And this is yet again something
that can come up in the exam, okay?
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.