So let's practice using Amazon ECS
by going into the ECS console service,
and then we're going
to enable the new ECS experience on the top left.
Then you're go in to cluster and we're going
to create our first cluster.
So this one is going to be called DemoCluster,
and we'll leave the default namespace as is.
So for infrastructure, we have three options.
The first one is AWS Fargate, which allows us
to provide the containers to AWS,
and then AWS will run these containers for us on demand.
So this is good because this is a serverless options.
We don't provide the compute.
AWS will provide the compute for us on demand,
but we don't even see it.
The other options are Amazon EC2 instances
where we provide our own Amazon EC2 instances
to provide the compute to run our containers on.
And we have external instances using ECS anywhere
where we can, for example, use your own data center
to run ECS containers on it.
So Fargate will leave it enabled,
and we'll also enable Amazon EC2 instances for the demo.
So we're going to create a new auto scaling group,
and then we have to choose the operating system.
So Amazon Linux 2 is great,
or you can choose the newest one, Amazon Linux 2023,
whatever you want.
For EC2 instance type, I'm going to use a t2.micro,
which is free tier eligible.
And then for desired capacity, I will choose minimum zero
and maximum five.
So no SSH key pair is going to be configured
and we'll leave the root EBS volume size as is.
Okay, now that we have specified an Amazon EC2 instance type
of infrastructure, we have to provide network settings
for the Amazon EC2 instances, so which is a default VPC,
as well as the three subnets available to me.
And for security group,
we'll use an existing security group
being the default security group.
And finally, for auto-assign public IP, again,
we'll use the default to use subnet setting.
We're not touching monitoring and tags.
And then we click on Create to create our cluster.
So while this is happening,
let's have a look at the auto scaling group
that is being created on AWS.
And then on the left-hand side,
I will click on auto scaling groups right here.
And it's showing, as you can see,
there was an auto scaling group created
for me called Infra-ECS-Cluster.
And desired capacity is zero, min capacity, zero,
max capacity, five.
And this was created directly by my ECS cluster.
And the creation is in progress.
And what this cluster has will have maybe EC2 instances
for me to launch tasks on.
So as you can see, it's in three availability zones.
So we know that the ECS tasks are going
to be launched across three AZ.
And what I'm going to do now is just wait for this cluster
to be created, which is the case now.
So what I can do now is explore this DemoCluster.
So if I click on it, I'm in the DemoCluster
and I can go to services are zero, tasks are zero
because we haven't launched anything yet.
And then we go to the more interesting infrastructure.
So if you go here to the infrastructure,
we have three capacity providers in this ECS cluster.
The first one is FARGATE.
That means that we can launch Fargate tasks
onto our ECS cluster.
The second one is FARGATE_SPOT
That means that we can launch Fargate tasks in spot mode,
select spot instances for EC2.
And the last one is a ASGProvider.
And this one means that we can launch EC2 instances
in this cluster directly through this ASG.
So it's managed scaling right now,
and the current size is zero,
but I can change it if I wanted to.
So let me show you what it would look like.
I go here, I go to details,
and I would edit the desired capacity to be one,
just to show you what it's like.
So what's going to happen out of this
is that an EC2 instance is going to be created, okay?
And when it's created,
it's going to register itself into the DemoCluster,
and then I will see it under container instances.
That means that when we create an ECS task,
it can either be launched on a FARGATE
or FARGATE_SPOT capacity provider,
or it can be launched on the container instances
that I will have launched as part of this ASG.
So what I'm going to do now is just wait for this instance
to be in the running state
and registered into my ECS cluster.
So let me refresh now.
My instance is InService and it's t2.micro.
And if I go back into my Amazon ECS cluster,
it is registered as a container instance that is currently,
of course, running zero tasks and has 1,024 CPU available
and 982 memory available.
So this is giving me the capacity of this instance,
and I can launch, as you'll see, tasks on it
until the capacity runs out.
So we're good to go.
So we have an ECS cluster.
We've seen two capacity providers, I mean three.
We've seen the container instances.
So now let's go ahead and do run our first service,
and I will see you in the next lecture to do that.