Now let's create an ECS service.
But before we do so, we need to create a task definition.
So I'm going to create a new task definition
from the task definition panels
and I need to give it a name.
So I'll call this one nginxdemos-hello.
And this is coming from this Docker image
called nginxdemos/hello on Docker Hub.
And so this is the one we're going to be using in our demo.
So this is why I call my task definition nginxdemo
with a hyphen of hello.
Okay, next we need to choose
the infrastructure requirements.
So do we want to launch on Fargate or Amazon EC2 instances.
Well, Fargate is serverless compute
so we'll leave it enabled.
And if we enable this, we could launch this task,
this service on our Amazon EC2 instances.
But for simplicity's sake right now,
I'm just going to use AWS Fargate
and launch our containers into serverless compute mode.
Then we need to choose what type of OS
and architecture we have.
So Linux is fine.
And what is the task size for our Fargate container?
So we can say for example, that we have 0.5 or 1 vCPU
and you can go up to 16 vCPU in this example.
And then you can also adjust memory.
So you can say, hey, I want up to, for example,
120 gigabytes of memory.
So all of this would be provided
by Fargate in a serverless fashion.
To keep things very cheap and simple,
I will choose 0.5 vCPU, and one gigabytes.
Next we have task role.
So task role is an IAM role that we can assign to our task
if we wanted to make API request to AWS services.
But because we don't do this right now,
we are not going to specify a task role.
But this is something of utmost importance
if your containers need to use AWS.
Now for the task execution role, leave it as default
and if this ECS task execution role is not created yet
it's going to be created automatically by ECS service.
So we're good.
Next our container, so the name is going to be
nginxdemos-hello and the image URL
is going to be nginxdemos/hello.
And this is going to pull automatically this image
from the Docker Hub right here.
So this is very handy and it's an essential container.
Now we have lots of different options.
For example, the port mappings.
So we want to map the port 80 to the port 80
of the container, which is great and we'll leave it as is.
And then you could add more port mappings if you wanted to.
You could, for example, set the resource allocation limits,
the environment variables from file or manually
and the logging.
But all these things I'm gonna leave as default
because this is going to work fine for us.
Storage, Fargate comes with some ephemeral storage.
So we'll leave it as is, again, from 21 gigabytes
which is a default right here.
And this is fine, just leave the value you have right now.
So let's create this.
And this is creating our first task definition.
Now you see version two for me
because I've just created it twice.
But for you, you should see version one.
So next, let's launch this task definition as a service.
So let's go into Clusters and then DemoCluster.
And under services I'm going to create a service.
So for compute option, I'm going to go into Launch type
and choose Fargate as my launch time
and the platform version to be latest.
And then the application type is a service.
That means it's going to be a long running service,
for example, a web application.
But if you wanted to have a task that terminates
and done, for example, a batch job, then you could use task.
But we'll use service
and then we'll select the nginxdemo-hello family
and choose whatever revision is the latest for you.
Should be number one for you.
Then let's assign a name for this service,
so nginxdemos-hello, the same as our task definition,
it's pretty standard.
And then the service type is going to be replica
of one task.
For deployment option, leave it as is
and deployment failure detection, leave it as is as well.
Next for networking, so we want to deploy into our VPC
on these three subnets
and we are going to create a new security group.
I will call this one nginxdemos-hello.
And I'll call this one security group for NGINX.
Now the idea is that we want to allow on HTTP
on port 80 and the source right now is going to be anywhere.
And for public IP, I leave this turned on.
And for load balancing, yes, we do want a load balancer.
It is going to be an application balancer.
You're going to create it.
So DemoALBForECS is the name,
we'll leave it as zero as the health check grace period.
We should leave enough time for our containers to start.
And then our containers is going to be this one
on port 80 on protocol HTTP.
And the target group is going to be tg-nginxdemos-hello.
The protocol is HTTP,
the protocol health check is HTTP
and the health check path is slash.
So now we've defined our service
where we have an application balancer, a target group,
a security group, and so on,
so we should be good to go.
We're not going to touch anything into service auto scaling
and task placement, but these things are available.
That means that, of course,
you can scale automatically on ECS.
So now my deployment is in progress
and we need to wait a few minutes.
So our service has now been deployed successfully.
So let's click on the service and have a look at it.
So we can see right now we have one desired task
and one is running and the status is active.
So this is really good.
And we can see that the service is linked to a target group.
So I click on the target group
and in the target group itself
we can see that it's linked to our DemoALB
which is the application balancer that was created
as part of this service.
And it looks like one IP address is registered as a target.
And this is the IP address of my container
which is very good.
So now if we have a look at this load balancer itself,
it is active, I can copy the DNS name
and then open a new tab and paste it.
And I get the Nginx welcome page, which is very good.
So that means that everything is working.
The server address is the exact same
as the IP we have registered in here.
So this is the private IP, which is good.
And what else?
So if we go under the service itself now
we can have a look at tasks.
So as you can see, one container is running right now
and this is this one task.
And I can click on it and have a look at this task itself.
So it tells me the configuration, the task revision,
where it's been launched, the private IP, the containers.
We can have a look at logs to know the logs
of our Nginx container as well, which is good.
And if we look at the service itself,
so we are on the service and then we go to events,
we can have a look at where the events of this.
So that means that we have one task that has been started.
It was registered in target-group
and then it's been complete deployment
and now we have a steady state.
So as we can see in this,
I can go to /test, for example,
and the URI will change in here.
So Nginx is working as expected.
Now what we can do because we're under ECS,
is that we have a look at our task,
we have one of them, but we can launch some more.
So I want to show you how easy it is
to launch more tasks with Fargate.
So let's update this service.
And now the desired number of task is going to be three.
So one per AZ, for example,
and the rest I will just leave as is.
So we'll leave the task definition to the same.
We'll leave the compute configuration as Fargate
and load balancing does not change
in terms of health checks and so on.
So let's just click on Update.
And now what's going to happen is that we have asked
the ECS service to run two more tasks.
So if I refresh this and wait a little bit,
now we have two more tasks being provisioned
and they are provisioned on the Fargate engine.
So that means that behind the scenes,
AWS is going to provision automatically the resource
that it needs to launch these tasks.
So let's wait a little bit.
They're pending, now they're activating
and now they're running.
So this was very quick actually.
And if I go under here
and now refresh this page, as you can see
the IP address is changing every time I refresh.
So the application balancer is distributing the load
between all my containers on ECS, which is great.
So this is quite powerful
and we just demonstrated the scaling
of ECS while scaling up.
And just to scale back the demo and save on cost,
we can update the service here
and have the desired number of tasks to be zero.
This way the service is still there
but we are don't have any containers running.
And under my application load balancer,
my auto scaling group, sorry,
then I'm going to click on this
and make sure the desired capacity is also zero.
This way we are sure not to be running any type
of instances on our EC2 cluster for ECS, okay?
So now you can verify this
that the tasks are gone and you're good to go
and you can look at the events to see what has ECS done
while we were asking you to update the service.
Okay? So that's it.
We've seen how to create an ECS cluster,
we've seen how to create an ECS service on Fargate.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.