So I wanna show you a quick hands on for Amazon EKS
but this is completely out of the feature.
So if you do decide to do it
it's going to cost you quite a bit of money.
So I just suggest you just watch what I'm doing
just to understand a bit better
the Kubernetes per service from AWS.
So we are going to create a new cluster on AWS.
So I use demo EKS as a name.
I can select a Kubernetes version.
I will use the default
and then we need to
have a service role to manage everything.
So to create this role
I need to follow the instructions from the EKS user guide.
So I go to IAM
and then I will have to create a role for EKS.
And then I will need to add the EKS cluster role.
So let's do this.
We're going to go to roles.
Create a role.
This is for a service.
This is for the EKS service.
Here we go.
And we'll do EKS cluster to allow access
to other services that are operated by our cluster.
So here we go.
We're good.
Next.
Then the permission is selected already
and the role name is EKS cluster role.
Let's create this role.
Invalid name, so let's just remove the
first space in the beginning.
And now the role is being created.
Okay, so let's refresh this
and we can find this role right here.
Now, do we want to encrypt our secrets with KMS?
For now I'm not going to do it, but this is a
possibility for security.
Then where do you want to deploy our clusters?
So we have a VPC and subnet.
So this is so we are, we are highly available.
Then security groups we want out of this.
So we could select, for example, the default security group.
And then we choose the IPv4 type of services.
Then the cluster endpoint access is going to be public
so that we can access it from our computer.
Do we want any networking add-ons?
So we'll just choose the default again
and the default for proxy and DNS.
So as you can see, these are like a lot
of configuration and EKS should be its own course.
To be honest, I just want to run through you the options
so you can understand what's happening.
Then we can configure logging for the control plane.
I'm not going to do it.
And then we review the settings.
So we have set up security groups, networking, cluster, API
access to public, and we are good to go.
So let's create this.
And what this is going to do is
that it's going to create the cluster itself
and then we'll have to create the nodes for the cluster.
So my cluster is now created.
And the next step is to provision compute capacity
for your cluster, by adding a managed node group
or creating your fargate profile.
So we've seen this in the overview
and that's just what I wanted to show you.
So if we go into the resources, this is where
all your Kubernetes resources are going to be managed.
And this is some Kubernetes specific knowledge, okay?
But this is where you have it for the Kubernetes experts.
Then in compute, this is where we can add node groups.
So if I go into node groups, I can add node group here.
I call this one demo node group.
You would need to create an IAM role for this node group.
So we go into the IAM console...
And then we create a new role.
And this role are, is for the EC2 instances that are part
of my manage node group.
So I will just use EC2
and then I will search for policies.
I will type EKS
and you want an Amazon EKS worker node policy added in it.
So let's click on next.
And for this, I will enter
and it's somewhere in documentation.
So I will enter the...
Amazon EKS node role
and actually there's add permissions for this.
And then we need to also add the Amazon EC2
container registry read only policy in this.
So let's go back.
In here, we're going to edit permissions
and add one more thing.
The Amazon EC2 container registry.
So let's look for this.
Here we go.
It's here, next.
And we're good to go.
Let's create this role.
So just make sure it doesn't start with the space.
Here we go.
The role is created...
and now I'm able to go in here
refresh this, and I will find the Amazon EKS node role.
Great. Then do we want to have a launch template
for our EC2 instances?
We can specify one
but I will leave this unticked and then click on next.
What type of node group do we want?
So Amazon Linux 2 is great.
Do we want on-demand or spot instances?
What type of instances do we want?
So we want T3 medium? T3 micro? Whatever you want.
What is the disc size?
What is the node scaling configuration?
So how many nodes in your node groups do you want?
So this is the settings for the OS scaling group.
And then what is the node group update?
So when you do update
how many nodes can you tolerate to be done?
So click on next.
What subnets do you want access to?
And then when we're good to go
we create this managed node group.
And so to show you this
this is the way to deploy EC2 instances
for your Amazon EKS cluster, but they are entirely managed
by AWS, which is, makes it very easy.
And the other way to create nodes in here.
So, we go one level up, we go back into computes.
The other way to create nodes, except
from this node group is actually to have fargates
and fargates allows you not to provision EC2 instances.
And so we would have
with a setup to go and add a target profile.
Now we're not going do this.
I just want to show you the options
for node groups for fargate profiles.
Actually don't need this one.
So I'll delete it when it's finished creating.
And the last option I wanna show you is around add-ons.
So if we wanted to actually use EBS volumes
we can install add-ons.
And one of them is the Amazon EBS CSI driver.
And this will allow us to leverage EBS
for our Amazon EKS cluster
and they will be STS side driver also for EFS X,
EFS, and so on.
Okay. So this is all the actions, I am gonna show you.
Kubernetes requires its own knowledge
to be honest, and it's very
very difficult and requires a full course on it.
So what I'm going to do now is just go ahead
and delete this cluster.
So for this I'll just type demo EKS, and this will be
it all I wanted to show you was how to create an EKS cluster
and to delete the first need to delete the note groups.
I will skip that from the video.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.