Okay, so I want to show you how AWS App Runner works
but this is not part of the feature
so if you do decide to follow along with me
just know you're going to pay some money
for vCPU and per gigabytes, okay?
So let's go and create an App Runner service.
So first we have to say the source of our deployment.
Is it part of a Container Registry
or is it part of a Source Code that we can connect,
for example, from GitHub, okay?
We are going to use a Container Registry.
Now it can either be Amazon ECR,
if it's an internal, private docker container that you have
in your infrastructure or Amazon ECR Public
if you wanted to deploy a public image,
and we're going to do this.
We're going to go into the
Amazon ECR Public Gallery website,
and I'm going to do HTTPD just to deploy
a very simple HTP server to do basically nothing
but show you how to deploy an HTTPD server.
So I'm going to just copy this right now.
Copy this address and paste it here.
Okay. Next, what is the Deployment Setting?
So whether or not we want to manually deploy our application
or automatically.
So if we were enabled
with a Source Code Repo or Amazon ECR, we could do automatic
but we are doing something manual right now, which is fine.
So, let's click on next.
Then I'll call it DemoHTTP.
We choose how many vCPUs we want
and how much memory we want.
So one vCPU and two gigabytes is fine.
This is the lowest I can get.
We can pass environment verbals.
We can configure the port of our service.
So if we go in here and we have a look at the documentation,
we can probably find that the ports of it is
port 80 of our image.
So we are going to use port 80 and then pretty quick,
because you don't need to know why exactly,
but here we go.
So it's port 80, then do we want to configure Auto Scaling?
So do we want to have the default configuration
from one instance to 25 instances
and what is the concurrency?
So with this scaling, we'll have 100 request
concurrent request, per instance, which is great.
Or you can use your custom configuration or add a new one.
Okay. Then you can do health checks.
So do you wanna perform health checks
on your application to make sure it's healthy?
So we can leave this as is.
Security if you want your containers
to have an instance role.
Networking, if you wanted to deploy into your Custom VPC,
but for now, we'll use a public access type of access,
and do we want tracing with AWS X-ray.
So for now I'll keep everything as default and press next.
So we verify the settings.
So we use a public HTTPD image,
and then the port is on port 80.
So this is pretty simple
because we just specified one container,
and then we just click on create and deploy,
and behind the scenes App Runner
is actually going to deploy an auto-scaling group.
It's going to deploy scaling triggers.
It's going to deploy most likely like target containers.
It's going to deploy a load balancer.
It's going to give us a domain and so on.
So it's quite handy,
and from this one interface,
I can get access to my logs, my activity,
my metrics, my observability, my configuration,
as well as connect any custom domain.
So it's very powerful, all-in-one service to
deploy containers in a production fashion on AWS,
and I really like it.
So I took a bit of time, but my service is now created,
and if I click on this
I'm able to access my default domain,
and it just says it works, which is the message
that is displayed when you have deployed HTTPD correctly.
So that's good news. It works,
and if you have a look at it
we can look at the event log into
where to see if everything was being deployed,
the health checks and so on, and that's about it.
It's as simple as that, and if we were to have a lot
of concurrent requests on this website
then automatically it would scale, which is quite nice.
So that's it really, I find App Runner
incredibly easy to use.
So now we can just delete this application
just type delete and we're done.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.