So, now, let's talk
about AWS App2Container or A2C.
So, it's a CLI tool that is used to migrate
and modernize Java and .NET
web applications into Docker containers.
The idea is that you wanna do a migration.
It's called a lift-and-shift migration,
where your apps are running on premises
on whatever you have, for example,
bare metal or visual machines,
and then you migrate it to AWS.
And so, the idea is that you accelerate modernization,
but you don't change any code
and you migrate legacy apps this way
to the cloud without doing any code changes.
So, this will in the end,
generate a CloudFormation templates
for your compute, your network, and so on.
It will also register the generated Docker containers
into Amazon ECR,
and then you can choose
to deploy to ECS, EKS, or App Runner.
And this supports as well prebuilt CI/CD pipelines.
So, the idea is that you're going to use the CLI to discover
and analyze which apps can be migrated.
Then, everything's going to be extracted and containerized.
Then, the deployment artifacts are going to be generated.
That means that there's going to be
a CloudFormation templates with ECS Task
and EKS Pod definitions,
anything CI/CD if needed, and other infrastructure.
And then, deployed to AWS.
So, the image of the Docker container
is going to be stored in Amazon ECR,
and then deployed anywhere you want
on ECS, EKS, or App Runner.
So, the very simple concept to remember in this instance
that if you want to migrate a web application
using Java or .NET to AWS very simply,
then you should use AWS App2Container.
And that's it.
That's the level of detail required for the exam.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.