So let's say you wanted to migrate a database
from your on-premise systems to the AWS Cloud.
In this case, you should use DMS,
or Database Migration Service.
It's a quick and secure database service
that allows you to migrate your database
from on-premise to AWS, but the cool thing
is that it's resilient and it's self-healing.
And all alongside the migration,
the source database remains available.
And it supports many types of engines,
such as homogeneous migration,
so from Oracle to Oracle, or Postgres to Postgres,
but also heterogeneous migrations.
For example, if you want to migrate
from Microsoft SQL server all the way to Aurora
and it supports continuous data replication using CDC,
which is Change Data Capture.
Finally, to use DMS,
you need to create an EC2 instance, and that EC2 instance
will perform the replication tasks for you.
So very simply, your source database may be on-premise
and then you're running an EC2 instance
that has the DMS software
and it will pull data from the source database,
in continuously, and put it in the target database.
So the question is
what are the sources and what are the targets?
You don't need to remember them all,
but the important to see ones,
just to understand the concepts behind the DMS.
So the sources can be on-premises databases
or EC2 instances based databases,
such as Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL,
MariaDB, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SAP, and DB2.
It can also be Azure databases, such as Azure SQL Database.
It could be Amazon RDS, any database including Aurora.
It could be Amazon S3 and DocumentDB.
In terms of targets,
well we have different options, as well.
We have on-premises and EC2 instances databases.
So we can have Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL,
MariaDB, PostgreSQL, SAP.
We can also have any database on Amazon RDS.
We can have Redshift, DynamoDB, Amazon S3,
the OpenSource service, Kinesis Data Streams,
Apache Kafka, DocumentDB, and Amazon Neptune,
as well as Redis and Babelfish.
So you don't need to remember all of these, of course,
but the general idea is that DMS can help you
take a database, for example, an on-premise database
and have it put and exported and migrated onto a target
that is, pretty much, any database that AWS is offering.
If you understand this,
then you have the general idea behind DMS.
So what if the source database and the target database
do not have the same engine?
Then you need to use something called AWS SCT,
for Schema Conversion Tool,
and it will convert the database schema
from one engine to another.
So for example, if you're using an OLTP, we can migrate
from SQL server or Oracle to MySQL, PostgreSQL, or Aurora.
As you can see on the left hand side, the database engine
is different from the one on the right hand side,
but also you can transform for analytics process,
such as Teradata or Oracle, all the way to Amazon Redshift.
So the idea is that here, the source database
has a different engine than the Target database.
In the middle, we have DMS,
but it's now also running SCT, or Schema Conversion Tool.
And the thing to know going into the exam
is that you do not need to use SCT
if you are migrating the same database engine.
So if you're doing on-premise PostgreSQL to RDS PostgreSQL,
it is the same database agent, it is PostgreSQL.
And so this for, you will not use SCT.
But if you're doing something such as Oracle to Postgres,
then you will need to use SCT.
So just so you know, the database agent is PostgreSQL,
but RDS is just a platform
that we're using to run this database engine.
So how would you go to set up
a continuous replication for DMS?
Well, you would have your corporate data center,
for example, with an Oracle database as a source
and an Amazon RDS database for MySQL DB as a target.
And as we can see,
we have two different kinds of types of database.
So in this case, we have to use SCT,
otherwise it will not work.
So the Schema Conversion Tool.
So we set up a server with AWS SCT installed
and we can set it up on-premises,
this is best practice,
and then we will do the schema conversion
into our Amazon RDS database running MySQL.
Then we can set up a DMS replication instance
that will do the full load and the change data capture, CDC,
to have continuous replication.
And so it will perform the data migration
by reading the database on-premises,
the source Oracle database,
and inserting the data into your private subnets.
That's it. So that's all you need to know for DMS.
This is for Database Migration Service.
Remember, you need to use SCT whenever you have
two different kinds of databases that you're migrating from.
And for DMS, there is a multi AZ deployment.
So when you have this,
then you have a DMS replication instance in one AZ
and then you have synchronous replication of that instance
into another AZ, which is going to be a standby replica.
So the benefits of using this is, of course,
to be resilient to a failure in one specific AZ,
but also gives you data redundancy,
will eliminate IO freezes and will minimize latency spikes.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.