So let's have a look
at the different options
offered by the AWS Database Migration Service, or DMS.
So we're going to get started
and we are going to, with the screen,
to figure out the right kind of migration we need.
So here, I can first discover and assess.
So this is going to use AWS DMS Fleet Advisor,
which is going to have a look at the inventory
of all your on-premises database
and will identify the right potential migration path.
So this is used to give you results in hours,
and save you a lot of planning time
without using third-party tools
or hiring migration experts.
The second option is to convert.
So this is to use the DMS Schema Conversion tool
to basically convert database schemas
from one database technology to another one.
And so this is good to just get an idea
of the kind of transformations you can do.
Then you have migration options,
and this is to actually migrate your data.
So you have different kind of migrations that are possible.
The first one is homogenous data migration.
And so this is when you go from, for example,
one database to the very same database technology.
So for example, from Oracle to Oracle,
and this is very helpful, for example,
and you would use native database tools
to gain some speed and be faster.
Then you have the heterogeneous migrations
and so they are when the database types are different.
For example, you migrate from Oracle
to Aurora or from Oracle to PostgreSQL, whatever.
In this case, you can use serverless replication
or instance-based migration.
So the difference here
is that with instance-based migration,
there is an EC2 instance
behind those scenes that you manage to do the migration,
but that DMS manages the instance itself
and does the the task on it.
And serverless, well, you don't manage
any kind of resources,
but it doesn't support every kind of database engines.
So try out with serverless
because obviously, it's a little bit nicer, easier,
but see if your technology is supported or not.
If not, use instance-based migrations.
So I'm going to show you instance-based migrations
in which we're going to create a replication instance
and just look at the options.
So you would give it a name,
then you would give a description,
and then you configure the instance.
So of course, based on how much data has to be transiting,
you would need to size up your instance.
So you have different options
from t3.micro, all the way to really large instances.
And it's really up to you to see what is going
to be necessary based on what load you are getting.
You choose a DMS version
and see the DMS release notes
to see what are the new updates
given by different engine versions.
And then you choose high availability.
So if you're doing a production workload of replication,
it's usually better to be in multiple availability zones,
in case one of these AZ goes down.
If you're doing a very simple migration
in dev or test, then single AZ may be sufficient.
So we use multi AZ,
and sometimes you get restrictions
around the type of database class you need.
So let's just go for Single-AZ to get no warning.
Then how much storage you want on your EC2 instance,
and then the connectivity and security.
So the IP, the VPC, the subnet group,
whether or not you want your instance
to be publicly accessible.
And then you have more advanced settings if you wanted to,
and maintenance settings to do maintenance
on the operating system of your instance.
When you're good, you click on Create replication instance,
but we're not going to do this
because this would cost us money,
and we don't have databases anyway to migrate to and from.
So just cancel this, but I just wanna show you the options.
So once you have chosen a replication instance,
on the left hand side,
we can create what's called a endpoint.
So endpoints allow you to define where your databases are.
So you can create an endpoint
and it could be a source endpoint or a target endpoint.
If it's a database in RDS,
you have a easy selector by choosing this option.
If not, then you can set up the endpoint identifier,
then the source engine type.
So you have all of these options in here for source engine.
And if you choose targets,
you have all of these options right here as well.
And then you would choose the endpoint settings.
So either a wizard to get guided to connect
or an editor and to provide it as a JSON format.
So these are very specific to your database,
and this is why I don't go deep into it,
but they provide information on how to connect
to your source or your target database.
So then you can test your connection
from a specific replication instance as well.
So when you have your source
and your target defined,
then you would go into Database migration tasks.
And this is where you can create a task
and say, Hey, here is my replication instance I want to use.
Here is my source database endpoint.
Here's my target database endpoint,
and what is my migration type.
So here we can migrate existing data
or we can also migrate the existing data
and replicate ongoing changes.
So that's for continuous data replication,
or just do the replication of data changes only.
Again, we can have a test setting,
so what settings we want,
we use Wizard and we choose all these settings,
or we just specify it as a JSON to see everything
that can be configured for your DMS task,
and as you can see, that is a lot of settings.
This is why maybe JSON editor may be better at some point.
Okay?
Then you can do an assessment
and do some configuration and then create your task.
Obviously, we're not doing any of this
because this would cost us some money,
but you get the idea.
You create a replication instance, then endpoints.
And then finally, a database migration tasks,
and DMS is evolving towards serverless replication
where you can just create a replication directly
from database to database without managing
any replication instance.
And then you have more features around schema conversion
and Fleet Advisor recommendations,
and as well as homogenous data migrations
to leverage the native database tooling
to perform these migrations.
So that's it for DMS and its overview.
That should be enough for the exam.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.