Okay, so yet another theoretical lecture,
but I still want to mention it
because I think it's extremely important going to the exam.
You need to know about the services
that AWS offers at a very, very high level,
but just hear about them once
to do on-premise strategy with cloud.
So we have the ability to download the Amazon Linux 2 AMI
as a virtual machine and that will be in the ISO format.
And you can load this ISO image
into the common software used to create VMs.
So that includes VMWare, KVM, Virtual Box,
which is Oracle VM or Microsoft Hyper-V.
And this would allow you
to run Amazon Linux 2 on your on-premise infrastructure
directly using that VM.
So that means that you can make it work
with some user data and so on.
So quite cool to think about.
Then we have a feature called VM import and export.
And what this allows you to do
is to migrate your existing VMs and applications
into EC2 directly using this feature.
And you can also create a, for example,
a disaster recovery repository strategy
if you had a lot of on-premise VMs,
but you want it to back them up into the cloud.
And because it's called imports and exports,
you can export back the VMs
from EC2 your on-premise environment
if you wanted to.
Now for AWS application discovery service,
well, this is a service
that allows you to gather information
about your on-premise servers and plan a migration.
This is very high level,
but it does give you some server utilization information
and dependency mappings.
And that could be quite helpful
when you want to do a massive migration
from on-premise to the cloud.
Finally, you can track all that migration
using the AWS Migration Hub.
Then we have AWS database migration service or DMS,
which allows you to replicate from on-premise to AWS,
AWS to AWS
or AWS to on-premise for your database.
So this is quite nice because
if you had a MySQL or a Postgres database
running on-premise,
and you wanted to start moving your workload into AWS,
you could use DMS
to replicate that database in the meantime,
and when you're ready,
you can fully transition to using AWS only.
And the nice thing about it is
that they work with various database technologies
that includes Oracle, MySQL, DynamoDB, et cetera,
and allows you to do some really
fancy use cases for example,
migrate data from MySQL into DynamoDB.
And then finally you have
AWS Server Migration Service or SMS.
And this is for incremental replication
of on-premise live servers to AWS.
So you can replicate the volumes directly into AWS.
And this is used for more ongoing type of replication.
Incremental replication.
And this is the last one that I have in my mind
for on-premise migration to AWS.
So at a high level, you may be like,
"Oh, this is a lot of services."
Just remember the names at a high level.
So in the next two on on-premise as possible,
we can do VM import and export for on-premise and EC2,
we can have migration services
such as application Discovery Service,
AWS Migration Hub, Database Migration Service
and Server Migration Service, DMS and SMS.
And just remember those at a high level.
That's it.
Just so you can see if you see the name in the question,
then you're not taken by surprise.
You know that all these things
have to relate to on-premise.
Well, that's it for this short theory lecture,
I will see you in the next lecture.