So there are two use cases
when you move to the cloud.
For example, you wanna start fresh
and you wanna leverage the cloud directly.
In this case, you don't need to do a migration.
But if you have on-premises servers and data centers
and you want to migrate to the cloud,
then you need to plan your migration.
And a way to do this is to plan your migration
using the AWS Application Discovery Service.
So the idea is that you're going to scan your servers,
and going to gather information
about the server utilization data and dependency mapping
which are going to be important for your migrations
so we can understand how to migrate
and what to migrate first.
So there are two types of migration you can do.
One is called the Agentless Discovery using a Connector.
And this gives you information around your virtual machines,
your configuration, your performance history
such as a CPU, memory, and disk usage.
Or you can run an agent
to do an Application Discovery Agent,
and this gives you more updates
and more information from within your virtual machines.
For example, system configuration, performance,
processes are running, and the details
of all the network connections between your systems,
which is good to get your dependency mapping.
Now, all this results data can be viewed
within another service called the AWS Migration Hub.
So this Application Discovery Service
really helps you to map out what you need to move
and how they are interconnected.
But then you actually need to move.
And the simplest way to move from on-premises
to AWS is using the AWS Application Migration Service,
also called MGN.
So this used to be called CloudEndure Migration,
but now it's been replaced.
And the idea is that using
the AWS Application Migration Service, so MGN,
you can do rehosting, also called lift-and-shift solution,
in which you convert your physical, virtual,
or other service on the other clouds to run natively on AWS.
How does that work?
Well, say you have a corporate data center
with OS apps and databases, and they run on disks.
What's going to happen is that you're going to run
the Application Migration Service.
And then the replication agent
that you have to install on your data center
is going to perform a continuous replication of your disks
so that you have, for example, low-cost EC2 instances
and EBS volumes that get this replication of data.
Now, the day you're ready to perform a cut over,
you can actually move from staging to production,
and have a bigger EC2 instance of the size you want,
as well as EBS volumes that match the performance you need.
So the idea is that you replicate data,
and then at some point, you do a cut over.
And that is by far the simplest way of doing it.
So this supports a wide range of platforms,
operating systems, and databases.
And this gives you minimal downtime,
as well as reduced costs
because, well, you don't need to hire complex engineers
to do this.
This is done automatically by this service.
So that's it.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.