So we've learned about
Amazon ElastiCache beforehand,
so let's just do a quick summary.
So ElastiCache is a managed Redis or Memcached for Amazon
so it's a similar offering as RDS,
but this time for caches technology.
So what is a cache?
Well it's an in-memory data store
which gives you sub-millisecond latency
when you want to read data.
So for this, you must provision
an ElastiCache instance type for your cache,
and then you are good to go.
So if you are using Redis, you can have support
for Clustering, Multi AZ, and Read Replicas for sharding,
and you have security provision through IAM.
You can use security groups.
You have KMS at-rest encryption,
and for Redis you have Redis Authentication.
You have the same kind of features as RDS
for backups, snapshots, and point-in-time restore.
You have managed and scheduled maintenance.
And the most important thing
need to remember for the exam
is that if you decide to use Amazon ElastiCache
to perform some caching on top
or combine with an RDS database,
is that to use ElastiCache,
you need to modify your application code
to leverage ElastiCache.
And so if the exam is asking you for a caching solution
that does not require a code change,
then ElastiCache is not a good choice.
Okay?
So the use cases for ElastiCache
are going to be Key/Value store,
when you do frequent read-on-top of your database,
it's good to cache database queries.
Also, if you have session data that needs to be stored
for your users on your website,
ElastiCache is also a very good use case.
And just so you know, you cannot use SQL on ElastiCache.
Okay, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.