So now let's do a summary of Amazon DynamoDB
which appears quite a bit at the exam.
So DynamoDB is a proprietary technology from AWS.
It's a managed serverless
and no SQL database that provides you
out of the box millisecond latency.
You have two capacity modes you need to choose from.
So one of them is the provision capacity
with optional auto scaling, which is great
when you have a smooth type of workload
that increases gradually
over time or decreases gradually over time.
Or you have the on demand capacity mode
where you don't have to provision capacity,
but it scales automatically for you,
which is great if you have very unpredictable workloads
or if you have sudden steep spikes of demand
on your database.
So DynamoDB can replace ElasticCache as a key value store
and it's a great way to, for example, store session data
for your website, combined with a TTL feature
to expire a row after a specific amount of time.
So DynamoDB is highly available.
It is across multiple availability zones by default.
The reads and the writes are fully decoupled
and it's possible for you to have transactions
on top of the DynamoDB tables.
It is possible for you to create a read cache
out of the box that is fully compatible with DynamoDB
which is a DAX cluster, DynamoDB accelerator,
and the particularity of it is
that you get then microsecond read latency.
So look for that in the exam.
In terms of security authentication and authorization,
everything is done through IAM.
You have event processing capability on top of DynamoDB,
so you can enable DynamoDB streams
to stream all the changes happening into your database
and you can have an integration to invoke Lambda
from the DynamoDB stream.
Therefore, Lambda can be invoked
for every single change in your DynamoDB table.
The other option is instead
of standing the data to DynamoDB streams,
you can send the data to Kinesis data streams.
The advantage is that on top of it,
you can use the Kinesis Data Firehose feature,
or you can use any type of integration
that leverages Kinesis data stream.
For example, you could have longer term retention
up to one year on Kinesis data streams.
You have a global table feature on top of the DynamoDB,
which allows you to do active-active replication
across multiple regions.
So anyone can read and write from any region;
this is why it's called active-active.
Now you have two backup options.
The first one is an automated backup.
You need to enable point in time recovery for that
and you can restore your table to a new dynamicDB table
for any point of time up to 35 days.
Or if you want to have longer term retention of backups,
you can enable on-demand backups,
which will also restore to a new table.
Now, you can export your DynamoDB table
to Amazon S3 without using any of the read capacity units
within the Pointing Time recovery windows,
So within 35 days using the export to S3 feature.
And you can also import from S3
without using any right capacity units into a new table.
So DynamoDB, from an exam perspective
anytime you see that you need to rapidly evolve schema
which have a flexible type of database schema
is going to be a great choice.
So the use cases for DynamoDB is when you want a database
and do serverless application development
and your data are small documents, for example,
in the hundreds of kilobytes of size maximum
or when you want a distributed serverless cache.
Okay, so that's it for DynamoDB.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.