So now let's talk about Amazon Timestream
and the name indicates
that it's actually a time series database.
So it's fully managed, it's fast, it's scalable
and it's serverless.
So what is a time series?
Well, it's a bunch of points that have a time
included in them.
So for example, here's a graph by year.
So this is a time series.
Now with Timestream you can automatically
adjust the database up and down to scale capacity
and you can store and analyze trillions of events per day.
The idea is that if you have a time series database
it's going to be much faster and much cheaper
than using relational databases for time series data.
Hence the specificity of having a time series database.
You can do schedule queries.
You can have records with multiple measures
and there is full SQL compatibility.
The recent data will be kept in memory.
And then the historical data is kept
in a cost-optimized storage tier.
As well as, you have time series analytics function
to help you analyze your data and find patterns
in near real time.
This database just like every database on AWS
supports encryption in transit and at rest.
So the use cases for Timestream would be
to have an IoT application,
operational applications, real-time analytics
but everything related to a time series database.
Now in terms of architecture, Timestream is here
and it can receive data from AWS IoT, so internet of things.
Kinesis Data Streams through Lambda can receive data
as well.
Prometheus, Telegraf, there are integrations for that.
Kinesis Data Streams as well through
Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink
can receive data into Amazon Timestream
and Amazon MSK as well through the same process.
And in terms of what can connect to Timestream,
where we can build dashboards using Amazon QuickSight.
We can do machine learning using Amazon SageMaker.
We can do Grafana or because there is a standard
JDBC connection into your database,
any application that is compatible with JDBC
and SQL can leverage Amazon Timestream.
So that's it.
I think for the exam you just need to remember
what Timestream is at a high level
but I want to give you a bit more details as well.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.