So let's have a look now
at the fundamental differences
between IAM roles and resource-based policies.
So for cross accounts,
especially when you want to perform an API call
on an S3 bucket cross account,
you have two options.
You can attach a resource-based policy to a resource,
for example, an S3 bucket policy on an S3 bucket,
or you can decide to use a role
that can actually access the resource.
So let's take an example of these two options.
So this is the example
where the user in Account A can assume a role in Account B,
and that role has the permissions
to access your Amazon S3 buckets.
Or similarly, the user in Account A,
through a bucket policy placed on the Amazon S3 bucket
in Account B,
can access the S3 buckets.
So both these two situations are valid,
but there is a little bit of difference, okay?
The first one is an IAM role
that has access to the S3 bucket.
The second one is the S3 bucket policy that allows the user.
So what's the difference?
When you actually assume a role, okay,
you actually give up all your original permissions,
and you take all the permissions assigned to the role.
So this is very important.
That means that we, for example, assume a role,
and this role can do whatever.
We can now do anything that the role does,
but we cannot use our original permissions.
And so when you use a resource-based policy,
instead, the principal does not assume a role,
and therefore, he does not have to give up his permissions.
So if you take an example of user in Account A,
they need to scan a DynamoDB table in Account A,
and then dump it in an S3 bucket in Account B.
What they can do is we should use a resource-based policy
because this way, we don't have to assume a role,
and we can both scan the DynamoDB table
and write to an S3 bucket in another account.
So resource-based policies are supported
by more and more AWS services and resources over time.
So we have the Amazon S3 buckets, the SNS topics,
the SQS queues, the Lambda functions, and so on.
And the big difference of when this comes into play
is when you use Amazon EventBridge.
So when an EventBridge rule runs,
it's going to need permissions on the targets.
And if your target supports resource-based policies,
for example, Lambda functions, SNS topics,
SQS queues, S3 buckets, or API Gateway,
then it's possible that EventBridge
will just add a resource-based policy on the target
to allow the invocation from the EventBridge rule.
That's one case.
On the other hand,
if the resource doesn't necessarily support
a resource policy,
then EventBridge will use an IAM role
to invoke the target service,
for example, for Kinesis Stream, EC2 Auto Scaling,
System Manager Run Command, ECS task, and so on.
And for example, for Kinesis Data Streams,
as a note, it supports resource-based policies,
but still, EventBridge is going to use an IAM role.
So how do you know which one is going to be used in which?
Well, you need to look at the configuration
of the EventBridge role itself
to see how this is going to work,
and then you will know, okay?
But as a matter of fact, Lambda, SNS, SQS,
S3 buckets are using resource-based policies.
And Kinesis Data Streams, EC2 Auto Scaling,
and so on are using IAM roles.
Even though it's possible
for you to use a resource-based policy
with Kinesis Data Stream,
that's not yet supported by EventBridge.
So all the information you need to know
for the exam is on this slide,
and I know that'll be enough for you at the exam.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.