Let's get into IAM Permission Boundaries.
And so these permission boundaries
are supported for users and roles
and they're not available for groups, so remember this.
And they're an advanced feature
that allow you to define the maximum amount of permissions
an IAM entity can get.
So let's have an example.
We have this IAM permission boundaries.
It looks just like an IAM policy.
So we're saying, allow everything on S3 CloudWatch and EC2.
So we attach this, for example, to an IAM user
and that's its permission boundaries.
That means that it can only do things
within S3 CloudWatch and EC2.
And then you need to specify on top of things
an IAM permission through policy.
And so here, say we attach to the very same user,
allow iam:CreateUser, resource *.
So there is a boundary
and there is an IAM policy with permissions.
What is going to be the results permission in this case?
Well, nothing, no permissions
because the IAM policy
is outside the IAM permission boundary.
Therefore, our user is not allowed to create other IAM users
because that is not in its IAM permission boundary.
So I want to show you
where IAM permission boundaries are created.
So let's go create a user.
I'm going to call the user John,
and then I'm going to give him programmatic access.
Next permissions.
I will not set anything,
and next Tags.
Review, and Create user.
So we have created John
and we're going to set permission boundaries for John.
So imagine John is a developer in our company
and he needs to have certain permissions
but we want to make sure that he has a permission boundary.
So for this, we could assign a policy,
for example, for John,
so if I add permission and I say, "Hey, John,
I'm going to attach to you AdministratorAccess."
It seems like John can do everything right now.
So John is a super user.
But I'm also going to set a permission boundary on John.
And I'm going say, okay, here is your boundary
and this is an advanced feature.
And I'm gonna say the only thing you can do, actually,
John, is to have AmazonS3FullAccess.
And so here, what I've been setting
is a permission boundary for John.
And so through this AWS S3 full access managed policy,
even though John has an administrator access,
when John logs in, the only thing he can do is to access S3
because S3 is its boundary.
So here we've seen that,
even though there is a policy attached to John
that gives him an administrator access,
the boundary is actually going to be more restrictive.
So IAM permission boundaries can be used
in combinations of AWS Organizations SCP.
So if look at this diagram,
we have the effective permissions
to be in the middle of your identity-based policy,
so whatever is attached to your user or your group.
The permission boundary, which by the way,
only applies to a user or a role and not a group.
And your organization SCP,
which applies to every single IAM entity in your account.
So in the middle lies what the users can do.
So we can use permission boundaries for a few use cases.
For example, to delegate responsibilities
to non-administrators within their permission boundaries,
for example to create new IAM users.
Or to allow developers to self assign
and manage their own permissions,
while making sure they can't escalate their privileges,
that means making themselves administrators.
Or for example, restrict one very specific user
inside yours organization
instead of applying an entire SCP to your account
and restricting everyone in your whole account.
So let's have a look at the IAM Policy Evaluation Logic.
Because this diagram basically explains to you
how you are authorized, or not, to do actions within AWS.
And you don't need to know by heart,
but it should make sense to you.
So we can see there's a whole flow,
but at every step, there is an evaluation.
And so we're going to look at Deny evaluation,
we're going to look at Organizations SCP,
Resource-based policy,
Identity-based policy,
IAM permission boundaries,
and then finally, Session policies
to allow or deny a specific IAM action.
So let's have a look in details to see how that works.
So we're going to look at all the possible policies in here.
And if there is an explicit deny,
then we know that it's going to be denied automatically.
Then we look at the organizations SCP,
and is there an allow?
If yes, then go to next step.
If not, then it's a deny because it's an implicit deny.
Then we look at resource-based policy,
for example, that can be applied to S3 buckets.
They can be applied to SQS and so on.
And again, we have a look,
is there a resource-based policy?
If so, is there an allow?
Yes or no?
Then we have identity-based policy.
So we look, again, as whether or not
there's an identity-based policy,
whether or not there's an allow,
and then we deny implicitly or go onto the next step.
Then we look at IAM permission boundaries that we just saw.
And then finally, we look at session policies
that won't go over them, this is more related to SDS.
But what I want you to remember is
that all these things are evaluated
when making a specific IAM action.
And so, only if all these things are allowing
and working together, or not denying specifically,
then you will have a final decision allow,
and you'll be able to do your action.
So it's just to give you a bit more overview
but hopefully you understand better
how security works in AWS.
So let's have a look at this policy
and see what it can do to make it a bit more concrete.
So we have sqs:*, Deny on resource *,
and we have action, sqs:DeleteQueue, Allow on resource *.
So first question is,
can you perform sqs:CreateQueue?
The answer is no, you cannot
because there is a Deny star on SQS,
and CreateQueue belongs to that block
and there's a deny on it,
so it's definitely going to be denied.
Now, can you perform an sqs:DeleteQueue?
So there's a deny on the top part
and there's an allow on the bottom part
and they conflict.
There's a deny and allow.
But what did I just tell you?
I told you that as soon as you have an explicit deny,
then the decision is going to be denied.
So because there is an explicit deny on sqs:*,
and sqs:DeleteQueue is within that sqs:*,
then no matter what, even there's an allow here,
this is going to be denied this action.
So you cannot perform sqs:DeleteQueue,
even though you have allowed it explicitly
in the second block.
So very important to know.
And finally, can you perform ec2:DescribeInstances?
So as we can see, there's nothing on EC2 in this thing.
And this is an IAM policy.
And so, because there is no explicit deny
but also there's no explicit allow,
then you cannot perform ec2:DescribeInstances
with this IAM policy.
All right, hope that makes sense.
So that's it for this lecture.
Hopefully you understand IAM better.
And I will see you in the next lecture.