Hey, so now let's talk
about Microsoft Active Directory and AWS Directory Services.
So in case you don't know what Microsoft AD is,
it is a software that is found on
any Windows Server with AD Domain Services.
And it's a database of objects,
and the objects can be user accounts, computers, printers,
file shares, security groups.
So all your users manage
within your entire Microsoft ecosystem on premise
is going to be managed by Microsoft Active Directory.
And there's going to be a centralized security management.
You can create account, assign permissions, and so on.
And all the objects will be organized into a tree.
And a group of tree is called a forest.
That's just for some terminology.
So let's take an example, we have a domain controller
and we're going to create an account on it.
We're create an account username is John,
and the password is Password.
And the idea is that
all the other Windows machines we have within our network
are going to be connected to the domain controller.
So that's if we're using the John password
on the first machine,
it's going to look it up in the controller and say,
yes, we have that login.
And then, allow you to log in from that machine.
So all these machines are going to be connected
to your domain controller and that allows you
to have the users accessible on any single machine.
So that's the whole idea behind Active Directory
in a very, very high level.
Now we have AWS Directory Services,
which is to provide you
a way to create an Active Directory on AWS.
And we have three flavors on it.
We don't have to do a deep dive on them,
but you have to understand the differences
between these three flavors.
The first one is AWS Manage Microsoft AD
to create your own Active Directory in AWS.
And you can manage users locally
and it supports multi-factor authentication.
The idea is that with this standalone Active Directory,
you can also create a trust connection
with your on-premise AD
where you have your own users there as well.
And what that means is that your AD in here, for example,
can be trusted with the on-premise AD.
So AWS trust the on-premise AD
and on-premise AD trust AWS.
And so that means that if your users
authenticated to the right,
and used an account that is not managed by AWS,
it can go and look up the accounts
into the on-premise Active Directory.
And similarly, if an on-premise directory user goes
and authentic to your on-premise AD using the AWS accounts,
it can be trusted to go and look it up.
So here our users are going to be shared
between our on-premise Active Directory and AWS, okay?
A little bit complicated, I know if you're new to this,
but hopefully it makes sense.
The AD Connector is a little bit different.
This is a direct gateway proxy to redirect to on-premise AD
and it supports MFA if you need multi-factor authentication
and the users are solely managed into the on-premise AD.
So here is the example.
In this example, our AD Connector is just acting as a proxy.
So if the users try to authenticate with our AD Connector
it's going to proxy the request
back to our on-premise AD and look it up.
So the idea here is that
in the first case with Microsoft Managed Microsoft AD,
we have users sitting in AWS Managed AD
and users sitting in on-premise AD.
Whereas with Ad Connector, as the name indicates,
it connects, it proxies
the queries, the connection requests
back to our on-premise Active Directory.
And the only place where we can manage users
is going to be on the on-premise AD.
Finally, you have Simple AD.
And it's an AD-compatible managed directory on AWS.
It doesn't use Microsoft Directory.
And it cannot be joined with a non-premise Active Directory.
So the idea is that if you don't have an on-premise AD
and you need an Active Directory for your AWS Cloud,
then you can have just a Simple AD as a standalone thing.
And the idea here is that using Active Directory
you can create EC2 instances
that are going to be running Windows.
And these Windows instances can join the domain controllers
for your network
and share all the logins, and the credentials, and so on.
So this is why we want to have a directory in AWS
to have a directory closer
to your EC2 instances running Windows.
And hopefully that makes sense.
Now, the exam should has queue
some very, very high level question,
saying we want to proxy our users to on-premise
and therefore you need AD Connector,
or we want to manage our users
on the cloud in AWS and have MFA
and therefore you need AWS Managed AD,
or we just want a Simple AD
and we don't have any on-premise stuff.
In this case, you want a Simple AD.
So now something that you know
is how to integrate the IAM Identity Center
with Active Directory.
So if you connect to an Active Directory
that is managed on your AWS using the directory service
then the integration is out of the box.
You just tell IAM Identity Center
to integrate and connect to your AWS Managed Microsoft AD.
Very simple.
But what if you don't manage
your Active Directory users on the cloud?
What if you have a self-managed directory
for example, on premises?
In that case, you have two ways of connecting
to your self-managed directory.
The first one is what we should call
a two-way trust relationship
using the AWS Managed Microsoft AD.
So you would create a Managed Microsoft AD
from the directory service,
and then you would set up a two-way trust relationship
between your Active Directory,
for example on premises and your Managed AD.
And then you would use the out of the box integration
coming from the IAM Identity Center for single sign-up.
The other option would be to use an AD Connector.
So an AD Connector here would have the role
to of course integrate with IAM Identity Center.
And then you would connect to it
and then it would automatically proxy any kind of request
onto your self-managed directory.
So if you had to choose one or the other,
it will depends on
if you want to also be able to manage users
from within the cloud on Active Directory in the cloud.
And then the first solution may better.
But if you just wanted to proxy API calls
then the second solution could be a fit,
although with a bit more latency.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.