So AWS is starting to push for hybrid cloud.
And what is hybrid cloud?
That means that part of your infrastructure
is going to be on the cloud of AWS.
And part of your infrastructure
is going to stay on-premises.
And this can be due to multiple reasons.
Maybe you have a long cloud migration,
maybe you have security requirements or past requirements,
maybe it's part of your strategy to only leverage a cloud
for elastic workloads,
but to keep a lot of stuff on-premises.
So we have some services that we really like in AWS,
which has Amazon S3,
which is a proprietary storage technology,
which is unlike EFS, which is an NFS compliance file system.
So how would you expose, for example,
the S3 data on-premises and the bridge between this S3
and your on-premises infrastructure
is going to be AWS Storage Gateway.
So if we look at the storage cloud native options on AWS,
we have block storage, which is Amazon EBS
or the EC2 Instance Store.
We have file systems such as Amazon EFS or Amazon FSx,
and we have object-level storage such as Amazon S3
or Amazon Glacier.
So now let's talk about the AWS Storage Gateway.
So very simply, it is a bridge between your on-premises data
and your cloud data.
So you have data on-premises and you're going to bridge it
using a storage gateway to the cloud.
Now that looks simple
but we have different use cases for this.
The first one is to do disaster recovery,
so to back up your on-premise data into the cloud.
Or you can also do backup and restore,
so to do a cloud migration
or to extend your storage from on-premises to the cloud.
And for example, your cloud has colder data
and your on-premises data has more warmer,
more frequently used data.
Also, you can, for example,
instead prefer to have the majority of your data
stored on AWS and use the storage gateway
as an on-premises cache for low-latency file access.
So there are different kind of use cases
and therefore there are different kinds of Storage Gateway
and there are a few of them.
So the first one is the S3 File Gateway,
then we have the FSx File Gateway,
the Volume Gateway, and the Tape Gateway.
I will be explaining all of those in this lecture.
So first we have the Amazon S3 File Gateway.
So we have an S3 bucket
and we can use whatever storage class we want.
For example, S3 Standard, S3 Standard-IA,
S3 One Zone-IA, S3 Intelligent-Tiering,
but not Glacier.
And we want to connect this S3 bucket
to an on-premises application server
but we want to use a standard network file system.
So for this we're going to create an S3 File Gateway
which is going to allow our application server
to use the NFS or the SMB protocol.
And by using this protocols,
behind the scene the S3 File Gateway
is going to translate those requests
into HTTPS requests for your Amazon S3 buckets.
So from an application server perspective,
it looks like it's accessing a normal file share.
But in fact, behind the scenes
it is using an Amazon S3 bucket.
And this is how you expose S3 objects
on two on-premises application servers.
Then if you wanted to archive some of these objects,
you could create a lifecycle policy for your S3 bucket
to transition objects after a while to S3 Glacier
in order to have them archived.
So whatever buckets you configure with your S3 File Gateway
are going to be accessible using the NFS and SMB protocol.
And on top of it, the most recently used data
is cached in the file gateway for rapid access.
So not your entire S3 bucket is on the file gateway
but your most recently files
that are most recently used files.
Okay, so as I said, it supports different storage classes
for your S3 buckets, and you can transition to S3 Glacier
using a lifecycle policy.
Now to access your bucket,
you need to create IAM roles for each file gateway.
And then if you were to use the SMB protocol
because it is more native for Windows file systems,
you have integration with active directory
for user authentication.
So that means that your users can be authentified
with your S3 File Gateway before accessing it
and then therefore accessing your S3 buckets.
So that's the Amazon S3 File Gateway.
Now, similarly, we have the Amazon FSx File Gateway
which provide again native access to Amazon FSx
for Windows File Server.
So we have a Windows File Server FSx
deployed on Amazon FSx File System.
And we want to access from SMB clients
on your corporate data center.
So, you know that, actually,
if you are using Amazon FSx for Windows File Server,
you don't need anything special.
This is already accessible for your on-premises system.
So why would you go ahead
with the trouble of creating an Amazon FSx File Gateway?
Well, the idea is that if you do create the gateway,
you're going to get a local cache
for the frequently access data.
So that means that some very important files
will be cached locally on your corporate data center
and you're going to have low latency access to them.
So this will be the main reason
for you to use the Amazon FSx file gateway
on top of using the Amazon FSx Windows File Server option.
You also have Windows and native compatibility
for your file gateway.
So SMB and TFS and active directory.
And so it's very useful for group file shares
and home directories that you want to expose on-premises.
Next, we have the Volume Gateway.
And this is block storage
using the iSCSI protocol backed by Amazon S3.
And the idea is that you will have your volumes
being backed up by EBS snapshots,
which can in turn helps you restore on-premises volumes
in case you need to.
So you have two types of Volume Gateway.
You have the Cached volumes to get low latency access
to the most recent data
or stored volume where the entire data set is on-premises
and there is a scheduled backup to Amazon S3.
So here our application server needs to be backed up.
And so using this protocol,
we are going to get a Volume Gateway
and the Volume Gateway will create Amazon EBS snapshots
backed by Amazon S3.
So the same logic here,
but here the goal of the Volume Gateway really
is to back up your volumes of your on-premises servers.
Tape Gateway is that if you have some companies
that have like, for example, a tape backup system
using physical tapes,
then with the Tape Gateway, you do the same process
but the tapes are going to be backed up in the cloud.
And so this virtual tape library or VTL
is going to be backed by Amazon S3 and Glacier.
You're going to back up existing data
using tape-based process and using the iSCSI interface.
And then this is going to work
with leading backup software vendors.
So diagram you can expect.
The corporate data center has a backup server,
which is tape-based.
The Tape Gateway will do the interface into the cloud
by storing the tapes into Amazon S3 or in Amazon Glacier.
Finally, as you can see in all these diagrams from before,
the gateway has to be installed
on your corporate data center,
it has to run within your corporate data center.
But sometimes you do not have virtual servers
to run this additional gateway.
So an option for you is to leverage hardware from AWS.
So it's called Storage Gateway Hardware Appliance.
So if you don't have virtualization on-premises,
you can use a Storage Gateway Hardware Appliance
and you can order it literally on amazon.com.
And then once you install this hardware appliance
for this mini server into your infrastructure,
then you can set it up as a File Gateway,
a Volume Gateway or a Tape Gateway.
And this is really something physical you have to install
and will have the enough CPU, memory, network
and SSD cache resources to function correctly.
So this is very helpful, for example,
for daily NFS backups in small data centers
where you don't have virtualization available.
So let's try to summarize the Storage Gateway service.
So we have on-premises where we deploy a storage gateway VM
or a hardware appliance,
then we have the Storage Gateway service,
and then we have the cloud of AWS.
So if we want to have a file gateway with a local cache,
this is the use case where we have a user group file share
and we want to access it over the NFS or the SMB protocol.
Option number one,
we connect this into directly an S3 file gateway.
So therefore your data is going to be backed by Amazon S3.
And that includes many storage tiers except Glacier
and Glacier Deep Archive.
But we can create a lifecycle policy
to send this into any storage class Amazon S3,
including S3 Glacier.
If we were to instead use an FSx file gateway
then we would send the data into Amazon FSx
for Windows File Server,
which is automatically backed up
to Amazon S3 once in a while.
Now the other use case for a volume gateway
is to have application servers mount volumes
over the iSCSI protocol.
So what we do is that this volume gateway
is going to be linked through Storage Gateway to Amazon S3.
So this is where the data of your volume is going to be.
And then Amazon S3, this data can be transformed
into AWS EBS volumes for really being restored on AWS.
Next, we have your backup applications
connecting over the iSCSI VTL protocol to a tape gateway.
And the Tape gateway is connected to Amazon S3
as a tape library.
And then we can transition these tapes
into the Glacier and Glacier Deep Archive tier
to create an archive of your tapes.
So hopefully that summarizes everything
we've seen in this lecture
and you understand it.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.