So here is a quick hands-on
on the Storage Gateway but you don't need to know
how to configure one for the exam,
just you need to know
the different kinds of offerings you have.
And so, that's what I'm going to show you in this console.
So, let's create a gateway.
As you can see, we have four different kinds of gateways,
we can have Amazon S3 File Gateway, FSx File Gateway,
Volume gateway, and Tape gateway.
So, the Amazon S3 File Gateway
is to have a local cache for Amazon S3 on-premises
with your most recently used data
so this is the whole purpose of a file gateway.
And if you click on Next,
you can look at the Platform options.
So, you can either host this
on some on-premises virtualization platforms,
such as VMware or Hyper-V, or Linux KVM,
or you can host it directly on Amazon EC2,
but it's going to remove someone as the benefits
for caching.
Or you can have your own hardware appliance
that you can order directly from here.
And then once you hook that hardware appliance
into your data center,
you'll be running a file gateway for you,
which is quite handy.
So once you do set up for example in EC2 instance,
then you click on Next
and you would configure the gateway, which is out of scope.
I just want to show you the main options.
So the Amazon FSx File Gateway is the same as free,
but this time you want to cache
the windows file server directly on-premises.
And again, we have different platform options,
including a hardware appliance, if we wanted to.
And then we would configure the FSx file gateway properly.
The Volume gateway is very interesting
because we have two options.
And that's what I want to show you in this hands-on.
So we have the cached volume,
which is going to give you low-latency access
to your most recently used data for your volumes
or storage volume, which is on-premise data
with scheduled upside backups.
So two very different use cases for Volume gateway,
and you need to know the differences going into the exam.
So the Volume gateway is going to use you block storage
in Amazon S3 and point-in-time backups as EBS snapshots,
so that they are actually volumes.
And finally, the tape gateway
is allowing you to backup your data into Amazon S3
and archive it into Glacier
using your existing tape based processes,
because it uses the same protocol that you're used to
with your VTL.
So that's it for your different storage gateways.
I hope you liked it, I hope it makes sense
and I will see you in the next session.