Now let's talk about the AWS transfer family.
So the idea is that you want to send data in and out
of Amazon S3 or EFS
but you don't want to use the S3 APIs.
You don't want to use the EFS network file system.
You just want to use the FTP protocol.
In this case,
you need to use the transfer family service from AWS.
So it supports three kinds of protocols.
It supports AWS transfer for FTP.
So the file transfer protocol, FTP.
FTPS, which is the file transfer protocol over SSL,
so encrypted form.
Or SFTP, which is a secure file transfer protocol.
Now you don't want you to be an expert on those.
Just know that FTP is unencrypted
whereas FTPS and SFTP are encrypted in flight.
Now, the idea is that using the FTP protocol,
you can upload to S3 or EFS.
The transfer family is fully managed infrastructure.
It's scalable, reliable, and highly available.
So you manage at all that capability.
And in terms of pricing, you're going to pay
per provision end points per hour, plus a fee per gigabytes
of data transferred in and out of the transfer family.
You can store and manage a user's credentials
for that service within the service.
Or you can also integrate
with existing authentication system,
such as Microsoft Active Directory, LDAP,
Okta, Amazon Cognito or any custom source.
The usage of this is obviously to have an FTP interface
into Amazon S3 or EFS.
So as to share files, to share public datasets,
to do CRM, ERP, et cetera, et cetera.
So just the diagram for you to understand.
The transfer family has three flavors
and the users can access directly using the end points
of the FTP or optional, you can use a GNS called route 53
to provide your own the host name into the FTP service.
And then the FTP service thus so the transfer
for FTP service will have an IAM role
that will be assumed to send or read through the files from
Amazon S3 or Amazon EFS.
And this is done transparently.
You don't have to set any many things up.
And finally,
if you wanted to secure the transfer family services
then you could authenticate your users
using an external authentication system
such as Active Directory, LDAP
or all the things I've just said in the previous slide.
Okay.
So let's say, just that you know,
this feature as a high level, I hope you liked it.
and I will see you in the next lecture.