So there are lots of storage options on the AWS,
all with their different use cases.
And I wanted to give you a short lecture
to just summarize what we've seen
and then understand what are the differences.
So we've seen Amazon S3.
It is for Object Storage
And we've seen it's a very specific API, okay?
But it's great for anything related to AWS.
And then should we want to archive these objects,
we can use the S3 Glacier service.
Now, if we want to attach storage to one EC2 instance
at a time, we could use EBS volumes.
And we saw EBS volumes have a little feature
called multitask for the IO1 and IO2 volumes.
And within EBS,
we saw that they were different kinds of volumes.
We had the GP3 volumes,
we had the IO2 volumes,
and so on.
If we wanted to get super high performance,
physical storage for your EC2 instance with very high IOPS.
But if this is not a network storage,
if this is the physical storage,
then we need to use the EC2 Instance Storage.
Now, if we wanted to get a Network File System
for Linux instances,
that could be mounted across multiple availability zones
with the POSIX filesystem,
then we should use the Amazon EFS service.
Now, if you wanted to have a Windows server file system
we need to use the Amazon FSx for Windows service.
If you wanted to get
very High Performance Computing Linux file system
that's compatible with a Lustre client,
then we need to use FSx for Lustre.
If you wanted to get
super High Operating System Compatibility
for a network file system,
we could use the FSx NetApp ONTAP file system.
And you want to get a managed ZFS file system,
we could use FSx for OpenZFS.
So we've seen all the flavors.
Now we have other ways to bridge storage
between on premises and AWS,
we have the Storage Gateway.
So we sell the different types of storage gateway.
We have the S3 and the FSx File Gateway
to synchronize files between on premises
and Amazon S3 or Amazon FSx.
We have the Volume Gateway to mount volumes
onto your on premises servers
but have them backed up in the cloud.
And we have the Tape Gateway to just do backups
in the tape form.
If you wanted to have a FTP, FTPS, or SFTP interface
on top of Amazon S3 or Amazon EFS,
then you would use the AWS Transfer Family.
And if you wanted to synchronize data on the schedule
from on premises to AWS, or AWS to AWS,
you would use the DataSync service.
And finally,
if you don't have the network capacity to move data,
but you want to move large amount of data physically,
then you would order a Snowcone, a Snowball,
or a Snowmobile type of device
into on premises and then move it to the cloud.
With the particularity that Snowcone comes
with a data sync agent bundled in it already.
And also I would not pass Databases
so you can store it on Databases
but there are sort of very specific workloads
usually need indexing and querying
and we'll have a whole section dedicated
to understanding the right Database.
So hopefully when you see these storage,
you understand their differences
and you'll be able to understand
which one is the right one at the exam.
I know this is a lot,
but this is part of your role
as a Solutions Architect on AWS
to understand the differences between all the storage
and choose the right one for the right architecture.
Okay. That's it.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.