Okay, so now let's talk about Redshift.
So Redshift is a database that's based on PostgreSQL,
but it's not used for online transaction processing.
Instead it's OLAP. So it's online analytical processing.
So it's used for analytics and data warehousing.
So any type of computations on your data,
Redshift is a good place to do it.
So it gives you 10 times better performance
than other data warehouses, and it has big scale.
You can scale to petabytes of data.
The data is going to be stored as a column instead of a row.
And so that's what makes it so good at analytics
because it's able to quickly add all the data
in a specific column.
And on top of it, it has a parallel query engine
to speed up any queries you may have.
You have two modes of starting a Redshift cluster.
You can do a provision cluster or a serverless cluster.
You also use a SQL interface for performing the queries.
And you have BI tools such as Amazon Quicksight
or Tableau that have direct integration with it.
So if you were to compare Redshift versus Athena, well,
Redshift has faster queries, faster joins
and aggregations thanks to indexes,
but you need to of course provision a whole cluster,
whereas Athena is serverless only
and all your data lives in S3.
So talking about this Redshift cluster,
so you have the concept of a leader node and a compute node.
So the leader node is for query planning
and results aggregation,
whereas the compute nodes in the Redshift cluster is going
to be to perform actually the queries
and to send the results to the leader.
When you are in provision mode, you have access
to choosing the instant types in advance,
and you can reserve instances if you wanted
to do cost savings.
But if you are in serverless mode,
you just leave everything in the hands of AWS
and you don't manage any type of cluster or node.
So list or summarize it, the leader node has access
to the compute nodes
and it makes it a whole Redshift cluster.
And so when you send a query, for example,
select count from My_TABLE GROUP BY by na na na.
The leader node is going to plan the query, send it
to the compute nodes, you're going to execute the query
and then send back the results to the leader node.
And that's the architecture of Redshift.
So let's talk about Snapshots and DR.
So Redshift is single AZ for most clusters,
but now there's a multi AZ mode for some cluster types.
And so if you have multi AZ, then you're good
for disaster recovery.
But if you have single AZ, then to do disaster recovery,
you need to use snapshots.
So snapshots are point in time backups of a cluster,
and they will be stored internally in Amazon S3,
and they are incremental only
where that has changed will be saved,
and that will save you a lot of space, obviously.
You can restore a snapshot into a new Redshift cluster,
and you have two modes for snapshots.
You can take them manually
or you can take them in an automated way.
So if you automate it, every eight hours is going
to be a snapshot or every five gigabytes on the schedule.
And then you can set the retention
for your automated snapshots,
or you wanna do a manual snapshot.
The snapshot is going to be retained
until you delete it manually.
And then a really, really cool feature of Redshift is
that you can configure Redshift
to automatically copy snapshots, whether they're automated
or manual of the cluster into another AWS region,
hence giving you a disaster recovery strategy.
So let's take this Redshift cluster, your original cluster,
and then we have another region.
So we're going to take snapshots.
They're going to be automatically copied
into your new region,
and from there you can restore a new Redshift cluster
from that copied snapshots.
Now let's talk about how we ingest data into Redshift.
So we have three ways I'm going to describe to you.
The first one is to use Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose.
So we have Firehose that will be receiving data
from different sources,
and then it will send it into Redshift.
And to do so, it will first write the data
into an Amazon S3 bucket, and then Kinesis Data Firehose
will issue automatically an S3 copy command
to load the data into Redshift.
Now, how does this copy come in work?
We can also use it manually.
So you would load data into S3,
and then you would issue a copy command directly
from Redshift to copy data
from an S3 bucket using an IAM role
into your Amazon Redshift cluster.
And as we've seen, there are two ways of doing so.
You might go through the internet
because your S3 buckets are public through the internet.
I mean, they're not public,
but they're connected to the internet.
And so therefore, you're going to have your data flow
through the internet back into your Redshift cluster.
And this is without enhanced VPC routing.
But if you wanted all your network
to remain private into your virtual private cloud,
then you can enable enhance VPC routing
to have all the data flow through the VPC entirely.
And finally, if you wanted
to insert data using the JDBC driver
into the Redshift cluster, you could do so as well.
So for example, if you have an application, an easy
to instance that needs to write data
into your Redshift cluster,
you would need to use this method.
And in that case, it is much better to write large batches
of data into Amazon Redshift instead of one row at a time,
which would be truly inefficient for this type of database.
So a cool feature of Redshift is Redshift Spectrum.
The ideas that you would have data in Amazon S3
and you want to analyze it using Redshift,
but you don't want to load it into Redshift first.
And on top of it, you want
to use a lot more processing power.
So you use Redshift Spectrum
and you must have a Redshift cluster already available
to start the query.
And then once you start the query,
the query will then be submitted to thousand
of Redshift Spectrum nodes
that will perform the query onto your data in S3.
So let's go for an example.
You have your Redshift cluster with a leader node
and a bunch of compute nodes as we've seen,
and the data you want to analyze is in Amazon S3.
So in this case, we're going to run a query
onto our cluster, as we can see.
What we want to do is that the table we want
to query is living in S3.
So we have from S3 dot and whatever you want.
In that case, Spectrum will launch automatically.
And so the query is going to be submitted to thousands
of Redshift Spectrum nodes who are going
to read the data from Amazon S3
and perform some aggregations.
And when they're done, they're going
to send back the results
into your own Amazon Redshift cluster,
and then you will get back into whoever initiated the query.
But with this feature,
we can leverage a lot more processing power
from a shift than the one we have provisioned
into our cluster in the first place,
loading the data from Amazon S3 into Redshift.
So that's it for Amazon Redshift.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.