So now, let's talk about the Amazon OpenSearch Service.
An Amazon OpenSearch is a successor
to something you may have heard before called,
Amazon ElasticSearch.
So the name change was due to some licensing issues.
So in DynamoDB, just to do a comparison,
you can only query the data by primary key
or if you have indexes on your database.
But with OpenSearch, you can actually,
as the name indicates, search any fields,
even for partial matches.
So it's very common to use OpenSearch to provide search
to your application.
And so you would use OpenSearch
as a compliment to another database.
So OpenSearch can be used for search,
but also as the name doesn't indicate,
you can also do analytic queries on top of OpenSearch.
So you have two modes to provision an OpenSearch Cluster.
Either you use the managed cluster option
and then actual physical instances will be provisioned
for you and you will see them.
Or you can go the serverless route
and have a serverless cluster,
where everything from scaling to operations
is handled by AWS.
And OpenSearch has its own query language,
it does not natively support SQL,
but you can enable SQL compatibility via a plugin.
So you can ingest data from different places,
such as Kinesis Data Firehose, IoT, CloudWatch Logs,
or any of your custom-built application.
You have security provided
through integration with Cognito, IAM,
you get at rest encryption and in-flight encryption.
And as I said, you can do analytics
on top of the OpenSearch Service,
so you can use something called OpenSearch Dashboards
to create visualizations on top of your OpenSearch Data.
So here are some common patterns to use OpenSearch.
So you would have DynamoDB and it will contain your data.
This is where your users will insert
and delete and update data.
And then you send all the streams in a DynamoDB Stream,
which is then picked up by a Lambda Function.
And that Lambda Function will insert the data
into Amazon OpenSearch in real time.
And through this process,
what happens that your application
now has the ability to search for a specific item.
For example, to do a partial search with the item name
and then find the item ID out of it.
And then once the item ID is obtained,
then it will call DynamoDB to actually retrieve
the full item from your DynamoDB Table.
So that's a common pattern in which OpenSearch
provides the search capability,
whereas your main source of data still remains
your DynamoDB Table.
There's also other ways you can ingest CloudWatch Logs
into OpenSearch.
So the first one is to use what's called
a CloudWatch Log Subscription Filter,
sending data in real time to a Lambda Function
that is managed by AWS.
And then the Lambda Function in real time
sends all the data into Amazon OpenSearch.
Or you can also use a CloudWatch Logs
and then Subscription Filter.
But this time Kinesis Data Firehose
can read it from the Subscription Filter.
And then near real time,
because this is Data Firehose,
data will be inserted in Amazon OpenSearch.
Other patterns are on Kinesis,
so to send Kinesis Data Streams into Amazon OpenSearch,
you have two strategies.
The first one is to use Kinesis Data Firehose.
This is a near real time again type of service.
You can optionally do some data transformation,
using a Lambda Function and then send data
into Amazon OpenSearch.
Or you can use Kinesis Data Streams again,
but this time, you would create a Lambda Function
that would read the data stream in real time.
And then you would write custom code
to have the Lambda Function write to Amazon OpenSearch
in real time.
So all these patterns are valid,
and now you know pretty much all the possible architectures
for using Amazon OpenSearch.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.