So now let's talk about AWS Glue.
So Glue is a managed extract, transform and load service,
also called commonly ETL service.
It's very useful
to prepare and transform data for analytics.
So this is a fully serverless service
and you're just going to submit whatever you want
and it will achieve it, for example, say you had data
in an S3 bucket or an Amazon RDS database and you wanted
to load this into a Redshift data warehouse.
So you could extract it using Glue,
then you would transform it if need be to maybe
filter some data or add some columns and so on,
whatever you want, and then you would load
the final output data into a Redshift data warehouse.
So all of this happened from within the Glue ETL service.
You just have to write some code,
launch your ETL job, and off you go.
So that's one example.
Another example that's gonna come up in the exam
is how to convert data into the Parquet format.
So why would we do this?
Because, well, the Parquet format is a columnar data format
and therefore it is much better when in use,
for example, with services like Athena.
So say for example that you are doing
inserts into your S3 buckets
and then these files are in the CSV formats.
Then you would use the Glue ETL service to import the CSV
and convert it into a Parquet format
from within the Glue service.
Then you would send it into an output S3 bucket.
And when in Parquet format, then Amazon Athena
is going to analyze this file in a much better fashion.
So the other thing you can do to automate
this entire process is that anytime a file
is inserted into the S3 bucket, then you can send
events notifications to a Lambda function,
which will then trigger a Glue ETL job.
But you could replace the Lambda function
with EventBridge as well.
This would work as an alternative.
Okay, so there's another feature of Glue
called the Glue Data Catalog, which is to catalog data sets.
So the Glue Data Catalog will run Glue data crawlers
and they will be connected to various data sources
such as Amazon S3, Amazon RDS, Amazon DynamoDB,
or a compatible JDBC database
that you own on premises, for example.
So the Glue Data Catalog is going to crawl these databases
and is going to write all the metadata of your tables,
of your columns, of your data types and so on,
into the Glue Data Catalog.
And so it will have all the databases, the tables,
and the metadata, and that will be leveraged
by the Glue jobs to perform ETF.
Now also, when you use Amazon Athena behind the scenes
to do the data discovery and the schema discovery,
Amazon Athena is going to be leveraging
the AWS Glue Data Catalog.
So will Amazon Retro Spectrum and so will Amazon EMRs.
So as you can see, the Glue Data Catalog service
is central to many other AWS services.
So other features that can appear at the exam on Glue
and that you should know at a high level.
The first one is Glue Job Bookmarks.
And so this is to prevent you from reprocessing all data
in case you run a new ETL job.
So this is very important and it can come up in the exam.
You have Glue Data Brew, which is used
to clean and normalize data using pre-built transformation.
You have Glue Studio, which is a GUI
to create, run, and monitor ETL jobs in Glue.
And then you have Glue Streaming ETL, and it's actually
built on top of Apache Spark Structured Streaming,
and instead of running ETL jobs, as you know, batch jobs
you can run them as streaming jobs.
And so therefore you can read data
using Glue Streaming ETL from Kinesis Data Streams
or Kafka or MSK as we'll see, which is managed Kafka on AWS.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.