Now let's talk
about the Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink.
It used to be called Kinesis Data Analytics
for Apache Flink, but since then it has been renamed
to just Managed Service for Apache Flink.
So Flink, what is Flink?
Well, it's a framework, and usually use the Java, SQL,
or Scala languages.
So it's a framework used for processing data streams
in real time.
So you have Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink
on the right hand side,
and then you can read data from Kinesis Data Streams,
or even Amazon MSK, which is Apache Kafka,
which is also a service for real-time data streams.
But it's not an AWS service, it's a managed service
for something called Apache Kafka.
All right, so you can,
thanks to the Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink,
you can run any Apache Flink application
on the managed cluster on AWS.
That means that AWS is going to provision for you
the compute resources,
is going to give you access to parallel computation
and automatic scaling.
On top of it,
AWS is going to manage your application backups,
which are going to be implemented
as checkpoints and snapshots.
And then you can use any sort
of Apache Flink supported programming features
to transform your data.
So you're really free around the type
of transformations you want to do on your streams.
And as you should know, Flink can read from, yes,
Kinesis Data Streams,
but it cannot read from Amazon Data Firehose,
and that could be an exam trick.
All right, so that's all you should know
for Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink.
Remember, it's only used for processing data streams.
And that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.