Okay, so, now let's talk
about another architecture for Big Data Ingestion Pipeline.
So, ideally, we want the application ingestion pipeline
to be fully serverless, fully managed by AWS,
and we want to collect data in real time,
we want to transform the data,
we want to query the transformed data using SQL,
and the reports we create using these queries,
maybe they should be stored in S3,
and then we want to load that data into a data warehouse
and create dashboards on it.
So, overall, you know,
the usual big data problems of ingestion,
collection, transformations, querying, and analysis.
Okay, so how do we do this?
And there's some technologies,
we may not have seen them directly in this course,
but that's okay,
I'll just introduce them to you in this pipeline
because they really help.
So, IoT devices,
so let's assume that the producers are data are IoT devices?
And so there is this really cool services
in Amazon Cloud services and it's called IoT Core.
And IoT Core helps you manage these IoT devices.
So remember this, if you go into the exam.
Now, these devices can send data in real time to IoT Core
and IoT Core directly into a Kinesis data stream.
So data stream for Kinesis, remember it allows us
to basically pipe big data in real time,
very fast into this Kinesis service.
Now, Kinesis can be talking to Kinesis data Firehose,
and Firehose allows us to, for example, every one minute
put and offload our data into an Amazon S3 bucket
and that will be an ingestion bucket.
So here, what we've done here is
that we've just had a whole pipeline to get a lot
of data from a lot of devices in real time
and put it every one minute into an S3 bucket.
On top of it,
it's possible for us to cleanse
or really quickly transform the data
using an AWS Lambda function that is directly linked
to Kenesis Data Firehose.
Okay, so now we have that ingestion bucket,
what can we do with it?
Well, for example,
we can trigger an SQS topic,
an SQS Queue, sorry, and it's optional.
And maybe the SQS Queue can trigger AWS Lambda function.
I say optional because Lambda can be directly triggered
by our S3 bucket,
but I just wanted to show you the possibility
of invoking SQS through that slide.
Okay, so Lambda, what we'll do, well Lambda will trigger
an Amazon Athena SQL query.
And this Athena query will pull data
from the ingestion bucket
and we'll do an SQL query that's all serverless.
And the outputs
of this serverless query will go into a reporting bucket,
maybe again in Amazon S3 B is different bucket.
Okay, so from this we have the data it's being reported on,
it's being cleansed and analyzed.
We can either directly visualize it using QuickSight.
So QuickSight is a way for us
to visualize our data into an Amazon S3 bucket,
or we can load the data into a proper data warehouse
for analytics, such as Amazon Redshift.
And so this Redshift data warehouse can also serve
as an endpoint for QuickSight.
But this shows you overall
what you can expect in data ingestion pipeline
at a high level,
including real-time ingestion, transformation,
serverless Lambda, and some data warehousing using Redshift
and visualization using QuickSight.
So let's discuss about the pipeline.
IoT Core allows you
to harvest many data from many IoT devices.
Kinesis is great for real-time data connection,
and Firehose helps you with data delivery
to S3 in near real time.
So one minute is the lowest frequency you can choose.
Lambda can help Firehose with data transformation,
and then Amazon S3 can trigger notifications
to SQS, SNS or Lambda.
Lambda can subscribe to SQS,
but we could have, as I said, connected S3 to Lambda.
And Athena is a serverless SQL service
and we can store the results
of Athena directly back into S3.
And the reporting buckets contain analyzed data
and we can use reporting tools such as QuickSight
for visualization or Redshift
if you want to do more analytics on it.
So that's it for a big data ingestion pipeline,
but at a high level
from a solution architecture perspective.
It's really good to know how all these things work.
I hope you like this and I will see you in the next lecture.