So, let's practice Amazon SQS.
So we are going to go into the SQS console
and then create a queue.
Now as we can see, we have two types of queue
we can set up in SQS.
We have the standard queue and the FIFO queue.
And I'm going to use standard
and the name is going to be Demo Queue.
We'll see FIFO later on.
For configuration, all these things we're going to see
in future lectures
so visibility timeout, delivery delay, the wait time,
the retention period, we're going to use four days
and the max message size is going to be 256 kilobytes
which is a max allowed in SQS.
For encryption, we have several encryption options
so we can disable encryption for our queue altogether
but by default we enable it with an Amazon SQS key.
It's called SSE-SQS type of encryption
which is similar to what we have in Amazon S3 with SSE-S3.
So that's one option for server side encryption.
The other one is to use KMS.
And this is where we have to choose the customer master key.
So we can choose the default CMK of AWS
called the alias/AWS/SQS
and then we can define a data key reuse period
that could be five minutes, for example.
This is to limit the number of API calls made in two KMS.
But this is not very important
so let's keep the encryption as Amazon SQS key,
SSE-SQS.
All right.
Next we have an access policy.
And this access policy can be defined
using these prompts right here.
So we can say, 'Hey, who can access this queue well?'
Only the queue owner can send messages
or maybe I wanna specify a list of accounts,
users and roles and then who can receive, again.
Is it just me, the queue owner
or specified accounts, users and roles?
And this will generate a json document out of it
and this json document, as you can see,
looks very similar to what we had in Amazon S3
with Amazon S3 Bucket policy.
So this is a resource policy for SQS
and it works very very similarly.
Now for the redrive and the dead-letter queue,
we'll see this later on so right now, we're good.
Let's go ahead and create our queue.
And now the queue is successfully created
so we can go ahead and send and receive messages from it.
So we get a lot of different panels in this UI
but what we want to be doing is
to go to the top right-hand side
and click on send and receive messages.
So here is a facility for us to send messages
and then at the bottom, to receive them.
So as we can see right now in the queue,
we have zero messages available.
But if I enter 'hello world!' in the message body
and then send the message.
As you can see, the message is sent
and is ready to be received.
Now we have a messages available one,
and so in here, as soon as I click on pull for messages,
the messages will appear.
So let's have a look.
I click on pull for messages
and yes, we did receive that message right here.
As we can see, we have a message id.
And if you want to look at the content of the message,
I click on the message details
and I can have some information.
So there's a lot of metadata around that message.
For example, the hash of the message, who sent it,
how many times were received so just one time right now
because this is the first time we process this message,
the size in bytes.
And if we go and want to receive the body itself,
we can see that whatever has sent before 'hello world!'
has in it up right here in the message that has just read.
If we created attributes for the message,
there was a message attributes panel that we didn't look at,
we could create key values and read them from here as well.
So very simple, what you would expect
when you send a message and then read it,
you get the exact same message.
But we have decoupled
because a producer has sent some information
and a consumer has received that information.
Now we can see that the message has been received twice
because we didn't process it in enough time.
So after 30 seconds, the message went back into the queue
and we received it again.
So if I pull for messages,
now the message receive count is three.
So it has been read yet again another time.
So to be done with this message,
because say we've processed this 'hello world!' Message,
I'm going to click on it
and then I'm going to click on delete.
And by deleting the message from the queue,
we have signaled to the SQS queue
that the message has been successfully processed
and therefore we have zero messages available in the queue.
And if we pull again,
we will not receive the same message again
because we have deleted it.
So you start seeing the power of queues.
We could go ahead and send many times different messages,
hello world and so on, and you can just play with it
and this is how you would set message attributes
but this is out of scope for the exam.
And here you would receive these messages
and you can receive many messages at time.
So if we send 'hello world', we'll send that message again
and 'hello world 2' for example and send that message
and 'hello world 3',
whatever you want really in that message.
As we can see, as soon as I refresh this window,
we can see that the number of messages available is three.
And so if I pull for messages,
I will get three messages available in here to be processed.
And again, you can take them all
and delete them to signal to SQS
that they have been processed.
So fairly easy.
But you've seen the power of producers and consumers.
Now, back in the queue,
just a few options as well we can see out.
So we can edit this queue to edit all the configurations
that we've seen from before or you can purge the queue.
This will delete all the messages in the queue.
And so to delete all the messages,
you just need to type purge,
and it will go ahead and remove everything
which is very helpful when you do developments.
But I don't think you should do this in production.
And then you get some information around monitoring
for example here, which gives you some information around
how many messages are in the queue,
what's the approximate age of the oldest message,
which could be another way to scale your SQS Queue
if you have an auto-scaling group reading from it,
and so on.
And finally, access policy,
which is who can access the queue and how;
encryption, which is the service side encryption we defined
for our SQS queue.
So for example, we're using SSE-SQS right now
as our encryption scheme, but we can edit it.
And finally, the dead-letter redrive status
which is relevant if you set up a dead letter queue.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.