So let's go ahead
and discuss long polling in Amazon SQS.
So the idea that your consumer,
that is requesting messages from the queue,
and it can wait for the messages to arrive,
if, when you do a request,
there are no messages for now in the queue.
This is called long polling.
So you have a queue
and then your consumer is going to poll the queue,
but the consumer can wait for a message to arrive.
So a message is going to arrive.
And then when, as soon as the message arrives,
it's going to be sent to the consumer.
So the idea is that with the long polling,
your consumer is going to decrease the number of API calls,
because they are long API calls.
Your consumer is asking SQS Queue maybe
for 10 seconds for a message.
And also, while you have less API calls,
you're going to also reduce the latency of your application.
Why?
Well, because as soon as a message is received by SQS,
it is going to be sent to the consumer.
And so therefore your consumer will receive your messages
with the least amount of lag.
So the long polling can be set anywhere between one second
to 20 seconds, and obviously, the longer you wait,
the more efficient you're going to do
and the less API calls you're going to do to SQS.
So, a wait time of 20 seconds may be preferable.
So overall you should prefer long polling to short polling,
and you can enable this at the queue level
or at the API level using the WaitTimeSeconds parameters.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.