So now let's talk
about Amazon's SQS FIFO queues.
So FIFO means first in, first out,
and it corresponds to the ordering of messages in the queue.
That means that when you have a producer
that send messages in a specific order,
then one, two, three, four,
then the consumer's polling messages
from your SQS FIFO queue
is going to read these messages in the same order.
So this is a guarantee of the FIFO queue
but this is not true for just a regular SQS queue.
Messages can be received out of order.
So because you have this ordering guarantee,
you have limits on throughput,
about 300 messages per second without batching,
and 3,000 messages per second with batching.
FIFO queue also have the ability
to do something called exactly-once send.
That means that any duplicates can be removed directly
at the queue level.
For this, you're just going to provide
on every message you send a deduplication ID.
And if this ID is seen twice
in the time range of five minutes,
then duplicates are going to be removed.
So this is a very handy thing
if you want to make sure you have no duplicates
within five minutes.
The messages are going to be processed in order
by the consumer and the ordering guarantee
is at the message group ID level.
So you need to send a message group ID
every time you send a message to Amazon SQS FIFO queue,
and then all the messages are going to be in order
for that specific group ID.
So that's it.
Now let's go in the console to see
how the FIFO queue work.
So let's go and create a queue,
and I will create a FIFO queue.
So as you can see, it's first-in-first-out delivery
and the message ordering is preserved.
Okay, so I will name it DemoQueue.fifo.
And you have to end it with .fifo,
otherwise you will not have the ability
to create this queue.
It has to end with .fifo.
Now, if we look at the configuration,
it looks very similar to before,
but we have one more setting
called content-based deduplication.
This is to deduplicate the messages
if the same is sent twice
in a very small five-minute window.
Access policy will be left the same,
encryption and so on will be left the same.
So I'll create this queue.
And now if I go to send and receive messages,
we can have a look at the message body.
We can say Hello World 1,
and then I will have to specify a message group ID.
I'll call this one demo,
and we'll use the same message group ID all along this demo.
So demo is sent and a deduplication ID, excuse me,
I will say it's my message number one.
So I'll say ID one, send this message.
I'll do Hellow World 2, the same message group ID,
and I will say deduplication ID two.
And then message the third one.
And I will say three in here, and finally the fourth one,
and I will say four.
Okay.
So now the messages have been sent
and they're ready to be received.
And so we have four messages available,
and if I pull four messages, we look at all the messages,
and if I look at this one, it's actually in the wrong order.
So if I look at the bottom one, which is the first one,
it says Hello World 1.
Then if I look at the second message,
I have Hello World 2.
The third message, I have Hello World 3,
and the fourth message, I will have Hello World 4.
So this is a guarantee that you get thanks to FIFO queues.
Then you go ahead and delete these messages and you're done.
So that's it, I hope that was helpful
and I will see you in the next lecture.