Now let's talk about
the SNS plus SQS fan-out pattern.
The idea is that you want a message
to be sent to multiple SQS queues,
but if you send them individually to every SQS queue,
there can be problems associated with it.
For example, if your application crashes in between,
if there are delivery failures,
or if you add more SQS queues down the road.
Therefore we want to use the fan-out pattern.
The idea is that you're going to push once an SNS topic
and then you're going to subscribe as many SQS queues
as you want to the SNS topic.
These queues are subscribers
and they will all receive the messages sent into SNS.
So for example, we have a buying service
that wants to send messages to two SQS queues.
What it will do instead,
it will send one message into an SNS topic,
and the queues are subscribers of that SNS topic
so that the fraud service and the shipping service
can read all messages from their own SQS queues.
The idea with this as well
is that it's a fully decoupled model
and there is no data loss.
SQS will give you data persistence, delayed processing,
as well as retries of work.
And with this pattern, we can add more SQS queues
as a subscriber of the SNS topic over time.
For this, we need to make sure
that your SQS queue access policy,
as we've seen from before,
allows your SNS topic to write to your SQS queue.
So again, yet another use case
for using queue access policies,
and we have cross-region delivery.
So it's definitely possible for an SNS topic
in one region to send messages
to SQS queues in other regions if the security allows it.
Next, so how do we use this pattern for other purposes?
For example, S3 events into multiple queues.
So there is a limitation of S3 event rules
is that for a combination of event type, for example,
an object is being created
and a prefix, for example,
images/, you can only have one S3 event rule.
But what if you want to send the same S3 event notification
to multiple SQS queues?
In that case, you would use the fan-out pattern.
So for example, we have S3 object created
as an event appearing in your S3 bucket,
and we will send this event into an SNS topic,
and we will subscribe many SQS queues
to the SNS topic as a final pattern.
But we could also subscribe other type of application,
email, Lambda functions, et cetera, et cetera.
And then what we get from this is that the message
of the event happening in Amazon S3
is going to go to many different destinations
thanks to this fan-out pattern.
Another architecture is that you can send data
directly from SNS to Amazon S3
through Kinesis Data Firehose.
So because SNS has a direct integration with KDF,
then your buying service can send data into an SNS topic.
Then Kinesis Data Firehose, KDF,
will receive that information.
And then from Kinesis Data Firehose,
you can send it into your Amazon S3 bucket,
or for that matter,
any supported KDF specific destination,
which allows you to be really extensible in the way
you want to maybe persist your messages from your SNS topic.
So we can apply the fan-out pattern to FIFO topics as well.
So Amazon SNS has a FIFO or FIFO capability,
which is first in first out,
which gives ordering of messages in the topic.
So the producer send the messages.
One, two, three, four.
And the subscribers can only be an SQS FIFO queue for now,
which is receiving messages,
one, two, three, four, in order.
So the idea is that with SNS FIFO,
we get the same features as SQS FIFO,
we get ordering by message group ID.
We get deduplication using a deduplication ID
or content-based deduplication.
And both SQS standard and FIFO queues can be subscribers.
In terms of throughput, you're limited.
You get the same throughput as the SQS FIFO queue.
So why do we need this?
Well, in case you wanna do a fan out using SQS FIFO.
So you need fan out, ordering and deduplication.
So the buying service will send the data
into an SNS FIFO topic,
and then it will fan out to two SQS FIFO queue,
which can have the fraud service
and the shipping service read from FIFO queues as well.
One last feature of SNS that can be really handy
regarding the fan-out pattern
is that you can do message filtering in SNS.
So what is message filtering?
Well, it's a JSON policy that is used
to filter messages sent to the SNS topics subscription.
So if a subscription doesn't have a filter policy,
it will receive every message,
and that's a default behavior.
But let's take an example of what happens
when we set up a message filtering policy.
So we have a buying service
and it sends transactions into an SNS topic.
For example, the transaction looked like
there's an order number,
there's a product, for example, a pencil,
the quantity for, and the state which is placed.
Now we want to create an SQS queue just for placed orders,
not all the orders, but just for placed orders.
So for this, we will subscribe the SQS queue
into the SNS topic, and we'll apply a filter policy in JSON,
and we will specify in a policy
that we want to have State equals Placed.
And so only the messages matching the policy
will go into the SQS queue,
but then we could have an SQS queue for canceled orders.
And so we can create our own filter policy for canceled
orders and have those coming from the same SNS topic
into the SQS queue.
And so the placed orders
and the canceled orders SQS queue
will not have the same messages.
We can also use the same filter policy, the canceled one,
to create an email subscription for canceled orders.
We could have a filter policy for declined orders,
for example, and as another SQS queue,
or we can create an SQS queue without a filter policy
to have all messages from that SNS topic.
So using all these fan-out patterns and message filtering,
FIFO queues and FIFO topics,
we get lots of different possibilities
and the exam will try to test you on all of those.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.