So, let's practice using SNS.
So, we're going to go into the Simple Notification Service
and create our first topic.
So I'll just call this MyFirstTopic,
and then click on Next step.
So we have two options for creating a topic.
It can either be a standard topic,
and this what we'll be creating,
which is best-effort message ordering,
at least once message delivery,
highest throughput in terms of publishes per second,
and SQS, Lambda, HTTPS, SMS, email,
and mobile application endpoints can read
from this SNS topic.
Or we've seen that we could create an SNS FIFO topic.
And this is to get strictly preserved message ordering,
exactly once message delivery,
high throughput up to 300 publishes per second,
and the only thing that can subscribe
to a FIFO SNS topic is an SQS queue.
In this case, if we have FIFO, we can see
that the name of topic has to end with .fifo.
So we'll just go with standard,
and then we'll use MyFirstTopic as the name.
We can encrypt the messages in our topic.
We can set up an access policy.
And the access policy is going
to define who and what can write to the SNS topic.
So this is similar to an S3 bucket policy,
and this is similar to also an SQS access queue policy.
Okay?
The idea is that with this access policy, for example,
we could set up an S3 bucket
to write events into an SNS topic,
and then the SNS topic could send data to SQS, and so on.
So the access policy will be needed
to allow the S3 bucket to write to our SNS topic.
So for now, I'll just use basic,
because we don't need to do anything fancy,
and then we are not going to set up any of these.
And then we'll just click on Create topic.
So MyFirstTopic is created,
and as we can see right now, we have zero subscriptions.
So we need to create our first subscription.
So I'm going to create one,
and we need to choose the protocol.
So it could be Kinesis Data Firehose, SQS Lambda, Email,
Email-JSON, HTTP, HTTPS, and SMS, okay?
And you have to remember those going into the exam.
But to make it very simple, we're first going to use Email,
and actually only going to use Email in this hands-on.
Now we need to use an endpoint on the email address.
I will use stephanetheteacher@mailinator.com,
and this is just a service for me to get a temporary email.
So if I type stephanetheteacher, and press on GO,
then I'm getting a public inbox,
and they will receive emails from this address, okay?
So we're going to create this.
As we can see right here,
we could set up a subscription filter policy.
This is optional, but with this policy,
we could filter the messages
that will be sent to the subscription,
which can be really helpful if you have many subscribers
that just need to get only subsets
of the messages sent into your SNS topic.
But we will not set it up right now.
So we'll create the subscription,
and now we need to validate the subscription.
So as you can see right now, it is pending confirmation.
And so to confirm it, I'm going to go into my Mailinator,
and I've received an email.
And by clicking on this Confirmed subscription,
I'm going to confirm my subscription, so here we go.
And now if I refresh this page, what I should be seeing is
that my subscription right here is confirmed.
So this is perfect.
So again, if I click on my subscription,
I can look at it, see that is going
to send an email to this endpoint.
And if I wanted to do it,
I could have a subscription filter policy.
But right now we don't have any,
because we want all messages sent to my SNS topic
to go directly into the subscription.
So now, let's do a test.
We're going to publish a message,
and I'm going to just enter a message structure.
I'll say hello world, which is very common
when we test some services, and then publish the message.
So the message has been published into MyFirstTopic.
And so what I should be seeing is
that if I go back to my emails and go to my public messages,
so back to my inbox, I should be seeing, yes,
an AWS notification message coming straight from SNS
saying hello world.
So very easy, very cool,
and we just shows that SNS is working for us.
So this is perfect. We're good to go.
If we wanted to implement the SQS fanout pattern,
we will need to choose SQS
and set up many, many different queues as the receivers
of the subscription for our SNS topic.
So yeah, that's it for SNS.
When you're done, delete the subscription
and then go back to the topic on the left hand side,
and then click on Delete to delete the topic
by typing, delete me.
And off you go. That's it for SNS.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.