Welcome to this section on Kinesis.
So Kinesis at the Certified Developer exam
is something you need to know in depth,
so I'm going to spend a lot of time
describing how each service works
to really give you that in-depth expertise
to allow you to score the maximum amount of points
at the exam.
So let's start with an overview of Kinesis.
Kinesis makes it easy to collect, process,
and analyze streaming data in real time.
So the real-time data could be anything,
such as application logs, metrics,
website clickstreams, IoT telemetry data.
As long as the data is generated fast and in real time,
this counts as a real time stream of data.
So there are four services that comprise Kinesis.
There's Kinesis Data Streams
that we'll explore really in depth
to capture, process, and store data streams.
There is Kinesis Data Firehose to load data streams
into some data stores in AWS, but also outside of AWS.
There is Kinesis Data Analytics to analyze data streams
with the SQL language or Apache Flink.
And finally, a service that doesn't appear at the exam
but still good to mention is Kinesis Video Streams
to capture, process, and store video streams.
So this was just a very high-level overview.
In the next lectures,
we'll be exploring one of these services one by one
and making sure
we get the right amount of knowledge on them.
So I will see you in the next lecture.