So now let's talk about Amazon Data Firehose.
So Amazon Data Firehose is a service
to send data from sources into target destinations.
So to get data into Amazon Data Firehose,
you may have producers that could be your applications,
your clients, or things you write,
and you use the SDK to send data into Firehose
or the Kinesis agents,
as well as Firehose has the capability
to pull directly from some services
such as, for example, a Kinesis Data Streams
or an Amazon CloudWatch logs and events,
or for example, AWS IoT.
And so all these services are either going
to be pushing into Amazon Data Firehose
or Firehose are going to be pulling from,
for example, a Kinesis data stream
and it is going to receive the records.
Now these records are going to be received,
and then they can optionally be transformed
using a Lambda function, if you wanted
to do some data conversion format, for example.
And they're going to be accumulated into a buffer
and the buffer is going to be flushed once in a while
to do batch writing into a lot of destinations.
So the first destinations are going
to be AWS specific destinations,
such as sending data into Amazon S3
or into Amazon Redshift to perform analytics,
or into Amazon OpenSearch as well.
You also have the option to send from Data Firehose
directly into third-party partner destinations
such as Datadog, Splunk, New Relic, and MongoDB.
And finally, if your destination is not supported,
you can simply use the HTTP endpoint integration
to send it anywhere you want.
Now, Firehose will write this data,
but you also have the option to write all
or just the failed data that has been sent
into an S3 bucket for a backup.
So Amazon Data Firehose
used to be called Kinesis Data Firehose
for the longest time,
but now it's called Amazon Data Firehose
because it does way more than just Kinesis.
It's a fully managed service,
and again, it supports Redshift, S3,
and Amazon OpenSearch service,
third party destinations such as Splunk
and a custom HTTP endpoint
if you wanted to write your own integration.
You also have automatic scaling.
It's fully serverless,
and you only pay for what you use from within the service.
It's called a near real-time service
and this is something you have to look for in the exam.
Near real-time usually points
to Amazon Data Firehose, and why?
Well, because you have a buffer inside of Firehose,
and the buffer can be optionally disabled,
but usually it's used
and it has a capability based on size or time.
So it's going to accumulate, accumulate,
and then after a while,
it's going to be flushed into your destination.
And therefore, because that takes a little bit of time,
it's a near real-time service.
In terms of what type of incoming data it supports,
it supports CSV, JSON, Parquet, Avro, text, or binary data.
And from within Firehose, you can convert your data
to Parquet or ORC as data formats
or even do compressions with gzip or snappy.
But if you wanted to do a custom conversion
or data transformation,
for example, you could use AWS Lambda.
For example, if you wanted to change your data
from CSV to JSON format before sending it to Amazon S3.
So it's usually helpful to compare Kinesis data streams
and Amazon Data Firehose, so here it is.
So Kinesis Data Stream
is a streaming data collection service.
You're going to usually have
to write your own producer and consumer code.
It's going to be real-time.
And there are two modes, provision and on-demand mode.
Data can be stored up to one year
and you have a replay capability.
For Amazon Data Firehose,
it's a way to load streaming data into target destinations
such as Amazon S3, Redshift, OpenSearch and so on.
It's fully managed, it's near real-time,
it has automatic scaling, no data storage,
and no replay capability.
All right, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.