Now let's learn about a new service,
which is Kinesis Data Firehose.
So it is a very helpful service
that can take data from producers.
And producers can be everything we've seen
for Kinesis Data Stream, so applications, clients, SDK,
or the Kinesis agents can all produce
into your Kinesis Data Firehose.
But also, a Kinesis Data Stream
can produce into Kinesis Sata Firehose.
Amazon CloudWatch logs and events
can produce into Kinesis Data Firehose.
And all these applications are going to send records
into Kinesis Data Firehose,
and then Kinesis Data Firehose can optionally choose
to transform the data using a Lambda function,
but this is optional.
And once the data is transformed optionally,
then it can be written in batches into destinations.
So Kinesis Data Firehose text data from sources.
Usually the most common is going to be Kinesis Data Streams
and it's going to write this data into destinations
without you writing any kind of code,
because Kinesis Data Firehose knows how to write data.
So there are three kinds of destinations
with Kinesis Data Firehose.
The number one category is AWS destinations
and you need to know them by heart.
So the first one is Amazon S3,
so you can write all your data into Amazon S3.
The second one is Amazon Redshift,
which is a warehousing database.
And to do so, it first writes the data into Amazon S3.
And then Kinesis Data Firehose will issue a copy command,
and this copy command is going to copy data
from Amazon S3 into Amazon Redshift.
And the last destination on AWS is called Amazon OpenSearch.
There are also some third party partner destinations.
So Kinesis Data Firehose can send data into Datadog,
Splunk, New Relic, MongoDB.
And this list can get bigger and bigger over time,
so it will not update this if there are new partners.
But just so you know, they are partners
that Kinesis Data Firehose can send data to.
Or finally, if you have your own API with an HTTP endpoint,
it is for you to send data from Kinesis Data Firehose
into a custom destination.
Okay, so once the data is sent into all these destinations,
you have two options.
You can also send all the data
into an S3 bucket as a backup
or just send the data that was failed
to be written into these destinations
into a failed S3 buckets.
So to summarize,
Kinesis Data Firehose is a fully managed service,
so there's no administration, automated scaling,
and it is serverless, so no service to manage.
You can send data into AWS destinations
such as the Redshift, Amazon S3, and OpenSearch,
third party partners such as Splunk, MongoDB,
Datadog, new Relic, et cetera, et cetera,
and custom destinations to any HTTP endpoints.
You're going to pay only for the data
going through Firehose,
so this is a very good data pressing model,
and it is a near real time.
Why?
Well, because we write data in batches
from Firehose to the destination.
So there's going to be a buffer interval.
Either it's zero seconds and you've disabled buffering
or you set it to a higher number and then you have buffering
and you can set it up up to 900 seconds.
And then if you have buffering,
you should also specify a buffer size.
So it's minimum one megabyte
and you can go to higher number.
So in case you have buffering,
well, that makes Kinesis Data Firehose
a near real-time service.
And if you don't have buffering,
if you have zero seconds for your buffer interval,
it's still going to be considered near real-time
because going to take a few seconds
to deliver your data into your destination.
It supports many data formats, conversions,
transformation, and compressions,
and you can write your own data transformation
using Lambda if you needed to.
Finally, you can send all the failed
or all the data into a backup S3 buckets.
So a question that comes up at the exam
usually is to understand the difference
of when to use Kinesis Data Streams
and Kinesis Data Firehose.
So should be very easy for you now if you followed closely,
but let's summarize.
Kinesis Data Streams is just streaming service
used to ingest data at scale
and you write your own custom code
for your producers and your consumers.
It's real time, so 200 millisecond or 70 millisecond,
and you manage scaling yourself,
you do chart splitting and chart merging
to increase the scale and throughputs.
You're going to also pay
for how much capacity you have provision.
The data storage in the Kinesis Data Stream
can be between one to 365 days.
This allows multiple consumers to read from the same stream
and also supports replay capability.
Whereas Kinesis Data Firehose is an ingestion service
to stream data into S3, Redshift, OpenSearch,
which a third party or a custom HTTP.
It is fully managed, no service to manage.
It is near real time.
So remember, this near real-time
is a keyword you need to look at in your exam questions.
There is automated scaling
so no need for you to worry about it.
And you're going to pay only
for what goes through Kinesis Data Firehose.
There is no data storage,
so you cannot replay data from Kinesis Data Firehose.
So yeah, it doesn't support the replay capability.
So that's it for the overview of Kinesis Data Firehose.
I hope that makes sense
and I will see you in the next lecture.