Now let's talk about CloudFront.
CloudFront is a content delivery network or CDN.
So anytime you see CDN on the exam, think CloudFront.
It improves the read performance by caching the content
of your website at the different Edge locations.
And because your content is caged
all around the world,
then your users all around the world
will have a lower latency,
and this will improve the user experience.
CloudFront is made of 216 points of presence globally,
which correspond to the AWS Edge locations around the world,
and AWS keeps on adding locations
to improve user experience even further everywhere.
On top of it,
by having the content distributed globally,
we are getting DDoS protection.
So DDoS is a sort of attack where all your servers
around the world are getting attacked at the same time.
We'll see this later on in this course.
And the idea is at CloudFront,
because your application is worldwide,
then you're protected against these attacks,
also using something called shield,
and web application firewall,
that we will be seeing in the security section.
So if we wanted to look at a map of the world,
these are the map.
And we see some Edge locations,
as well at Edge cases.
And so say we had created an S3 bucket,
and a website on our S3 bucket in Australia,
but we had a user maybe in America.
Then what the user will do,
is that it will request the content
from an American Edge location using CloudFront,
and CloudFront will be able
to fetch the content from Australia.
Now, if another user in the US
will be requesting the same content,
then it will be served directly from the Edge,
and it will not go all the way
to Australia to serve that content.
Same if a user is in China,
then it will be talking to a Chinese
point of presence, and then redirected to the S3 buckets,
and then the content will be caged at the Edge.
CloudFront has several types of origins,
which are basically backends
you want to connect CloudFront to.
So we have Amazon S3 buckets for
distributing files and caching them at the Edge.
And also for the other way to upload files
to Amazon S3 directly through CloudFront.
And the connection between CloudFront
and your S3 bucket is secured using something
called an OAC, an Origin Access Control.
You can also have a VPC origin.
So this is if you have an application hosted
in a private subnet in a VPC, then for example,
it could be an application load balancer,
a network cloud balancer, an EC2 instance.
You can connect CloudFront directly to them privately.
You can also have any custom origin.
So anything that uses HTTP can be used in the backend.
For example, it could be a website hosted on Amazon S3.
And first, we must make sure that the S3 bucket
is enabled as a static S3 website,
or any public HTTP backend you want
within or outside of AWS.
So at a high level, how does platform work?
We have the Edge location all around the world, okay?
And then it will be connecting to your origin.
So would it be an S3 bucket, or an HTTP server?
And when the client connects,
and does an HTTP request into your Edge location,
then the Edge location will see if
it has it in the cache.
If it doesn't have it in the cache,
then it will go to the origin to get the request results.
And then once it retrieves the results,
it will be caching it into a local cache,
so that if another client requests
the same content from the same Edge location,
then the Edge location does not need to go to the origin.
So if we have S3 as an origin,
then if we look at the cloud,
your S3 bucket is your origin in some region,
and then you have Edge locations all around the world.
For example, at Los Angeles.
And your users accessing the Edge location in Los Angeles
we'll get their content directly
served through the Edge location.
But first, the Edge location will get it from
the origin S3 bucket through the private network.
And the S3 bucket will be secured using
an origin access control,
and by modifying the S3 bucket policy on the S3 bucket.
So this is the same when we have a user in Sao Paulo,
for example, in Brazil.
Again, this is will be another Edge location,
which will be serving users close to Brazil.
And then it will be a private connection
between your Edge location and your S3 bucket and so on.
So using CloudFront and the Edge locations,
we can see that the content
of our S3 bucket in one region
can be distributed all around the world
through the Edge locations, or points of presence.
So one question that's common is,
"What is the difference between
"CloudFront and something like S3 replication?"
Well, if you have CloudFront,
you're using the Global Edge network.
So this is about 216 points of presence,
and the files are going to be caged
in each Edge location maybe for a day.
So this is amazing if you have static content,
that must be able to be available
everywhere around the world.
S3 cross region replication is different.
It must be set up for each region
you want replication to happen.
So this is not for every region in the world.
And then files are going to be updated in near real-time.
So there is no caching that happens.
And this is only for read-only.
And so this is great if you have dynamic content
that needs to change all the time,
and be available at low latency in a few regions.
So they serve very different purposes.
CloudFront is a CDN,
which is to cache content all around the world,
whereas S3 cross region replication
is to really replicate an entire bucket into another region.
So hopefully that makes sense about CloudFront.
In the next lecture, we'll have a play,
and see how we can set up a CloudFront
distribution on the cloud for an S3 buckets.
So we'll see you in the next lecture.