Let's explore some advanced options
for CloudFront that can come up in the exam.
So let's talk about pricing and price classes.
So we know that CloudFront edge locations
are all around the world,
but because they're all around the world,
the cost of data out per edge location will vary,
and so, here is a table.
So as you can see,
based on the continent or geographic region
that the edge location is in,
then you will have a different pricing.
So if you look at this table, you're going to see numbers,
but if you look at Mexico, United States, and Canada,
the first 10 terabytes
is going to cost $0.085 per gigabytes,
but if you have the same edge location as India,
it's going to be about twice the cost at $0.17 per gigabyte
of data transferred, and so on.
And the more data transferred out of CloudFront,
the lower the cost, so if you transfer
over five petabytes of data out of CloudFront,
you're only going to pay $0.02 out of the United States.
So, the idea is that from the left hand side
to the right hand side, you have a higher cost.
Which brings us to the price classes.
So you have a choice you can make,
and you can reduce the number
of edge locations around the world that is going to be used
for your CloudFront distribution
in order to do cost reduction.
And there are three price classes available,
there is the Price Class All,
which is giving you all regions,
and obviously, the best performance,
but it's going to cost you a little bit more money
because as you can see for example
an edge location in India will cost more
than an edge location in the United States.
You can do the Price Class 200,
which gives you most regions,
but excludes the most expensive regions,
and Price Class 100 to only get the least expensive regions,
and this is summarized in this table.
Now, the table is not really fun to look at,
so I made a little diagram.
Here is the world,
and we have a lot of edge locations around the world.
Now, the Price Class 100 is going to give us the America,
the North America, and Europe,
then Price Class 200 is going to add some of these regions,
and Price Class All
is going to have the entire world available
for the edge locations.
So that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.