This section is one of the most important one the exam will ask you lots of question about security.
Now you may have noticed in all the previous lectures I have talked about security quite a bit.
I said how different AWS services were integrated with security and I'm sure you get a good idea of it but
I wanted to dedicate a whole section just to reflect on what we learn and learn about the KMS properly
encryption properly, the parameters store and so on. This section
should really bring light to everything you've seen on the security side.
I hope you like it.
It is very real world oriented.
And we're going to practice stuff with AWS Lambda.
So let's go and learn about security.