So here is a lecture
that is more focused on the solution architecture,
and this is around DDoS protection and best practices.
So let's assume that you have this kind of architecture.
We have an auto scaling group with EC2 instances.
It's fronted by a Elastic Load Balancer,
and then your load balancer can be either exposed
by a Global Accelerator as fixed IPs,
or it could be fronted, for example, by CloudFronts.
CloudFronts can be linked to WAF,
a web application firewall, and so on.
You can have Route 53 for DNS routing.
And finally you could also have another architecture
where you have CloudFront and the API gateway.
So this is just to represent the
kind of combinations you can do.
Obviously there are more than one,
but the idea's that we're going to discuss
thanks to the letter BP1, best practice one,
best practice two, et cetera,
what the implications are
in terms of DDoS resiliency, okay?
So by using CloudFront, we are actually at the Edge.
So this slide is all about Edge location mitigation.
That means that your web application delivery
is at the Edge, and so you're going
to be protected against DDoS common attacks
by using Shield, just a normal setup of Shield's,
so SYN floods and UDB reflection.
If you use the Global Accelerator,
this is going to be able to access your application
around the world, again at the Edge.
And again, it's fully integrated
with Shield for DDoS protection.
So it's very helpful if your backend
is somehow not compatible with CloudFronts.
In this case, you would have Global Accelerator
in front of it, and so that means that no matter
what backend you have, either using CloudFront
or the Global Accelerator,
you will be fully distributed at the Edge of AWS
and the Edge location will be DDoS protected.
Also, if you use Route 53,
then the domain name resolution is global,
it's at the Edge, and you also have
a DDoS protection mechanism on your DNS.
So we understand that if we're at the Edge,
we can have a better DDoS protection.
Next, we can have the best practices for DDoS mitigation.
So first, let's look at the infrastructure layer defense.
This is BP1, BP3, and BP6.
So the idea is that by using CloudFront,
Global Accelerator, Route 53
and the Elastic Load Balancing,
we protect our Amazon EC2 instances against high traffic.
And this is the idea that by using all these services,
the traffic is going to be handled by most of them
before ever reaching our EC2 instances.
Now, if we enable our EC2 instances with auto-scaling,
that means that in case the traffic does indeed
reach our auto scaling group, we can scale automatically
to accommodate for a greater load on our application.
And if we use Elastic Load Balancing,
then the ELB is going to automatically spread
the traffic across many EC2 instances.
And so that means that each EC2 instances
will have a manageable amount of traffic onto them,
provided the fact that the auto-scaling group
of course has scaled as well.
Now at the application layer defense,
we can detect and filter malicious requests
at BP1 and BP2.
So the idea is that CloudFront is going
to serve static content, and serve it from Edge locations,
therefore protecting your backend.
And then you can use WAF on top of CloudFront,
or your application load balancers to filter
and block requests based on request signatures,
for example, you can block specific IPs,
specific request types and so on.
And if you use the WAF rate based rules,
you can automatically block the IPs of bad actors.
So you can use a bunch of managed rules on WAF
to block IPs based on reputation
or block anonymous IPs and so on.
And using CloudFront, you can block specific geographies.
The idea is that CloudFront and WAF are managed services,
and so they will take care of filtering
some requests for you, so you can be protected
against DDoS attack.
And of course using Shield Advanced,
so in case you enable it,
then it will automatically create WAF rules for you
to mitigate layer seven attacks.
So this is good for the application layer defense,
again to protect your EC2 instances
from getting any bad request or at least minimize them.
And also, how do we reduce our attack surface?
So the idea with this architecture is
that the backend AWS resources are used
to serve our application, are hidden.
So we have BP1, BP4, and BP6.
So if we use CloudFront, the API Gateway,
or Elastic Load Balancing,
we can hide our backend resources.
The attacker will never know if it's a lambda function
or EC2 instances or ECS tasks, and so on,
because we have used other things in front of them.
Also, we can set up security groups and network ACLs
to filter traffic based on specific IPs,
and elastic IPs, if we use them,
they can be protected by AWS Shield Advanced as well.
And then you can protect API endpoints themselves,
so if you use the API gateway,
then you can hide whatever backend it is,
whether it be EC2, lambda or something else.
And if you use the Edge optimized mode,
you're already global.
Otherwise you can use CloudFront plus the regional mode,
which gives you more control for DDoS protection.
And if you use WAF on top of the API gateway,
then you can get filtering of any HTTP request.
And if you set up the API gateway correctly,
you can have burst limits, you can do headers filtering,
and you can use and force API keys for your users,
therefore protecting yourself from a DDoS attack.
So hopefully this kind of architecture makes sense
and you understand the different ways you can protect
against DDoS, because the exam will ask you
to think just like that, okay?
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.