So let's talk about some other services
within the Systems Manager service that can come up
at one question at the exam maybe.
So if you don't understand everything,
just remember the general idea out of these.
So the first one is run command
and it's used to execute a document,
therefore a script or just one command.
And these commands are run on multiple instances
using resource groups.
And these instances are EC2 instances or on-premises servers
that are registered with the Systems Manager service
because, well, the agent is running on them.
So for this, when we run the command, no need for SSH.
This is using the same mechanism
as we saw for Session Manager.
It just runs them through the agents.
And then any output of the command through the run command
can be sent to S3 or to CloudWatch Logs.
And then in case you have any kind of failures,
then they will be sent into SNS.
So you can have in-progress, success, failed and so on.
All these updates can be sent into SNS.
You have full integration with IAM for security
and CloudTrail to see who run what commands.
And then, of course, there is some automation out of it.
So EventBridge can directly run a run command.
So we have EC2 instances or on-premises servers
and they're managed with the SSM Agent.
And then very simply, we're going to run a command on them
using the run command feature of Sessions Manager.
The output can be sent to Amazon S3 or to CloudWatch Logs.
Any kind of status notifications is sent to Amazon SNS.
And it can be triggered either by us, the user,
or automatically using EventBridge.
Another one is called Patch Manager.
So as the name indicates, it's very simple.
It's used to automate the process
of patching managed instances.
So this is being used to apply operating system updates,
application updates, security updates.
It supports, of course, your EC2 instances
and on-premises servers.
And it supports Linux, Mac, and Windows.
So you can patch either on-demand, so right away,
or you can have a schedule of patches
using what's called a maintenance window
where your instances are ready to be patched.
Now also within Patch Manager, you can scan your instances
and you can generate a patch compliance report
to find if all your instances are patched correctly
and find if anyone or anything is missing a patch.
So again, from either the console, the SDK,
or a maintenance window,
we're going to invoke the Patch Manager.
And for this, it's called
the AWS-RunPatchBaseline run command.
And it's going to patch all of my EC2 instances
and then we can find a report within Patch Manager.
So I mentioned maintenance windows,
but let's just do a deep dive on them.
So it's used to define a schedule
of when to perform actions on your instances.
So for example, you want to define a maintenance window
to do OS patching or updating drivers
or installing software or whatever you want.
And when you define a maintenance window,
you contain a schedule.
So when is it going to be triggered?
A duration, so for how long?
What instances is this maintenance window applying to?
That makes sense.
And finally, what tasks will be run
during this maintenance window?
And so therefore, the maintenance window, for example,
can be triggered every 24 hour to run the command
to update or to patch my EC2 instances,
but you can be very creative with it as well.
Next we have Automation.
So Automation is used to simplify the common maintenance
and deployment task on EC2 instances or other AWS resources.
For example, you would use an automation
to restart many instances at a time
or to create an AMI or to create EBS snapshots and so on.
So you would have an Automation Runbook.
They represent SSM documents and they are predefined actions
on your EC2 instances or your resources on AWS.
So these runbooks will be used by the SSM Automation
to execute some actions on EC2 instances,
for example, restart them all,
or to execute actions on your resources on AWS,
for example, take snapshots of all my RDS databases.
So this can be triggered using the console, the SDK,
or the CLI, Amazon EventBridge,
or the Maintenance Windows or as well AWS Config.
So there's an integration such as
if Config finds that a resource is non-compliant,
then we can have a remediation automatically
to run an SSM Automation
and try to remediate this non-compliant resource.
So that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.