So now let's talk about
Instance Scheduler on AWS.
So it's a bit of a weird one.
It's not a service, it's an AWS solution
that's deployed through CloudFormation.
And here is the architecture.
It's quite complete and quite complicated,
but the idea is that you deploy this using CloudFormation
and this provides you a capability in your account
to automatically start and stop your AWS services
in order to reduce costs, maybe up to 70%.
For example, if you have a use case
where you want to stop the company's
EC2 instances outside business hours,
then you may want to use
the Instance Scheduler solution on AWS.
So this has support for EC2 instances,
EC2 Auto Scaling Groups and RDS instances.
Now, all the schedules are managed in a DynamoDB table
and the idea behind how this service works is that
there's a Lambda function that will look up the schedule
in DynamoDB and then it will trigger other lambdas
that will automatically stop or start the required instances
in the required services.
So this is a complete solution.
It supports cross-account and cross region resources
and is production ready.
If you are interested, this is the link
and the exam may ask you
about the idea behind this solution.
So again, this allows you to just stop and start resources
to save on costs.
Now I just wanna show you how this gets deployed.
We're not going to use it, but I want
for you to see it in action for the deployment part.
So let's type Instance Scheduler AWS,
and then we click on the solution
and we arrive on this webpage.
So this is to stop and start Amazon EC2 and RDS instances
to manage cost.
So we get the benefits,
we get some information around the version, the release,
we can look at the implementation guide
and you can download it, it's very helpful.
The source code is there,
this is the CloudFormation template and so on.
And then we have a developer guide and an operator guide.
So it's quite a complete solution and one of the most,
I would say complete one on AWS and this is architecture
and it shows you what is step 1, step 2, step 3,
step 4, step 5, step 6 and step 7.
Obviously, using it is out of the scope of this course,
but we're just going to do the quick start
to see how we can get started.
So the way to actually launch the stack is
to use the management console
and you click on launch solution here
and this takes you directly into CloudFormation.
And then automatically is going to pre-fill
the instance at this template and the Amazon S3 URL
and then we click on next.
So this is going to deploy the solution
as a CloudFormation template
so I'll call this one Instance Scheduler
and you don't have to do it,
I just wanna show you how it's done.
And here we get some information
around the different parameters.
So we have...
And I need to have no space, okay.
So we have here the tech key is Schedule.
This is every five minutes that we're going to look at
if we can shut down things.
What's the default time zone?
If you want to enable yes or no scheduling,
so no if you want to disable it
or yes, if you want to enable the solution.
Then we have services.
So do we want to allow it
to enable EC2 scheduling, yes;
RDS, RDS cluster
as well as Neptune, DocumentDB and auto-scaling
so it's possible that over time
more services are added to this,
but the main ones to remember are EC2 instances
and RDS instances and cluster.
And then you have tagging.
So this is what happens when an instance is started
or stopped.
A tag is going to be added automatically describing
how instant scheduler actually did an action on this date,
on this time zone.
And then, more service specific things
that we don't need to really look at.
Do we want to have RDS instances snapshot on stop?
What do we want to look at for ASG and so on?
So it's quite a very complete,
I would say solution monitoring and then other things.
But for now, we're good.
Let's click on next
and then let's click on yes and click on next.
And so this is going to create
based on all these parameters,
a stack on CloudFormation with all the solution.
So now I'm just going to wait for it to be created.
Okay, so the stack is now created
and what's important to see is the resources.
As you can see, there's a lot of resources
that have been created
and so we can tree view or a flat view.
And what I wanna show you though is a DynamoDB table.
So if a type dynamo,
okay, we have three tables, we have the config tables,
and that's the most important table here.
So, in this table that you would set your schedules.
So let's explore the table item and here we go.
So we have here the types of things that happen.
So we have the name, the begin time, the description,
the end time, and so on.
So this is just an example,
but it tells you like for example,
how to have office hours or days in the week or working days
or every first Monday of each quarter.
So this is where you would actually schedule
and set up everything.
And then for the rest,
then if you go into the Lambda console over here,
it's just a bunch of Lambda functions.
You can see I have a lot of them right here.
This bunch of Lambda functions are going to do
all the scheduling.
Of course, getting into the details
of the architecture is not what's necessary,
but for you to understand the idea behind it.
Okay, so that's it.
I went a little bit too deep into it probably,
but it's good for you to see it.
And I'm just going to go ahead
and delete my stack and we'll be done.
Alright, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.