So there is another use case for EFS three access points
and it's called S3 Object Lambda.
So the idea is that you have an S3 bucket,
but you want to modify the object
just before it is being retrieved by a color application.
And instead of, for example
duplicating our buckets to have different versions
of each object, we can use S3 Object Lambda instead.
And for this, we need the S3 access points that we just saw.
So how does that work?
Say we have the cloud and we have an S3 bucket in it.
So an E-commerce application maybe owns the data
in this S3 bucket
and so they're able to access directly the S3 buckets
and put and get the original object out of it.
But then an analytics application may want to
only have access to the redacted object.
That means that some data has been deleted from the object.
And so instead of creating a new S3 bucket for this
what we can do is that we create an S3 access point
on top of a S3 bucket and is connected to a Lambda function.
Now, we haven't seen Lambda in depth,
but a Lambda function allows you to run a bit of code
in the cloud very easily.
And so this Lambda function is going to redact the object
as it is being retrieved.
And on top of this Lambda function,
we're going to create an S3 object Lambda access point.
And, this is how the analytics application is
going to access our S3 buckets.
So to summarize
the analytics application accesses our S3 Object
Lambda access points, which invokes our Lambda function.
Our Lambda function is going to retrieve the data
from the S3 bucket and runs some code to redact the data.
And therefore the analytics application is
obtaining a redacted object from the very same S3 bucket
as the E-commerce application.
Now, a marketing application may want to have access
to an enriched object, and they have a customer
loyalty database to enhance the data.
So instead of, again, creating a new S3 bucket and
creating all the objects with all the enriched data.
What we can do is, again, using a Lambda function.
So another piece of code.
And this one will enrich the data by looking it up
from the customer loyalty database.
And therefore we can also create an object
Lambda access point on top of it.
And therefore our marketing application
can access this access point,
this S3 object Lambda access point to get, again
the enriched objects.
As you can see, we only need one S3 bucket
but we can create access points
and object Lambda to modify the data
as we wish.
So the use cases for it is to redact, for example, PII data.
So personally identifiable information, for analytics
or non-production environments, or for example
to convert data from XML to JSON or to perform any kind
of transformation you want.
For example resizing and watermarking images on the fly
but the watermark is specific
to the user who request the object.
So that's kind of a cool usage for S3 Object Lambda.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.