Welcome.
So in this lecture we are going
to launch our first EC2 instance running Amazon Linux.
So for this we'll be launching our first EC2 instance,
which is well a visual server
and we'll use the console for this.
We'll get a high level approach
to all the various parameters you have
when launching an EC2 instance,
and you'll see there are many,
but we'll learn the most important ones.
And then we will launch a web server directly
on the EC2 instance using a piece of code we will pass
to the EC2 instance that is called the user data.
Finally, we'll learn how to start, stop
and terminate our instance.
So let's get started and launch our first EC2 instance.
For this, I'm gonna go
into the EC2 Console, then I will click on Instances
and then click on Launch Instances.
So in there I'm able to launch my first EC2 instance
and to do so I need to add a name and tags.
So the name is going to be My First Instance
and that is an app that is the name tag.
And if you wanted to add additional tags
to tag your instance differently,
then you could click there, but you don't need
to click on this using just name
as My First Instance is good enough.
Next, you need to choose a base image for your EC2 instance.
This is the operating system of your instance.
As you can see, there's a full catalog that you can search
from, but we're going to use the ones
from the quick start that are very, very helpful.
And the one we'll be using is the Amazon Linux,
which is provided by AWS.
So in it I will choose the Amazon Linux 2 AMI.
And as you can see that one is free tier eligible.
So we'll just leave it as is.
So this gives me Amazon Linux 2
and the architecture I will choose is 64-bits x86.
So everything left pretty much as a default
and we'll see in this section and more
and the other ones, you can create your own AMIs
and you can found them in here, okay?
But currently we're just going to use the ones provided
by AWS as quick starts.
Next, we need to choose an instance type.
And so instance types are going to differ based
on the number of CPUs they have, the amount
of memory they have and how much they cost.
As you can see right now I have a t2.micro selected.
This one is free tier eligible, so it will be free
to launch one of them during an entire month
if we leave it running.
So this is what we'll be using.
But in here you could scroll down
and look at other types of instances.
For example, t1.micro is also free tier eligible,
but that's older generation.
And as you can see, you have a bunch
of instances right here available to you.
Some of them are going
to be free tier eligible, some of them will not.
And by default, the one
that's gonna be free tier eligible is a t2.micro.
So we'll be using that one a lot.
If you wanted
to compare the instance types, you would just click on
that link and it shows you all the type of instances in here
as well as how much memory they have and so on.
So right now we'll be using a t2.micro.
Okay next, a key pair to log into your instance.
So this is necessary if we use the SSH utility
to access our instance and we will be using the SSH utility
in this course.
Therefore, it is required for us to create a key pair.
So as we can see right now there is no key pair
and we could proceed without a key pair,
but for now we won't do this.
So let's go ahead and create a new key pair
and the name is going to be EC2 Tutorial.
Then you need to choose a key pair type.
So we'll be using the RSA encrypted, okay, this is good.
And then the key pair format.
So if you have Mac or Linux
or Windows 10, then you can use the .pem format.
If you have Windows less than version 10,
for example Windows 7
or Windows 8, then you can do our shortcut
and directly use a ppk, which is going to be used for PuTTY
and PuTTY is how you do SSH on windows 7
and Windows 8.
So remember anything else but Windows 7
and Windows 8, choose .ppm else use ppk.
Okay, I should be clear enough, I'm going
to create this key pair and it is downloaded
for me directly.
So now it is selected automatically here.
Next we have to go into network settings.
So for now, I will not touch anything.
My instance is going to get a public IP
and then we need to connect to our instance.
And so for this, there's going
to be a security group attached
to our instance, which is going to control the traffic from
and to our instance, and therefore we can add rules.
And the first security group created will be called
launch-wizard-1.
So created by the console directly
and we can define multiple rules.
So the first rule we want to have is
to allow SSH traffic from anywhere.
So we leave it as this and this will create a rule
in our security group to allow SSH traffic,
but we also want to allow HTTP traffic from the internet.
So we'll tick that box and this is
because we're going to launch a web server
on our EC2 instance, so we need it as well.
As we're now going to use HTTPS
for now, we don't need to tick the second box.
Let's configure the storage
so then we can configure the storage.
And as we can see we have eight gigabits gp2 root volume
that will leave it as is, okay?
Because in the free tier we can get up to 30 gigabytes
of EBS general purpose SSD storage.
So this is good. And we only have one volume necessary.
If you go into advanced, you could configure them
and see a little bit more information, okay?
And the one important thing
to note in here is the delete on termination.
By default, it is unable to yes, I just did advanced
to show you that one detail, okay?
That means that once we terminate our EC2 instance, then
that volume is also going to be deleted.
Okay, so we leave everything as is
and we'll be get back into the simple mode.
Okay?
Next, for advanced details,
this is where it gets interesting.
So I will skip spot, I will skip IAM instance profile.
Don't worry, I will go
over them once we need to explore them.
I will skip all of that. So let's scroll down.
Let's scroll down, let's scroll down all the way
to the bottom.
And at the bottom there is user data.
User data is when we pass a script.
So some comments to our EC2 instance
to execute on the first launch of our EC2 instance
and only the first launch.
And therefore on the first launch, we want
to be able to pass these command right here.
So for this, you go into your code, you go
to the EC2 fundamentals,
and then the EC2 user data set file, you copy entirely this,
so all of it.
And then you paste it here. So you paste everything.
And that means that this script is going
to be executed when the instance is first started
and only once, okay?
In the whole lifecycle of the instance.
And what it's going to do is that it's going
to update a few things, then install the HTTPD web server
on the machine and then write a file, an HTML file.
That will be our web server.
And so you don't need to know code or know these commands.
Okay?
This is provided to you to illustrate a few things
on this lecture.
So finally for summary, we want to start one instance.
This is great and we can review everything we have here.
It all looks good. We are very happy.
And as you can see in the free tier, we get a first year
of 750 hours of 2.micro, which is running it for one month.
So that's every month.
And if you don't have a t.2micro
in your region, then it's going to be a t3.micro, okay?
And then also we get 30 gigabytes of EBS storage and so on.
So let's launch this instance and the instance is going
to be launched.
Let's go to View all Instances, Refresh.
And now my instance is in pending state.
So it's gonna take about 10, 15 seconds
for the instance to come up.
And this is the whole power of the cloud.
Thanks to the cloud, I am able to create an instance or 100
of them very quickly in less than 10 seconds
without me owning any single server.
So that is extremely powerful
and we just scratched the surface of the power of the cloud,
obviously because the course is just getting started,
but you can get a feeling of the advances
and the speed we can have on the cloud thanks to this.
So as you can see now my instance is running
and right now I wanna show you a few things, okay?
The first one is
that the instance name is My First Instance,
and there's an instance ID which is just
a unique identifier for my instance.
There is a public IPv4 address.
This is what we're going to use to access our EC2 instance.
Or there is a private IPv4 address, which is how
to access that instance internally
on the AWS network, which is private.
The instance site is running and we get some information
around host name, private DNS, which instance that we have.
So t2.micro as well as if you scroll
down the AMI we're using, which is Amazon Linux 2,
and the key pair we're using, which is EC2 tutorial, okay?
So you can have a look at a few details in here.
You have more information.
For example, on security, we get some information
on the security group, which was created called
launch-wizard-1 with these inbound rules.
So port 22 accessible from everywhere
and port 80 accessible from everywhere.
So you should have something similar, okay?
If you don't start over because you probably missed a step.
And the rule allowing all communication
outwards, which allows the instance to access the internet.
For storage we saw that, yes, we created one volume
of eight gigabytes, so we're good to go.
So now let's have a look
at the web server running on my instance.
And for this you go on public IPv4 address, you copy this
or you click on Open Address.
And as you can see, it doesn't work.
Or if you click on it, copy
and then paste it, you press Enter, it's going to work.
So it depends on the web browsers you have and so on. Okay?
But the reason it doesn't work here is that
in the URL you need to make sure
that you're using the HTTP protocol,
so http:// and then the IP.
Because if you use HTTPS, this is not going to work.
It's going to give you an infinite loading screen
which was happening right here.
So please make sure to use http:// and then the IP address.
And you're going to get this screen.
And in programming, when you do something
for the first time, you usually say Hello World.
So this web server is saying,
Hello World from and this IP right here,
which is not the public IP, this IP right here,
172-31-33-135 actually corresponds
to the private IPv4 address.
So this is something that I program myself.
So we use the public IP address to access it,
but we have the private IP address in here
and we have the hello world.
And if you go too fast, you're going to get no messages.
So if you go too fast, just wait five minutes, get back
to it, refresh this page and you'll see it.
Okay, so cool, we have a web server running, this is great.
Now let's explore a few options.
So we have an EC2 instance and it's running,
but if we don't need it, we can go to instance states
and then click on Stop Instance.
And in the cloud you can start
and stop instances just as you wish.
And why would you stop an instance?
Well, the longer you leave it running, the more you're going
to pay of course.
But if you decide
to stop an instance, then AWS will not bill you for it.
The instance state is kept
because you have a volume attached to it,
but at least you're not paying for it.
So we can see right now, well the instance is
in a stopping state, and if we try
to refresh this page, it's going to,
of course it's not going to work
because well you don't have the server running anymore.
So you can see it gets
to some like infinite loading experience.
Okay?
So my instance is now stopped and if I wanted
to actually I could get rid of it.
And in the cloud it's very common
to start instances and then get rid of them.
We're very quickly just to try it out
because this is the cloud and we can do whatever we want.
So we can do in instance state and then terminate instance.
If we do so, we're going to get a warning message
and don't click on Terminate
because I want to keep this instance with me, okay?
But this is how we would get rid of it.
So I cancel this, but what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to start my instance again.
So I go to Instance State and then Start Instance.
And now as you can see, the state is pending,
so it is getting started and I just wait for it
to be started in the green state
and I will show you something very interesting.
Okay, so my instance is now running, and if I go here
and stop the refresh and try again to refresh,
as you can see, it still goes into an infinite loop.
Well, you may say while the server is running, Stefan.
So why is it not displaying the message now?
It is displaying here,
but like from the old one, of course.
So here the IP start with 54, right?
But here, if you click on here, now the public IP start
with 3.250.
So the public IP actually has changed.
So if you stop an instance and then you start it later
on, then AWS will maybe change its public IPv4.
So therefore you need
to copy the new IPv4, make sure to use HTP.
And voila, we have access back to our EC2 instance.
But one thing that has not changed is the private IPv4,
the private IP will always stay the same,
but the public IPv4 may change.
Okay? So well, so that's it for this hands-on.
We have seen quite a lot of things.
We've launched our first EC2 instance,
which is very exciting.
Our first web server in the cloud.
We've had to look at some of the power of the cloud.
You're just using some API calls
to stop an instance, start instance, and so on.
So I hope you liked it and I will see you
in the next lecture.