So we've launched our EC2 instance
and now let's have a look at security groups.
So we have a short idea of security groups
by just clicking on security in here.
And we get some overview
of the security groups attached to our instance
as well as the inbound rules and the outbound rules.
But what I will do is
that I will just access the more complete page
of security groups from the left hand side menu.
So under networking and security,
you click on security group.
And we can see so far
that we have two security groups
in our console so far.
So the default security group that is created by default
as well as the launch wizard one
which is the first security group
that was created when we created our EC2 instance.
And so a security group has an ID.
So an identifier, just like an EC2 instance has an ID.
And then we can check the inbound rules.
So the inbound rules are the rules that allows connectivity
from the outside into the EC2 instance.
And as we can see, we have two inbound rules in here.
And the first one is of type SSH,
which allows port 22 in our instance.
And let me just click on edit inbound rules to see better.
So set first one as SSH on port 22 from anywhere.
So 000/0 is anywhere.
And the second one is HTTP
from port 80, again, anywhere.
So this rule right here is what allowed us
to access our web servers.
So if you go back to the EC2 console,
go to our instance
and
we were doing this IPv4 address.
Okay, so we were opening it as an HTTP website.
This worked thanks to this rule, port 80.
Let's verify this.
So if we delete this rule on port 80 and save the rules,
as we can see now we only have port 22.
So if I go back to this and refresh my page,
now as we can see,
there is an infinite loading screen right here
on the top of my screen,
which shows that well,
indeed I don't have access to my EC2 instance.
So here is a very important tip for you.
Any time you see a timeout,
okay, this is a timeout
because it keeps on trying to connect
but it doesn't succeed
and then it will eventually fail, called a timeout.
So if you see a timeout when trying to establish any kind
of connection into your EC2 instances,
for example, if you try to SSH into it,
but there's a timeout,
or if you try to do an HTTP query,
or if you try to do anything with it
and there is a timeout,
this is 100% the cause
of an EC2 security group.
Okay, so in that case,
go to your security group rules
and make sure that they are correct,
because if they're not correct,
then you will get a timeout.
So to fix this, we can add back a rule.
We will do
HTTP,
which allows to get port 80
in here automatically.
And then from anywhere IPv6, IPv4, excuse me, right here,
which allows this block right here.
We save the rule.
Now the rule is done.
If I go back to my page and refresh
as you can see, now it is fully working.
So this inbound rule really did the trick.
But we could add any sort of inbound rule.
So we could define the port or the port range
that we want to.
So we could say, for example, any port we want,
for example 443, which is HTTPS
or choose directly from a dropdown here
as a little shortcut the type of protocol you want.
For example, HTTPS is 443 automatically.
And then you can define where you want to allow from.
So you have different CIDR blocks
and we don't need them right now,
or security groups or prefix list,
but we'll get to see them later on,
okay, in this course.
For now, just know that you could have
either a custom CIDR anywhere which adds this blog
or if you want to, can select my IP
to only allow access to your IP.
But just be aware that if your IP changes,
then you will get a timeout
and will not be able to access your EC2 instance.
Finally, one last bit of information.
So we can have a look at outbound rules.
So we allow all traffic on IPv4 to anywhere.
So this allows our EC2 instance
to get full internet connectivity anywhere.
And something you should know,
so we have two security groups right here
default and launch wizard,
and an EC2 instance
can have many security groups attached to it.
So it can attach one but two or three
if you want maybe five security groups
and the rules will just add on to each other.
And also this security group we have created from default
so for example, this launch wizard one can be attached
to other EC2 instances.
Okay, so you can attach
as many security groups as you want
as well as as many EC2 instances you want
to one security group.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.