I want to show you an alternative to SSH
that I found a lot easier
which is the EC2 Instance Connect.
So for this, you click on My First Instance
and then you click on the top, it says connect.
You have multiple options including
the SSH client we saw from before.
But one option I wanna show you is the EC2 Instance Connect.
So this allows us to do a browser based SSH session
into our EC2 Instance.
For this we verified the public IP address, which is good.
The username is provided by default,
which is EC2 user because it get guessed
by AWS that we are using Amazon and X2
and therefore EC2 User is the right username,
but if you wanted to, you could override it,
but it doesn't work unless you enter EC2 users.
So we'll leave it as is for now,
and then, as you see there's no SSH key option,
because, well, when we do connect to it,
it's going to upload for us a temporary SSH key
and establish a connection this way.
So with this methodology,
we don't even need to manage SSH keys which I found lovely.
So you click on Connect and it's going to open a new tab.
And very quickly you are into your Amazon Linux 2 AMI
and you can start running some commands
such as whoami or ping google.com.
And as you can see, everything is working.
So the cool thing about it is that,
well, your session is in the browser
instead of using a different command line interface
such as terminal and so on.
And so you do ping google.com or do
any kind of commands you want really on it
without using the SSH utility beforehand.
But in this course, if I say use SSH,
you have either the option to use your own terminal mssh
or to use for example, party, or to use the SSH command
on windows or to use, regardless of you here
on windows, Linux, or Mac, the EC2 Instance Connect.
Now this is relying on the SSH behind the scenes.
So if I go, for example, to my Instance
look at the security group and I want to edit the rules.
So I click on my security group in here,
the inbound rules I'm going to edit them
and I'm going to remove the SSH inbound rules.
So I delete it and save the rules
and then go back to my EC2 Instances,
and I close this one and I'll try to establish
a new EC2 Instance Connect.
So let's connect, as you can see, this is not working
because while there's a problem connected to your Instance.
The first thing is that you need to open the port 22.
So back into my launch wizard, I can fix this.
I will edit the inbound rule, add the SSH rule
from anywhere IPV4, save the rule.
Let's go back in here and just in case,
if it doesn't work for you,
sometimes it's because you're using IPV6, excuse me.
So therefore you need to do from anywhere IPV6 as well.
So you need to add these two entries
for your EC2 Instance Connect
to work sometimes, depends on your setup.
So we're good to go.
And now if we try to connect to the Instance itself,
so let's try to connect in here.
Voila, we are into the Instance.
Okay.
So there was a quick demo of EC2 Instance Connect.
I will use it a lot in this course.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.